<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2013 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="standalone_server" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"  version="5.0">    
    <title>Standalone Server Setup</title>
    <para>This chapter is designed to provide simple step-by-step instructions on how to set up a
        Kuali Rice standalone server intended for enterprise deployment. The same steps can be used
        to set up a standalone server locally for development purposes, you would just install the
        database on the same machine.</para>
    <para>The steps to install and setup a standalone server with Kuali Rice are:</para>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Determine your expected load and storage needs and consult the Suggested Server
                Hardware section for guidance. Install OS.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Install &amp; configure the database management system.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Install &amp; configure required software</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Install and configure Tomcat.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Install and configure Rice.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Launch the sample application.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Set up a Keystore.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <note><para>Rather than install and setup as the root user on systems designed for production, you may
            want to create a non-privileged user named something like 'rice' to use for this
            purpose.</para></note>
    <section>
        <title>Suggested Server Hardware</title>
        <para>Note that hardware needs may vary depending on the amount of expected load, the
            operating system being used, and the number of applications that are integrated with
            Kuali Rice. Kuali Rice is typically deployed as a standalone server with the database
            server separate from the application server. </para>
        <para>The recommended minimum requirements are as follows:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Processor 1.5 GHz or faster (2 GHz preferred)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>1024 MB (1 GB) of RAM or more</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>100 Mbit/s network card (gigabit preferred)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>200 MB of hard disk space (for Tomcat server and web application)</para>
                    <note><para>Additional space needed if storing attachments.</para></note>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>See <link linkend="appendix_server_configs">Example Server Configurations</link> in
            the appendix for examples of hardware and software configurations of Kuali Rice
            servers.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="install_db">
        <title>Installing and Configuring the Database Management System</title>
        <para>Kuali Rice was developed using two relational database management systems: <emphasis
                role="bold">MySQL</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">Oracle</emphasis>. The
            typical production install involves running the Rice server separate from the database
            server, however both can be run on the same machine for development purposes.</para>
        <para>Rice runs, and has been tested with the following versions:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Oracle</emphasis>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Oracle Database 10g</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Oracle Database 11g</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Oracle Express Edition (XE)</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>Use the Oracle JDBC Driver to connect to these databases.</para>
                <para>Ensure that the Oracle database you intend to use encodes character data in a
                    UTF variant by default. For Oracle XE, this entails downloading the "Universal"
                    flavor of the binary, which uses AL32UTF8.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">MySQL</emphasis><itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>MySQL 5.1.+</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>Use the MySQL Connector/J (5.1.+) to connect to MySQL databases.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>You should be able to adapt Rice to other standard relational databases (e.g., Sybase,
            Microsoft SQL Server, DB2, etc.). However, this Installation Guide does not provide
            information for running Rice with these products.</para>
        <section xml:id ="database_software_locations">
            <title>Locations for Database Software</title>
            <para>Below are locations from which Oracle and MySQL could be downloaded at the time of
                release of Rice ${project.version}.</para>
            <table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
                <title>Locations for Database Software</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="4.11*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Software</entry>
                            <entry>Download Location</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Oracle Standard and Enterprise Editions </entry>
                            <entry><link
                                xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/enterprise-edition/downloads/index.html"
                                >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/enterprise-edition/downloads/index.html</link></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Oracle Express Edition</entry>
                            <entry><link
                                xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/express-edition/downloads/index.html"
                                >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/express-edition/downloads/index.html</link></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Oracle JDBC DB Driver</entry>
                            <entry><link
                                xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/features/jdbc/index-091264.html"
                                >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/features/jdbc/index-091264.html</link></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>MySQL </entry>
                            <entry><link xlink:href="http://www.mysql.com/downloads/"
                                >http://www.mysql.com/downloads/</link></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>MySQL Connector/J JDBC Driver</entry>
                            <entry><link xlink:href="http://www.mysql.com/products/connector/j/"
                                >http://www.mysql.com/products/connector/j/</link></entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="mysql_db_prep">
            <title>MySQL Database Preparation</title>
            <para>Kuali Rice supports both MySQL and Oracle databases. However, MySQL is easier to
                install than Oracle and uses less machine resources so many developers prefer to use
                that when getting started with Rice.</para>
            <section>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <para>The installation steps for MySQL are going to be different for each platform.
                    Please download the latest version MySQL Server from the location listed in the
                    <link linkend="database_software_locations">Locations for Database Software</link> section of this document and follow the installation
                    instructions for your platform.</para>
                <note>
                    <para>You may be required to create an account on the MySQL site in order to
                        download the software.</para>
                    <para>Please be sure to follow the instructions for installing MySQL on your
                        platform very carefully. If downloading for Mac OS X, <emphasis role="bold"
                            >be careful</emphasis> to download the appropriate version for your
                        platform (32-bit vs. 64-bit and 10.6 vs 10.7)</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Configuration</title>
                <para>There are a few MySQL database configuration options that are required in
                    order for Kuali Rice to work properly. These will need to be set in either your
                    <emphasis role="bold">my.cnf</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold"
                        >my.ini</emphasis> file. The location and names of these files will differ
                    depending on which platform you are working on. For details on where these files
                    can be found, see the following document:</para>
                <para><link xlink:href="http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.1/en/option-files.html"
                    >http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.1/en/option-files.html</link></para>
                <para>Once you have located this file, please add the following options, paying
                    special attention to the line that needs to be commented out:</para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">[mysqld]
transaction-isolation=READ-COMMITTED
max_connections=1000 <co xml:id="max_connections-co" linkends="max_connections"/>
...
# Be sure to comment this out if it's in the file!!! <co xml:id="log_bin-co" linkends="log_bin"/>
#log-bin=mysql-bin</programlisting>
                <note>
                <calloutlist>
                    <callout arearefs="max_connections-co" xml:id="max_connections"><para>Leaving the max_connections at the default value of 151 may result in a "too many connections" error. Please see <link xlink:href="http://docs.oracle.com/cd/E17952_01/refman-5.6-en/too-many-connections.html">this link</link> for more information.</para></callout>
                </calloutlist>
                </note>
                <para>Note that the <emphasis role="bold">[mysqld]</emphasis> section may already be
                        in your my.cnf file. If so, you can just add the options listed above underneath
                        that section.</para>
                <caution>
                    <calloutlist>
                    <callout arearefs="log_bin-co" xml:id="log_bin"><para>It is very important that you comment out <emphasis role="bold"
                        >log-bin</emphasis>. Otherwise you will end up with some very bad
                        problems later!</para></callout>
                    </calloutlist>
                </caution>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Verification</title>
                <para>Before verifying your mysql installation you will need to ensure that MySQL is
                    running. Some of the platform-specific packages will set this up automatically
                    (or allow you to install yourself in the case of Mac OS X). If MySQL is not
                    starting automatically you can start it using a command like the following
                    example from Mac OS X:</para>
                <programlisting>sudo /usr/local/mysql/bin/mysqld_safe</programlisting>
                <para>This will start the MySQL server.</para>
                <para>To verify that you can actually connect to the server, execute the following
                    at the command line:</para>
                <programlisting>mysql -u root -p</programlisting>
                <para>This should bring you to a command line client interface for the MySQL server.
                    Type "show databases;" and press return. You should see output similar to the
                    following.</para>
                <programlisting>Welcome to the MySQL monitor.  Commands end with ; or \g.
Your MySQL connection id is 1
Server version: 5.1.50-log MySQL Community Server (GPL)

Copyright (c) 2000, 2010, Oracle and/or its affiliates. All rights reserved.
This software comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY. This is free software,
and you are welcome to modify and redistribute it under the GPL v2 license

Type 'help;' or '\h' for help. Type '\c' to clear the current input statement.

mysql> show databases;
+--------------------+
| Database           |
+--------------------+
| information_schema |
| mysql              |
| test               |
+--------------------+
3 rows in set (0.13 sec)

mysql> </programlisting>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Install the JDBC Driver</title>
                <para>Kuali Rice uses the MySQL Connector/J product as the native JDBC driver. Please
                    download this driver from the location specified in the <link
                        linkend="database_software_locations">Locations for Database Software</link>
                    section of this Guide.</para>
                <para>Once you have downloaded the JDBC driver that corresponds to your version of
                    MySQL, copy it to <emphasis role="bold">/java/drivers</emphasis>. <emphasis
                        role="bold">/java/drivers</emphasis> is a hard coded directory that the Rice
                    scripts use as a default directory in which to search for drivers when the
                    installation scripts are running.</para>
            </section>
        </section>    
        <section xml:id="oracle_db_prep">
            <title>Oracle Database Preparation</title>
            <section>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <para>The installation steps for Oracle are going to be different for each platform and
                    version of Oracle. Please download from the location listed in the <link
                        linkend="database_software_locations">Locations for Database Software</link>
                    section of this document and follow the installation instructions for your
                    platform.</para>
                <para>To run the database completely on your local machine, we recommend installing
                    Oracle Express (XE). Please refer to the <link linkend="database_software_locations"
                        >Locations for Database Software</link> section of this Installation Guide to
                    find the download location for this software.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Configuration</title>
                <para>By default, OracleXE registers a web user interface on port 8080. This is the
                    same port that the standalone version of Rice is preconfigured to use. To avoid
                    a port conflict, you must change the port that the OracleXE web user interface
                    uses with the Oracle XE admin webapp:
                    <figure>
                        <title>Oracle XE admin webapp</title>
                        <mediaobject>    
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/oracle_xe_admin_webapp.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                </para>
                <para>If you prefer, you can use the Oracle SQL tool described here to change the
                    OracleXE web user interface port: <link
                        xlink:href="http://daust.blogspot.com/2006/01/xe-changing-default-http-port.html"
                        >http://daust.blogspot.com/2006/01/xe-changing-default-http-port.html</link></para>
                <para>Please edit your hosts file with an entry to refer to your Oracle database.
                    When this Installation Guide refers to the Oracle database host server, it will
                    be referred to in the examples as koracle.</para>
                <para>Now edit the hosts file and add this:</para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;ip address of mysql server&gt; koracle</programlisting>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Verification</title>
                <para>To connect to the supporting Oracle database (i.e., run scripts, view database
                    tables, etc.), we recommend installing the Squirrel SQL client.  Please see the
                    <link linkend="squirrel_SQL">section on Squirrel SQL</link> for more information.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Install the JDBC Driver</title>
                <para>Kuali Rice uses the standard Oracle JDBC driver as the native JDBC driver. <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Please download this driver from the location specified in the
                                    <link linkend="database_software_locations">Locations for
                                    Database Software</link> section of this Guide.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Once you have downloaded the JDBC driver that corresponds to your
                                version of Oracle, copy it to <emphasis role="bold"
                                    >/java/drivers</emphasis>. <emphasis role="bold"
                                    >/java/drivers</emphasis> is a hard coded directory that the
                                Rice scripts use as a default directory in which to search for
                                drivers when the installation scripts are running.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Use the <link
                                    xlink:href="http://maven.apache.org/plugins/maven-install-plugin"
                                    >maven-install-plugin</link> to copy ojdbc14.jar into your local
                                maven repository.</para>
                            <programlisting>mvn install:install-file -DgroupId=com.oracle -DartifactId=ojdbc14 -Dversion=10.2.0.3.0 -Dpackaging=jar -Dfile=ojdbc14.jar</programlisting>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>You should see output similar to this if the jar gets installed
                                correctly. </para>
                            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">[INFO] Installing ojdbc14.jar to /.m2/repository/com/oracle/ojdbc14/10.2.0.3.0/ojdbc14-10.2.0.3.0.jar</programlisting>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="sql_client_sw">
            <title>Suggested SQL Client Software</title>
            <para>To examine and test your database setup, SQL client software is useful. Any SQL client
                software that will connect to a MySQL or Oracle database will work. Two tools used by
                the development team are the <emphasis role="bold">mysql</emphasis> command-line client
                and SQuirrel SQL.</para>
            <section xml:id="mysql_client_sw">
                <title>mysql client software</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">mysql</emphasis> command-line client only works with MySQL
                    and is usually installed with the MySQL Server software. An example of connection to
                    MySQL as root and then switching to a database named <emphasis role="bold"
                        >test</emphasis> can be found below:</para>
                <programlisting>Welcome to the MySQL monitor.  Commands end with ; or \g.
Your MySQL connection id is 2
Server version: 5.1.50-log MySQL Community Server (GPL)

Copyright (c) 2000, 2010, Oracle and/or its affiliates. All rights reserved.
This software comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY. This is free software,
and you are welcome to modify and redistribute it under the GPL v2 license

Type 'help;' or '\h' for help. Type '\c' to clear the current input statement.

mysql> use test;
Database changed</programlisting>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="squirrel_SQL">
                <title>SQuirrel SQL</title>
                <para>Tools like SQuirrel SQL use JDBC to access the database and will work with both
                    MySQL and Oracle databases. You can download and install it from the following
                    URL:</para>
                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><link xlink:href="http://squirrel-sql.sourceforge.net/"
                                >http://squirrel-sql.sourceforge.net/</link></para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <section>
                    <title>With MySQL</title>
                    <para>Connecting to a MySQL database with the name <emphasis role="bold">test</emphasis>
                        would have a JDBC URL like the following: <emphasis role="bold"
                            >jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/test</emphasis>.</para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>With Oracle</title>
                    <para>Connecting to an Oracle database would have a JDBC URL like the following:
                        <emphasis role="bold">jdbc:oracle:thin:@localhost:1521:XE</emphasis>.</para>
                    <para>The Rice SQL files use slash '/' as the statement delimiter. You may have to
                        configure your SQL client appropriately so it can run the Rice SQL. In SQuirreL, you
                        do this in Session->Session Properties->SQL->Statement Separator.</para>
                </section>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section> 
    <section xml:id="install_sw">
        <title>Install and Configure Required Software</title>
        <section>
            <title>Overview</title>
            <para>Kuali Rice requires the following software to be setup and configured:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Sun Microsystems Java Development Kit (JDK 1.6.x or 1.7.x)</para>
                    <warning>
                        <para>You must use a JDK and not a Java runtime environment (JRE); the JDK
                                you use must be version 1.6.x or 1.7.x. Additionally, Rice has not
                                been tested on JDKs other than Sun. So alternative implementations
                                like OpenJDK should be used at your own risk.</para>
                    </warning>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Maven 3</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="environment_variables">
            <title>Environment Variables</title>
            <para>First, some environment variables need to be configured.</para>
                <section>
                    <title>Mac OS X</title>
                    <para>Environment variables in Mac OS X can be set in a number of ways, but here we will
                        show how to modify or create the .profile files in your user home directory. On OS X
                        your user home directory is typically located at /Users/&lt;username>,</para>
                    <para>An example .profile can be found below:</para>
                    <programlisting>M2_HOME=/usr/local/maven
MAVEN_OPTS="-Xmx1024m -XX:MaxPermSize=768m"
GROOVY_HOME=/usr/local/groovy
JAVA_HOME=/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/1.7/Home
CATALINA_HOME=/usr/local/tomcat
MYSQL_HOME=/usr/local/mysql
    
PATH="$ANT_HOME/bin:$M2_HOME/bin:$GROOVY_HOME/bin:$CATALINA_HOME:$MYSQL_HOME/bin:$PATH"
export PATH ANT_HOME ANT_OPTS M2_HOME MAVEN_OPTS GROOVY_HOME JAVA_HOME CATALINA_HOME MYSQL_HOME</programlisting>
                    <note><para>It is important to export your environment variables once they are defined as the
                        file above does.</para></note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Windows XP</title>
                    <para>To get to the screen where you can define environment variables on Windows XP
                        follow these steps:<orderedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Click on the "Start" button in the bottom left-hand corner.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>On the resulting screen, right click on "My Computer".</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>In the context menu, click on "Properties".</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>This will open up the "System Properties" dialog window.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Click on the "Advanced" tab.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Click on the "Environment Variables" button.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>You will see the screen where you can edit existing
                                environment variables or define new ones.</para>
<!--                                <para>&lt;TODO: Insert screen shot here></para>     -->
                            </listitem>
                        </orderedlist></para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Windows Vista and Windows 7</title>
                    <para>To get to the screen where you can define environment variables on Windows Vista
                        or Windows 7 follow these steps:<orderedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Click on the "Start" button in the bottom left-hand corner.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>On the resulting screen, right click on "Computer".</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para>In the context menu, click on "Properties".</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>This will open up the Control Panel "System" dialog.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Click on the "Advanced system settings".</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>In the resulting window, click on the "Environment Variables..."
                                    button.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>You will see the screen where you can edit existing environment
                                    variables or define new ones.</para>
<!--                                <para>&lt;TODO: Insert screen shot here></para> -->
                            </listitem>
                        </orderedlist></para>
                    <note><para>The windows command line console must be closed and reopened in order for environment
                       variable changes to be effective.</para></note>
                </section>
        </section> 
       <section xml:id="Java_SDK">
            <title>Java SDK</title>
            <section>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <para>You should download and install the latest version of JDK 6 or JDK 7. If you
                    are on Windows, you can download it from the following URL: <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html"
                        >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html</link>.</para>
                <para>If you are on a Mac, then Java 6 or Java 7 should already be installed if you
                    are up to date with the latest updates from Apple.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Configuration</title>
                <para>You will also want to set up your <emphasis role="bold">JAVA_HOME</emphasis>
                    environment variable to point to the installation directory of your JDK. In both
                    Windows and Mac environments, the <emphasis role="bold">java</emphasis> executable
                    program should already be on your path. But if it is not, you will want to include
                    <emphasis role="bold">JAVA_HOME/bin</emphasis> in your <emphasis role="bold"
                        >PATH</emphasis> environment variable.</para>
                <para>If you do not know how to do this, see the <command
                    linkend="environment_variables">Environment Variables</command> section above
                    for your platform.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Verification</title>
                <para>In order to verify that your JDK has been installed successfully, open a command
                    prompt and type the following:</para>
                <programlisting>java -version</programlisting>
                <para>You should see output similar to the following:</para>
                <programlisting>java version "1.7.0_10"
Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.7.0_10-b18)
Java HotSpot(TM) Client VM (build 23.6-b04, mixed mode)</programlisting>
                <para>If you receive an error indicating that the "java" command could not be found,
                    please ensure that the java command is on your machine's <emphasis role="bold"
                        >PATH</emphasis> environment variable.</para>
              <para>To prevent potential out of memory errors when running Rice,
                you should set your <emphasis role="bold">JAVA_OPTS</emphasis> environment to a
                value like the following:</para>
              <programlisting>JAVA_OPTS="-Xmx1024m -XX:MaxPermSize=768m"</programlisting>
              <para>If you do not know how to do this, see the <link
                      linkend="environment_variables">Environment Variables</link> section above
                for your platform.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <!-- TODO: Determine if we need to add a section for ant or if we're done here -->
        <section xml:id="Maven">
            <title>Maven</title>
            <para>Maven is the primary build tool used by the Kuali Rice project. Maven is based on a
                project object model (POM) that defines various standards and conventions surrounding
                the organization of a project. This facilitates a set of standard build goals and
                lifecycle phases (such as compile, test, package, etc.)</para>
            <section>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <para>To download version 3 of Maven, use the following link: <link
                    xlink:href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html"
                    >http://maven.apache.org/download.html</link></para>
                <para>Once you have downloaded the zip file, unzip it to a location of your
                    choosing.</para>
            </section>    
            <section>
                <title>Configuration</title>
                <para>You will want to set your <emphasis role="bold">M2_HOME</emphasis> environment
                    variable to point to the location where you unzipped Maven. You will additionally
                    want to include <emphasis role="bold">M2_HOME/bin</emphasis> in your <emphasis
                        role="bold">PATH</emphasis> environment variable so that maven can be executed
                    from the command line without having to specify the full path.</para>
                <para>Finally, to prevent potential out of memory errors when compiling Rice with Maven,
                    you should set your <emphasis role="bold">MAVEN_OPTS</emphasis> environment to a
                    value like the following:</para>
                <programlisting>MAVEN_OPTS="-Xmx1024m -XX:MaxPermSize=768m"</programlisting>
                <para>If you do not know how to do this, see the <link
                    linkend="environment_variables">Environment Variables</link> section above
                    for your platform.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Verification</title>
                <para>In order to verify that Maven has been installed successfully and is available on
                    the path, open a command prompt and type the following:</para>
                <programlisting>mvn -version</programlisting>
                <para>You should see output like the following:</para>
                <programlisting>Apache Maven 3.0.3 (r1075438; 2011-02-28 10:31:09-0700)
Maven home: /usr/local/maven
Java version: 1.6.0_26, vendor: Apple Inc.
Java home: /System/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/1.6.0.jdk/Contents/Home
Default locale: en_US, platform encoding: MacRoman
OS name: "mac os x", version: "10.7.2", arch: "x86_64", family: "mac"</programlisting>
                <para>If you receive an error indicating hat the "mvn" command could not be found,
                    please ensure that the directory that includes the mvn executable (<emphasis
                        role="bold">M2_HOME/bin</emphasis>) is on your machine's <emphasis role="bold"
                            >PATH</emphasis> environment variable.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="Apache_Tomcat">
            <title>Install and Setup Apache Tomcat</title>
            <para>Kuali Rice ${project.version} supports the following Tomcat versions:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Tomcat 6 (Servlet API 2.5, JSP 2.1) </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Tomcat 7 (Servlet API 3.0, JSP 2.2) </para>
                    </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Please visit the <link xlink:href="http://tomcat.apache.org/">Apache Tomcat
                    site</link> for information on how to install and configure Tomcat.</para>
            <para>Other servlet containers can be used with Kuali Rice, but this guide will focus on
                Tomcat.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="Rice_SW">
            <title>Install Rice software from distribution</title>
            <para>The quickest way to get Rice installed on a standalone server is to download the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Standalone Server</emphasis> distribution from the <link
                    xlink:href="http://kuali.org/rice/download">kuali.org download site</link>. Once
                downloaded, decompress the software.</para>
        </section>
    </section>    
    <section xml:id="Rice_DB">
        <title>Building the Rice Database</title>
        <section>
            <title>Load Impex Data with Maven</title>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Change to the directory <emphasis role="bold">db/impex</emphasis> located
                        where you decompressed the software.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Decide which type of server you want to install.
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>If you want to install a full Rice development environment, change
                                to the directory <emphasis role="bold">master</emphasis>.  This will
                                create a database named <emphasis role="bold">RICE</emphasis> by default.
                                This is the recommended way to get started developing with Rice.
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>If you want a production standalone Rice install, change to the
                                directory <emphasis role="bold">server/bootstrap</emphasis>.  This will
                                create a database named <emphasis role="bold">RICESERVERBOOTSTRAP</emphasis>
                                by default.
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>If you want to install some demonstration data on top of the production
                                standalone Rice install, change to the directory <emphasis role="bold">server/demo</emphasis>.
                                This will create a database named <emphasis role="bold">RICESERVERDEMO</emphasis>
                                by default.
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                The <emphasis role="bold">client</emphasis> folder is for client applications
                                that connect to Rice separately and is not needed at this stage.
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <note>Selecting to install the master or demo databases is for testing only.  There
                            is no easy way to remove this data once it is in your database.  Only select these
                            options if you are in a development or testing environment.</note>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Verify that Maven can connect to your database instance.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis role="bold">Running Locally:</emphasis>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>MySQL</para>
                                <programlisting>mvn validate -Pdb,mysql -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword]</programlisting>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Oracle</para>
                                <programlisting>mvn validate -Pdb,oracle -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword]</programlisting>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis role="bold">Connecting to a remote database:</emphasis>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>MySQL</para>
                                <programlisting>mvn validate -Pdb,mysql -Dimpex.dba.url=jdbc:mysql://[your-mysql-instance]/ -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword]</programlisting>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Oracle</para>
                                <programlisting>mvn validate -Pdb,oracle -Dimpex.url=jdbc:oracle:thin:@[your-oracle-server]:1521:XE -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword]</programlisting>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Some setup may be necessary if the setup for connecting as an administrator to your
                          database differs from the base install.  For example, if the username to connect to
                          the database engine (often known as the 'admin' or 'root' user) is different in your
                          setup, then you may have to add the following parameter:
                          <programlisting>-Dimpex.dba.username=[dbaUsername]</programlisting>
                          If for MySQL the 'root' user does not have a password (which is the default on a new
                          install), you can either remove the parameter altogether:
                          <programlisting>mvn validate -Pdb,mysql</programlisting>
                          or specify 'NONE':
                          <programlisting>mvn validate -Pdb,mysql -Dimpex.dba.password=NONE</programlisting>
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Review the options for creating your database.  The commands in the next step
                        will verify the connection and create a new user and schema based on the default name.
                        So, if you choose to install inside the <emphasis role="bold">master</emphasis>
                        directory, it will create a user and schema named <emphasis role="bold">RICE</emphasis>.
                        If you wish to change this, you can add one or more of these options to the following
                        commands.
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <emphasis role="bold">-Dimpex.username=[username]</emphasis>: Controls the user
                                name that is created to access the schema.
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <emphasis role="bold">-Dimpex.password=[password]</emphasis>: Controls the password
                                for the user that is created to access the schema.
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <emphasis role="bold">-Dimpex.database=[database]</emphasis>: (MySQL only) Controls
                                the schema name that is created.
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Load the data set.</para>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Running Locally:</emphasis><itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>MySQL</para>
                            <programlisting>mvn clean install -Pdb,mysql -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword] </programlisting>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Oracle</para>
                            <programlisting>mvn clean install -Pdb,oracle -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword] </programlisting>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Connecting to a remote database:</emphasis><itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>MySQL</para>
                            <programlisting>mvn clean install -Pdb,mysql  -Dimpex.dba.url=jdbc:mysql://[your-mysql-instance]/ -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword] </programlisting>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Oracle</para>
                            <programlisting>mvn clean install -Pdb,oracle -Dimpex.url=jdbc:oracle:thin:@[your-oracle-server]:1521:XE  -Dimpex.dba.password=[dbapassword] </programlisting>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Wait for the maven process to build your database (it may take a little
                        while, especially if this is the first time you've done it and maven has to
                        download impex and other plugins).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You should get the following message at the end of the process.</para>
                    <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] BUILD SUCCESS
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------ </programlisting>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Verifying your Database Installation</title>
            <para>At this point, your Kuali Rice database should be successfully installed. To
                verify this, log into your database and verify the number of tables that are
                present. There should be at least 200 (the number will be different for mysql and
                oracle).</para>
        </section>
    </section>    
    <section xml:id="Rice_Config">
        <title>Configure Rice</title>
        <section>
            <title>Deploying the WAR file</title>
            <para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Copy the kr-dev.war file from the base directory of the server
                            distribution to the directory that contains web applications in your
                            servlet container. For Tomcat, this is <emphasis role="bold"
                                >[Tomcat-root-directory]/webapps</emphasis>.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Copy the database-specific JDBC driver to the
                        [Tomcat-root-directory]/lib. Examples:</para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>MySQL</para>
                                <para>
                                    <programlisting>cp -p /java/drivers/mysql-connector-java-5.1.5-bin.jar /usr/local/tomcat/lib</programlisting>
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Oracle</para>
                                <para>
                                    <programlisting>cp -p /java/drivers/ojdbc14.jar /usr/local/tomcat/lib</programlisting>
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                <listitem><para>Configure the rice-config.xml File. By default when it starts, Rice attempts to read the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >rice-config.xml</emphasis> configuration file from the paths in this order:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>/usr/local/rice/rice-config.xml </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>${rice.base}../../../conf/rice-config.xml </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>${rice.base}../../conf/rice-config.xml </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>${additional.config.locations} </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
                <para>The value for <emphasis role="bold">rice.base</emphasis> is calculated using
                    different locations until a valid location is found. Kuali calculates it using
                    these locations in this sequence:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>ServletContext.getRealPath("/") </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">catalina.base</emphasis> system property
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>The current working directory</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
                <para>On Windows it also checks the following location:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>%USERPROFILE%\kuali\main\dev</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                </para>
                <para>An example <emphasis role="bold">rice-config.xml</emphasis> file is included
                    in the server distribution under
                    <emphasis role="bold">config/web/src/main/config/example-config</emphasis>.
                </para>
                <para>Modify the following database parameters in the
                    <emphasis role="bold">rice-config.xml</emphasis> file.  The values should conform
                    to the values you selected in the
                    <link linkend="Rice_DB">Building the Rice Database</link> section of this guide.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <programlisting>datasource.url=jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/rice
datasource.username=rice
datasource.password=rice
datasource.url=jdbc:mysql://remoteMySQLServerComputerName:3306/rice
datasource.username=rice
datasource.password=rice</programlisting>
                    </para>
                    <para>If you are using Oracle, the JDBC URL will have this
                        general form:</para>
                    <para>
                        <programlisting>datasource.url=jdbc:oracle:thin:@remoteMySQLServerComputerName:1521:ORACLE_SID</programlisting>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>At this point, you are ready to try to bring up the Tomcat
                        server with the Rice web application:</para>
                    <para>
                        <programlisting>cd /usr/local/tomcat/bin
./startup.sh</programlisting>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>    
                    <para>Check if Tomcat and Rice started successfully:</para>
                    <para>
                        <programlisting>cd /usr/local/tomcat/logs
tail -n 500 -f catalina.out</programlisting>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If your Rice server started up successfully, browse to the
                        site <emphasis role="bold"
                            >http://yourlocalip:8080/kr-dev</emphasis>. You should
                        see the Rice portal screen which will look something like
                        this: </para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Rice Portal Main Menu</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/rice_portal_main_menu.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
            </listitem></orderedlist>
            </para>
            </section>
             <section xml:id="rice_config_parameters"> 
                    <title>Parameters</title>
                <para>The tables below have the basic set of parameters for <emphasis role="bold"
                    >rice-config.xml</emphasis> that you need to get an instance of Rice running.
                Please use these tables as a beginning reference to modify your <emphasis
                    role="bold">rice-config.xml</emphasis> file. </para>
                <warning>
                    <para>Make sure the <emphasis role="bold">application.url</emphasis> and
                        database user name and password are set correctly.</para>
                </warning>  
                <table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
                    <title>Core </title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.56*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.39*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Parameter</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                                <entry>Examples or Values</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>application.url </entry>
                                <entry>The external URL used to access the Rice web
                                    interface; edit only the fully-qualified domain name and
                                    port of the server </entry>
                                <entry>http://yourlocalip:8080/kuali-rice-url</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>app.context.name</entry>
                                <entry><para>Context name of the web application</para>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                          <para>Essentially, the name of the WAR file</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                          <para>Used to build the path for images and help
                                          URLs</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                                <entry>kuali-rice-url
                                    (This value should not be changed)
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry><para>context.names._____</para><para>*See note below</para></entry>
                                <entry><para>The context name of each web application, including
                                    Rice, needs to be specified when the supplied portal is used. The parameter must start with "context.names." and may have a suffix of your choice (i.e. context.names.rice, context.names.kfs, context.names.kc)</para>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>context.names.app defaults to app.context.name (i.e. no configuration needed for bundled setup or the server that hosts the portal)</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>No configuration needed when the application context name is blank</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>Used with default iframe portal when accessing servers</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                                <entry>kuali-rice-web-app-url
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>log4j.settings.path </entry>
                                <entry>Path to log4j.properties file. If the file does not
                                    exist, you must create it.</entry>
                                <entry>/usr/local/rice/log4j.properties</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>log4j.settings.reloadInterval</entry>
                                <entry>interval (in minutes) to check for changes to the
                                    log4j.properties file</entry>
                                <entry>5</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>mail.smtp.host</entry>
                                <entry>SMTP host name or IP (This param is not in the
                                    default config.) </entry>
                                <entry>localhost</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>config.location</entry>
                                <entry>Location of configuration file to load
                                    environment-specific configuration parameters (This
                                    param is not in the default config.) </entry>
                                <entry>/usr/local/rice/rice-config-${environment}.xml</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>sample.enabled</entry>
                                <entry>Enable the sample application</entry>
                                <entry>boolean</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                 <note><para>*context.names.____: Each content source that is served from an application server that uses a
                    context name will need a context.names.&lt;webappcontext> parameter. Replace the
                    &lt;webappcontext> with a unique suffix of your choosing. Specify the context
                    name of the web application server as the value of this parameter.</para><para>By default context.names.app is set to app.context.name. This allows bundled mode usage
                    without additional configuration. With standalone mode, the server that hosts
                    the portal also doesn't need any additional configurations thanks to
                    context.names.app.</para><para>
                         
                             <emphasis role="bold">Example:</emphasis> KFS is used with a standalone Rice server.</para><para>
                         
                         KFS URL:http://www.example.com:8080/kfs-test/portal.do</para><para>
                         Rice URL:http://www.example.com:8080/rice-test/portal.do</para><para>
                         
                         The following additional configuration is needed in the kfs-config.xml:</para><para>
                         
                             <code>&lt;param name="context.names.rice">rice-test&lt;/param></code></para><para> A <code>&lt;param name="context.names.kfs">kfs-test&lt;/param></code> is not needed since
                    "kfs-test" is specified as the app.context.name.</para>
                     <para>
                         
                         <emphasis role="bold">Example:</emphasis> KFS is used with a standalone Rice server.</para><para>
                         
                         KFS URL:http://www.example.com:8080/kfs-test/portal.do</para><para>
                             Rice URL:http://www.example.com:8080/portal.do</para><para>
                         
                         
                         No additional configuration is needed.
                         Specifying <code>&lt;param name="context.names.rice">&lt;/param></code> would be acceptable as well.</para><para>
                         
                             <emphasis role="bold">Example:</emphasis> KFS is used with bundled Rice server.
                         No additional configuration is needed.
                 </para></note>
            <table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
                <title>Database</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.2*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.55*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="2.14*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Parameter</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                            <entry>Examples or Values</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.ojb.platform </entry>
                                <entry>Name of OJB platform to use for the database </entry>
                                <entry>Oracle9i or MySQL</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.platform </entry>
                                <entry>Rice platform implementation for the database </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>org.kuali.rice.core.framework.persistence.platform.DerbyPlatform</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>org.kuali.rice.core.framework.persistence.platform.OraclePlatform</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>org.kuali.rice.core.framework.persistence.platform.MySQLDatabasePlatform
                                          </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.driver.name </entry>
                                <entry>JDBC driver for the database </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                          <para>org.apache.derby.jdbc.EmbeddedDriver,</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                          <para>oracle.jdbc.driver.OracleDriver</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                          <para>com.mysql.jdbc.Driver </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.username </entry>
                                <entry>User name for connecting to the server database </entry>
                                <entry>rice</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.password </entry>
                                <entry>Password for connecting to the server database </entry>
                                <entry/>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.url </entry>
                                <entry>JDBC URL of database to connect to </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>jdbc:oracle:thin:@localhost:1521:XE</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/kuldemo </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.pool.minSize </entry>
                                <entry>Minimum number of connections to hold in the pool </entry>
                                <entry>an integer value suitable for your environment</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.pool.maxSize </entry>
                                <entry>Maximum number of connections to allocate in the pool </entry>
                                <entry>an integer value suitable for your environment</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.pool.maxWait </entry>
                                <entry>Maximum amount of time (in ms) to wait for a connection from
                                    the pool </entry>
                                <entry>10000</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>datasource.pool.validationQuery </entry>
                                <entry>Query to validate connections from the database </entry>
                                <entry>select 1 from dual</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
                    <title>KSB</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.55*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="2.34*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Parameter</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                                <entry>Examples or Values</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>serviceServletUrl </entry>
                                <entry>URL that maps to the KSBDispatcherServlet (include a trailing
                                    slash); This param is not in the default config. </entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>keystore.file </entry>
                                <entry>Path to the keystore file to use for security </entry>
                                <entry>/usr/local/rice/rice.keystore</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>keystore.alias </entry>
                                <entry>Alias of the standalone server's key </entry>
                                <entry>see section entitled Generating the Keystore</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>keystore.password </entry>
                                <entry>Password to access the keystore and the server's key </entry>
                                <entry>see section entitled Generating the Keystore</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table> 
                <table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
                    <title>KEN</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.55*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="2.34*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Parameter</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                                <entry>Examples or Values</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>notification.basewebappurl </entry>
                                <entry>Base URL of the KEN web application (This param is not in the
                                    default config.) </entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table> 
                <table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
                    <title>KEW</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.55*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="2.34*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Parameter</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                                <entry>Examples or Values</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>workflow.url </entry>
                                <entry>URL to the KEW web module</entry>
                                <entry>${application.url}/kew</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>plugin.dir </entry>
                                <entry>Directory from which plugins will be loaded </entry>
                                <entry>/usr/local/rice/plugins</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>attachment.dir.location </entry>
                                <entry>Directory where attachments will be stored (This param is not
                                    in the default config.) </entry>
                                <entry/>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>   
              </section>     
            </section>
    <section xml:id="keystore">
        <title>Setup a Keystore</title>
        <para>For client applications to consume secured services hosted from a Rice server, you
            must generate a keystore. As an initial setup, you can use the keystore provided by
            Rice. Once a keystore is generated, you must configure the KSB to use the
            keystore.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Generating a Keystore</title>
            <para>There are three ways to get this keystore:<orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If you are doing a source code build of Rice, it is in the directory <emphasis
                        role="bold">&lt;source root>/security</emphasis> and it has a file name of
                        <emphasis role="bold">rice.keystore</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The keystore is also located in the server distribution under the security
                        directory. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can generate the keystore yourself. Please refer to the <link xlink:href="http://site.kuali.org/rice/${project.version}/reference/html/KSB_Guide.html#security_and_keystores">Security and Keystores</link> 
                        section in the KSB Guide for the steps to accomplish this.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist></para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configure KSB to use the keystore</title>
            <para>You must have these params in the xml config to allow KSB to use the keystore:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;param name="keystore.file">/usr/local/rice/rice.keystore&lt;/param>
&lt;param name="keystore.alias">rice&lt;/param>
&lt;param name="keystore.password">r1c3pw&lt;/param>            </programlisting>
            </para>    
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>keystore.file - The location of the keystore</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>keystore.alias - The alias used in creating the keystore above</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>keystore.password - This is the password of the alias AND the keystore. This
                        assumes that the keystore is set up so that these are the same. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
