<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2013 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<glossary xml:id="glossary" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Glossary</title>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>A</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.action.list">
            <glossterm>Action List</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A list of the user's notification and workflow items. Also called the user's
                    Notification List. Clicking an item in the Action List displays details about
                    that notification, if the item is a notification, or displays that document, if
                    it is a workflow item. The user will usually load the document from their Action
                    List in order to take the requested action against it, such as approving or
                    acknowledging the document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.action.list.type">
            <glossterm>Action List Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This tells you if the Action List item is a notification or a more specific
                    workflow request item. When the Action List item is a notification, the Action
                    List Type is "Notification."</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.action.request">
            <glossterm>Action Request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A request to a user or Workgroup to take action on a document. It designates
                    the type of action that is requested, which includes:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approve: requests an approve or disapprove action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Complete: requests a completion of the contents of a document. This
                            action request is displayed in the Action List after the user saves an
                            incomplete document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Acknowledge: requests an acknowledgment by the user that the document
                            has been opened - the doc will not leave the Action List until
                            acknowledgment has occurred; however, the document routing will not be
                            held up and the document will be permitted to transaction into the
                            processed state if neccessary.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>FYI: a notification to the user regarding the document. Documents
                            requesting FYI can be cleared directly from the Action List. Even if a
                            document has FYI requests remaining, it will still be permitted to
                            transition into the FINAL state.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.action.request.hierarchy">
            <glossterm>Action Request Hierarchy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Action requests are hierarchical in nature and can have one parent and
                    multiple children.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.action.requested">
            <glossterm>Action Requested</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>The action one needs to take on a document; also the type of action that
                        is requested by an Action Request. Actions that may be requested of a user
                        are: </para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Acknowledge: requests that the users states he or she has reviewed the
                            document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approve: requests that the user either Approve or Disapprove a
                            document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Complete: requests the user to enter additional information in a
                            document so that the content of the document is complete.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>FYI: intended to simply makes a user aware of the document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.action.taken">
            <glossterm>Action Taken</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>An action taken on a document by a <glossterm linkend="glossary.reviewer"
                            >Reviewer</glossterm> in response to an Action Request. The Action Taken
                        may be:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Acknowledged: Reviewer has viewed and acknowledged document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approved: Reviewer has approved the action requested on
                            document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Blanket Approved: Reviewer has requested a blanket approval up to a
                            specified point in the route path on the document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Canceled: Reviewer has canceled the document. The document will not be
                            routed to any more reviewers.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Cleared FYI: Reviewer has viewed the document and cleared all of his
                            or her pending FYI(s) on this document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Completed: Reviewer has completed and supplied all data requested on
                            document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Created Document: User has created a document</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Disapproved: Reviewer has disapproved the document. The document will
                            not being routed to any subsequent reviewers for approval. Acknowledge
                            Requests are sent to previous approvers to inform them of the
                            disapproval.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Logged Document: Reviewer has added a message to the Route Log of the
                            document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Moved Document: Reviewer has moved the document either backward or
                            forward in its routing path.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Returned to Previous Node: Reviewer has returned the document to a
                            previous routing node. When a Reviewer does this, all the actions taken
                            between the current node and the return node are removed and all the
                            pending requests on the document are deactivated.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Routed Document: Reviewer has submitted the document to the workflow
                            engine for routing.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Saved: Reviewer has saved the document for later completion and
                            routing.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Approved Document: <glossterm linkend="glossary.superuser"
                                >Superuser</glossterm> has approved the entire document, any
                            remaining routing is cancelled.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Approved Node: Superuser has approved the document through
                            all nodes up to (but not including) a specific node. When the document
                            gets to that node, the normal Action Requests will be created.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Approved Request: Superuser has approved a single pending
                            Approve or Complete Action Request. The document then goes to the next
                            routing node.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Cancelled: Superuser has canceled the document. A Superuser
                            can cancel a document without a pending Action Request to him/her on the
                            document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Disapproved: Superuser has disapproved the document. A
                            Superuser can disapprove a document without a pending Action Request to
                            him/her on the document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Returned to Previous Node: Superuser has returned the
                            document to a previous routing node. A Superuser can do this without a
                            pending Action Request to him/her on the document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.activated">
            <glossterm>Activated</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The state of an action request when it is has been sent to a user's Action
                    List.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.activation">
            <glossterm>Activation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which requests appear in a user's Action List</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.activation.type">
            <glossterm>Activation Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Defines how a route node handles activation of Action Requests. There are two
                    standard activation types:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Sequential: Action Requests are activated one at a time based on
                            routing priority. The next Action Request isn't activated until the
                            previous request is satisfied.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Parallel: All Action Requests at the route node are activated
                            immediately, regardless of priority</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.active.indicator">
            <glossterm>Active Indicator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An indicator specifying whether an object in the system is active or not. Used
                    as an alternative to complete removal of an object.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.ad.hoc.routing">
            <glossterm>Ad Hoc Routing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of routing used to route a document to users or groups that are not in
                    the Routing path for that Document Type. When the Ad Hoc Routing is complete,
                    the routing returns to its normal path.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.annotation">
            <glossterm>Annotation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Optional comments added by a <glossterm linkend="glossary.reviewer"
                        >Reviewer</glossterm> when taking action. Intended to explain or clarify the
                    action taken or to advise subsequent Reviewers.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.approve">
            <glossterm>Approve</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of workflow action button. Signifies that the document represents a
                    valid business transaction in accordance with institutional needs and policies
                    in the user's judgment. A single document may require approval from several
                    users, at multiple route levels, before it moves to final status.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.approver">
            <glossterm>Approver</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The user who approves the document. As a document moves through Workflow, it
                    moves one route level at a time. An Approver operates at a particular route
                    level of the document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.attachment">
            <glossterm>Attachment</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The pathname of a related file to attach to a Note. Use the "Browse..." button
                    to open the file dialog, select the file and automatically fill in the
                    pathname.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.attribute.type">
            <glossterm>Attribute Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Used to strongly type or categorize the values that can be stored for the
                    various attributes in the system (e.g., the value of the arbitrary key/value
                    pairs that can be defined and associated with a given parent object in the
                    system).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.authentication">
            <glossterm>Authentication</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The act of logging into the system. The Out of the box (OOTB) authenticaton
                    implementation in Rice does not require a password as it is intended for testing
                    puposes only. This is something that must be enabled as part of an
                    implementation. Various authentication solutions exist, such as CAS or
                    Shibboleth, that an implementer may want to use depending on their needs.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.authorization">
            <glossterm>Authorization</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authorization is the permissions that an authenticated user has for performing
                    actions in the system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.author.universal.id">
            <glossterm>Author Universal ID</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A free-form text field for the full name of the Author of the Note, expressed
                    as "Lastname, Firstname Initial"</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>B</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.base.rule.attribute">
            <glossterm>Base Rule Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The standard fields that are defined and collected for every <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.routing.rule">Routing Rule</glossterm> These
                    include:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Active: A true/false flag to indicate if the Routing Rule is active.
                            If false, then the rule will not be evaluated during routing.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Document Type: The <glossterm linkend="glossary.document.type"
                                >Document Type</glossterm> to which the Routing Rule applies.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>From Date: The inclusive start date from which the Routing Rule will
                            be considered for a match.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Force Action: a true/false flag to indicate if the review should be
                            forced to take action again for the requests generated by this rule,
                            even if they had taken action on the document previously.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Name: the name of the rule, this serves as a unique identifier for the
                            rule. If one is not specified when the rule is created, then it will be
                            generated.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Rule Template: The Rule Template used to create the Routing
                            Rule.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>To Date: The inclusive end date to which the Routing Rule will be
                            considered for a match.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.blanket.approval">
            <glossterm>Blanket Approval</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authority that is given to designated <glossterm linkend="glossary.reviewer"
                        >Reviewers</glossterm> who can approve a document to a chosen route point. A
                    Blanket Approval bypasses approvals that would otherwise be required in the
                        <glossterm linkend="glossary.routing">Routing</glossterm> For an authorized
                    Reviewer, the <glossterm linkend="glossary.doc.handler">Doc Handler</glossterm>
                    typically displays the Blanket Approval button along with the other options.
                    When a Blanket Approval is used, the Reviewers who are skipped are sent
                    Acknowledge requests to notify them that they were bypassed.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.blanket.approve.workgroup">
            <glossterm>Blanket Approve Workgroup</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workgroup that has the authority to Blanket Approve a document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.branch">
            <glossterm>Branch</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A path containing one or more Route Nodes that a document traverses during
                    routing. When a document enters a <glossterm linkend="glossary.split.node">Split
                        Node</glossterm> multiple branches can be created. A <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.join.node">Join Node</glossterm> joins multiple branches
                    together.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.business.rule">
            <glossterm>Business Rule</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Describes the operations, definitions and constraints that apply to an
                            organization in achieving its goals.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A restriction to a function for a business reason (such as making a
                            specific object code unavailable for a particular type of disbursement).
                            Customizable business rules are controlled by Parameters.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>C</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.campus">
            <glossterm>Campus</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Identifies the different fiscal and physical operating entities of an
                    institution.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.campus.type">
            <glossterm>Campus Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Designates a campus as physical only, fiscal only or both.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.cancel">
            <glossterm>Cancel</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action available to document initiators on documents that have not
                    yet been routed for approval. Denotes that the document is void and should be
                    disregarded. Canceled documents cannot be modified in any way and do not route
                    for approval.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.canceled">
            <glossterm>Canceled</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing status. The document is denoted as void and should be
                    disregarded.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.cas">
            <glossterm>CAS - Central Authentication Service</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para><link xlink:href="http://www.jasig.org/cas"/> - An open source authentication
                    framework. Kuali Rice provides support for integrating with CAS as an
                    authentication provider (among other authentication solutions) and also provides
                    an implementation of a CAS server that integrates with Kuali Identity
                    Management.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.client">
            <glossterm>Client</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Java Application Program Interface (API) for interfacing with the Kuali
                    Enterprise Workflow Engine.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.client.server">
            <glossterm>Client/Server</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The use of one computer to request the services of another computer over a
                    network. The workstation in an organization will be used to initiate a business
                    transaction (e.g., a budget transfer). This workstation needs to gather
                    information from a remote database to process the transaction, and will
                    eventually be used to post new or changed information back onto that remote
                    database. The workstation is thus a Client and the remote computer that houses
                    the database is the Server.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.close">
            <glossterm>Close</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action available on documents in most statuses. Signifies that the
                    user wishes to exit the document. No changes to Action Requests, Route Logs or
                    document status occur as a result of a Close action. If you initiate a document
                    and close it without saving, it is the same as canceling that document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.comma.separated.value">
            <glossterm>Comma-separated value</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A file format using commas as delimiters utilized in import and export
                    functionality.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.complete">
            <glossterm>Complete</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A pending action request to a user to submit a saved document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.completed">
            <glossterm>Completed</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The action taken by a user or group in response to a request in order to
                    finish populating a document with information, as evidenced in the Document
                    Route Log.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.country.restricted.indicator">
            <glossterm>Country Restricted Indicator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Field used to indicate if a country is restricted from use in procurement. If
                    there is no value then there is no restriction.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.creation.date">
            <glossterm>Creation Date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which a document is created.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="csv">
            <glossterm>CSV</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <glossterm linkend="glossary.comma.separated.value">comma-separated
                        value</glossterm></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>D</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.date.approved">
            <glossterm>Date Approved</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which a document was most recently approved.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.date.finalized">
            <glossterm>Date Finalized</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which a document enters the FINAL state. At this point, all
                    approvals and acknowledgments are complete for the document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.deactivation">
            <glossterm>Deactivation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which requests are removed from a user's <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.action.list">Action List</glossterm></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.delegate">
            <glossterm>Delegate</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user who has been registered to act on behalf of another user. The Delegate
                    acts with the full authority of the Delegator. Delegation may be either
                        <glossterm linkend="glossary.primary.delegate">Primary
                        Delegation</glossterm> or <glossterm linkend="glossary.secondary.delegate"
                        >Secondary Delegation</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.delegate.action.list">
            <glossterm>Delegate Action List</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A separate Action List for Delegate actions. When a Delegate selects a
                    Delegator for whom to act, an Action List of all documents sent to the Delegator
                    is displayed.</para>
                <para>For both <glossterm linkend="glossary.primary.delegate">Primary</glossterm>
                    and <glossterm linkend="glossary.secondary.delegate">Secondary
                        Delegation</glossterm> the Delegate may act on any of the entries with the
                    full authority of the Delegator.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.disapprove">
            <glossterm>Disapprove</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action that allows a user to indicate that a document does not
                    represent a valid business transaction in that user's judgment. The initiator
                    and previous approvers will receive Acknowledgment requests indicating the
                    document was disapproved.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.disapproved">
            <glossterm>Disapproved</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A status that indicates the document has been disapproved by an approver as a
                    valid transaction and it will not generate the originally intended
                    transaction.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.doc.handler">
            <glossterm>Doc Handler</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Doc Handler is a web interface that a Client uses for the appropriate
                    display of a document. When a user opens a document from the Action List or
                    Document Search, the Doc Handler manages access permissions, content format, and
                    user options according to the requirements of the Client.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.doc.handler.url">
            <glossterm>Doc Handler URL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The URL for the <glossterm linkend="glossary.doc.handler">Doc
                        Handler</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.doc.nbr">
            <glossterm>Doc Nbr</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <glossterm linkend="glossary.document.number">Document
                    Number</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document">
            <glossterm>Document</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Also see <glossterm linkend="glossary.e-doc">E-Doc</glossterm>.</para>
                <para>An electronic document containing information for a business transaction that
                    is routed for Actions in KEW. It includes information such as Document ID, Type,
                    Title, Route Status, Initiator, Date Created, etc. In KEW, a document typically
                    has XML content attached to it that is used to make routing decisions.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.id">
            <glossterm>Document Id</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <glossterm linkend="glossary.document.number">Document
                    Number</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.number">
            <glossterm>Document Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A unique, sequential, system-assigned number for a document</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.operation">
            <glossterm>Document Operation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow screen that provides an interface for authorized users to
                    manipulate the XML and other data that defines a document in workflow. It allows
                    you to access and open a document by Document ID for the purpose of performing
                    operations on the document. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.search">
            <glossterm>Document Search</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A web interface in which users can search for documents. Users may search by a
                    combination of document properties such as Document Type or Document ID, or by
                    more specialized properties using the Detailed Search. Search results are
                    displayed in a list similar to an Action List.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.status">
            <glossterm>Document Status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See also <glossterm linkend="glossary.route.status">Route
                    Status</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.title">
            <glossterm>Document Title</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The title given to the document when it was created. Depending on the Document
                    Type, this title may have been assigned by the Initiator or built automatically
                    based on the contents of the document. The Document Title is displayed in both
                    the Action List and Document Search.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.type">
            <glossterm>Document Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Document Type defines the routing definition and other properties for a
                    set of documents. Each document is an instance of a Document Type and conducts
                    the same type of business transaction as other instances of that Document
                    Type.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>Document Types have the following characteristics:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They are specifications for a document that can be created in
                            KEW</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They contain identifying information as well as policies and other
                            attributes</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They defines the Route Path executed for a document of that type
                            (Process Definition)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They are hierarchical in nature may be part of a hierarchy of Document
                            Types, each of which inherits certain properties of its <glossterm
                                linkend="glossary.parent.document.type">Parent Document
                                Type</glossterm>.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They are typically defined in XML, but certain properties can be
                            maintained from a graphical interface</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.type.hierarchy">
            <glossterm>Document Type Hierarchy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A hierarchy of Document Type definitions. Document Types inherit certain
                    attributes from their parent Document Types. This hierarchy is also leveraged by
                    various pieces of the system, including the Rules engine when evaluating rule
                    sets and KIM when evaluating certain Document Type-based permissions.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.type.label">
            <glossterm>Document Type Label</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The human-readable label assigned to a Document Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.type.name">
            <glossterm>Document Type Name</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The assigned name of the document type. It must be unique.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.document.type.policy">
            <glossterm>Document Type Policy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>These advise various checks and authorizations for instances of a Document
                    Type during the routing process.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.drilldown">
            <glossterm>Drilldown</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A link that allows a user to access more detailed information about the
                    current data. These links typically take the user through a series of inquiries
                    on different business objects.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.dynamic.node">
            <glossterm>Dynamic Node</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An advanced type of <glossterm linkend="glossary.route.node">Route
                        Node</glossterm> that can be used to generate complex routing paths on the
                    fly. Typically used whenever the route path of a document cannot be statically
                    defined and must be completely derived from document data.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>E</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.ecl">
            <glossterm>ECL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>An acronym for Educational Community License.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All Kuali software and material is available under the Educational
                            Community License and may be adopted by colleges and universities
                            without licensing fees. The open licensing approach also provides
                            opportunities for support and implementation assistance from commercial
                            affiliates.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.e-doc">
            <glossterm>E-Doc</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An abbreviation for electronic documents, also a shorthand reference to
                    documents created with eDocLite.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.edoclite">
            <glossterm>eDocLite</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A framework for quickly building workflow-enabled documents. Allows you to
                    define document screens in XML and render them using XSL style sheets.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.embedded.client">
            <glossterm>Embedded Client</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of client that runs an embedded workflow engine.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.employee.status">
            <glossterm>Employee Status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Found on the Person Document; defines the employee's current employment
                    classification (for example, "A" for Active).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.employee.type">
            <glossterm>Employee Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Found on the Person Document; defines the employee's position classification
                    (for example, "P" for Professional).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.entity">
            <glossterm>Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An Entity record houses identity information for a given Person, Process,
                    System, etc. Each Entity is categorized by its association with an Entity
                    Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.entity.attribute">
            <glossterm>Entity Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Entities have directory-like information called Entity Attributes that are
                    associated with them</para>
                <para>Entity Attributes make up the identity information for an Entity
                    record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.entity.type">
            <glossterm>Entity Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Provides categorization to Entities. For example, a "System" could be
                    considered an Entity Type because something like a batch process may need to
                    interfact with the application.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.exception">
            <glossterm>Exception</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow routing status indicating that the document routed to an exception
                    queue because workflow has encountered a system error when trying to process the
                    document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.exception.messaging">
            <glossterm>Exception Messaging</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The set of services and configuration options that are responsible for
                    handling messages when they cannot be successfully delivered. Exception
                    Messaging is set up when you configure KSB using the properties outlined in KSB
                    Module Configuration.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.exception.routing">
            <glossterm>Exception Routing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of routing used to handle error conditions that occur during the
                    routing of a document. A document goes into Exception Routing when the workflow
                    engine encounters an error or a situation where it cannot proceed, such as a
                    violation of a Document Type Policy or an error contacting external services.
                    When this occurs, the document is routed to the parties responsible for handling
                    these exception cases. This can be a group configured on the document or a
                    responsibility configured in KIM. Once one of these responsible parties has
                    reviewed the situation and approved the document, it will be resubmitted to the
                    workflow engine to attempt the processing again.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.extended.attributes">
            <glossterm>Extended Attributes</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Custom, table-driven business object attributes that can be established by
                    implementing institutions.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.extension.rule.attribute">
            <glossterm>Extension Rule Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>One of the rule attributes added in the definition of a rule template that
                    extends beyond the base rule attributes to differentiate the routing rule. A
                    Required Extension Attribute has its "Required" field set to True in the rule
                    template. Otherwise, it is an Optional Extension Attribute. Extension attributes
                    are typically used to add additional fields that can be collected on a rule.
                    They also define the logic for how those fields will be processed during rule
                    evaluation.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>F</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.field.lookup">
            <glossterm>Field Lookup</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The round magnifying glass icon found next to fields throughout the GUI that
                    allow the user to look up reference table information and display (and select
                    from) a list of valid values for that field.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.final">
            <glossterm>Final</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow routing status indicating that the document has been routed and has
                    no pending approval or acknowledgement requests.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.flexible.route.management">
            <glossterm>Flexible Route Management</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A standard KEW routing scheme based on rules rather than dedicated table-based
                    routing.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.flexrm">
            <glossterm>FlexRM (Flexible Route Module)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Route Module that performs the Routing for any Routing Rule is defined
                    through FlexRM. FlexRM generates Action Requests when a Rule matches the data
                    value contained in a document. An abbreviation of "Flexible Route Module." A
                    standard KEW routing scheme that is based on rules rather than dedicated
                    table-based routing.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.force.action">
            <glossterm>Force Action</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A true/false flag that indicates if previous Routing for approval will be
                    ignored when an <glossterm linkend="glossary.action.request">Action
                        Request</glossterm> is generated. The flag is used in multiple contexts
                    where requests are generated (e.g., rules, ad hoc routing). If Force Action is
                    False, then prior Actions taken by a user can satisfy newly generated requests.
                    If it is True, then the user needs to take another Action to satisfy the
                    request.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.fyi">
            <glossterm>FYI</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action request that can be cleared from a user's Action List with
                    or without opening and viewing the document. A document with no pending approval
                    requests but with pending Acknowledge requests is in Processed status. A
                    document with no pending approval requests but with pending FYI requests is in
                    Final status. See also <glossterm linkend="glossary.ad.hoc.routing">Ad Hoc
                        Routing</glossterm> and <glossterm linkend="glossary.action.request">Action
                        Request</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>G</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.group">
            <glossterm>Group</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Group has members that can be either <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.principal">Principals</glossterm> or other Groups
                    (nested). Groups essentially become a way to organize Entities (via Principal
                    relationships) and other Groups within logical categories.</para>
                <para>Groups can be given authorization to perform actions within applications by
                    assigning them as members of <glossterm linkend="glossary.role"
                        >Roles</glossterm>.</para>
                <para>Groups can also have arbitrary identity information (i.e., <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.group.attribute">Group Attributes</glossterm> hanging
                    from them. Group Attributes might be values for "Office Address," "Group
                    Leader," etc.</para>
                <para>Groups can be maintained at runtime through a user interface that is capable
                    of workflow.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.group.attribute">
            <glossterm>Group Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Groups have directory-like information called Group Attributes hanging from
                    them. "Group Phone Number" and "Team Leader" are examples of Group
                    Attributes.</para>
                <para>Group Attributes make up the identity information for a Group record.</para>
                <para>Group Attributes can be maintained at runtime through a user interface that is
                    capable of workflow.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>H</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.hierarchical.tree.structure">
            <glossterm>Hierarchical Tree Structure</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A hierarchical representation of data in a graphical form.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>I</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.initialized">
            <glossterm>Initialized</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The state of an Action Request when it is first created but has not yet been
                    Activated (sent to a user's Action List).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.initiated">
            <glossterm>Initiated</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow routing status indicating a document has been created but has not
                    yet been saved or routed. A Document Number is automatically assigned by the
                    system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.initiator">
            <glossterm>Initiator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user role for a person who creates (initiates or authors) a new document for
                    routing. Depending on the permissions associated with the Document Type, only
                    certain users may be able to initiate documents of that type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.inquiry">
            <glossterm>Inquiry</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A screen that allows a user to view information about a business
                    object.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>J</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.join.node">
            <glossterm>Join Node</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The point in the routing path where multiple branches are joined together. A
                    Join Node typically has a corresponding <glossterm linkend="glossary.split.node"
                        >Split Node</glossterm> for which it joins the branches.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>K</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kc">
            <glossterm>KC - Kuali Coeus</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>TODO</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kca">
            <glossterm>KCA - Kuali Commercial Affiliates</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A designation provided to commercial affiliates who become part of the Kuali
                    Partners Program to provide for-fee guidance, support, implementation, and
                    integration services related to the Kuali software. Affiliates hold no ownership
                    of Kuali intellectual property, but are full KPP participants. Affiliates may
                    provide packaged versions of Kuali that provide value for installation or
                    integration beyond the basic Kuali software. Affiliates may also offer other
                    types of training, documentation, or hosting services.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kcb">
            <glossterm>KCB  Kuali Communications Broker</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>KCB is logically related to KEN. It handles dispatching messages based on user
                    preferences (email, SMS, etc.).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.ken">
            <glossterm>KEN - Kuali Enterprise Notification</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>A key component of the Enterprise Integration layer of the architecture
                        framework. Its features include:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Automatic Message Generation and Logging </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Message integrity and delivery standards</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Delivery of notifications to a user's Action List</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kew">
            <glossterm>KEW  Kuali Enterprise Workflow</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Kuali Enterprise Workflow is a general-purpose electronic routing
                    infrastructure, or workflow engine. It manages the creation, routing, and
                    processing of electronic documents (eDocs) necessary to complete a transaction.
                    Other applications can also use Kuali Enterprise Workflow to automate and
                    regulate the approval process for the transactions or documents they
                    create.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kfs">
            <glossterm>KFS  Kuali Financial System</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivers a comprehensive suite of functionality to serve the financial system
                    needs of all Carnegie-Class institutions. An enhancement of the proven
                    functionality of Indiana University's Financial Information System (FIS), KFS
                    meets GASB and FASB standards while providing a strong control environment to
                    keep pace with advances in both technology and business. Modules include
                    financial transactions, general ledger, chart of accounts, contracts and grants,
                    purchasing/accounts payable, labor distribution, budget, accounts receivable and
                    capital assets.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kim">
            <glossterm>KIM  Kuali Identity Management</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Kuali Rice module, Kuali Identity Management provides a standard API for
                    persons, groups, roles and permissions that can be implemented by an
                    institution. It also provdies an out of the box reference implementation that
                    allows for a university to use Kuali as their Identity Management
                    solution.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kns">
            <glossterm>KNS  Kuali Nervous System</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A core technical module composed of reusable code components that provide the
                    common, underlying infrastructure code and functionality that any module may
                    employ to perform its functions (for example, creating custom attributes,
                    attaching electronic images, uploading data from desktop applications,
                    lookup/search routines, and database interaction).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kuali.partners.program">
            <glossterm>KPP - Kuali Partners Program</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Kuali Partners Program (KPP) is the means for organizations to get
                    involved in the Kuali software community and influence its future through voting
                    rights to determine software development priorities. Membership dues pay staff
                    to perform Quality Assurance (QA) work, release engineering, packaging,
                    documentation, and other work to coordinate the timely enhancement and release
                    of quality software and other services valuable to the members. Partners are
                    also encouraged to tender functional, technical, support or administrative staff
                    members to the Kuali Foundation for specific periods of time.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.krad">
            <glossterm>KRAD - Kuali Rapid Application Development</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>TODO</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.krms">
            <glossterm>KRMS - Kuali Rules Management System</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>TODO</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kuali.student">
            <glossterm>KS - Kuali Student</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivers a means to support students and other users with a student-centric
                    system that provides real-time, cost-effective, scalable support to help them
                    identify and achieve their goals while simplifying or eliminating administrative
                    tasks. The high-level entities of person (evolving roles-student, instructor,
                    etc.), time (nested units of time - semesters, terms, classes), learning unit
                    (assigned to any learning activity), learning result (grades, assessments,
                    evaluations), learning plan (intentions, activities, major, degree), and
                    learning resources (instructors, classrooms, equipment). The concierge function
                    is a self-service information sharing system that aligns information with needs
                    and tasks to accomplish goals. The support for integration of locally-developed
                    processes provides flexibility for any institution's needs.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.ksb">
            <glossterm>KSB  Kuali Service Bus</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>Provides an out-of-the-box service architecture and runtime environment
                        for Kuali Applications. It is the cornerstone of the Service Oriented
                        Architecture layer of the architectural reference framework. The Kuali
                        Service Bus consists of:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A services registry and repository for identifying and instantiating
                            services</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Run time monitoring of messages</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Support for synchronous and asynchronous service and message
                            paradigms</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kuali">
            <glossterm>Kuali</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Pronounced "ku-wah-lee". A partnership organization that produces a
                            suite of community-source, modular administrative software for
                            Carnegie-class higher education institutions. See also <glossterm
                                linkend="glossary.kuali.foundation">Kuali Foundation</glossterm>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>(n.) A humble kitchen wok that plays an important role in a successful
                            kitchen.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kuali.foundation">
            <glossterm>Kuali Foundation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Employs staff to coordinate partner efforts and to manage and protect the
                    Foundation's intellectual property. The Kuali Foundation manages a growing
                    portfolio of enterprise software applications for colleges and universities. A
                    lightweight Foundation staff coordinates the activities of Foundation members
                    for critical software development and coordination activities such as source
                    code control, release engineering, packaging, documentation, project management,
                    software testing and quality assurance, conference planning, and educating and
                    assisting members of the Kuali Partners program.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.kuali.rice">
            <glossterm>Kuali Rice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Provides an enterprise-class middleware suite of integrated products that
                    allow both Kuali and non-Kuali applications to be built in an agile fashion,
                    such that developers are able to react to end-user business requirements in an
                    efficient manner to produce high-quality business applications. Built with
                    Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) concepts in mind, KR enables developers to
                    build robust systems with common enterprise workflow functionality, customizable
                    and configurable user interfaces with a clean and universal look and feel, and
                    general notification features to allow for a consolidated list of work "action
                    items." All of this adds up to providing a re-usable development framework that
                    encourages a simplified approach to developing true business functionality as
                    modular applications.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>L</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.last.modified.date">
            <glossterm>Last Modified Date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which the document was last modified (e.g., the date of the last
                    action taken, the last action request generated, the last status changed,
                    etc.).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>M</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.maintenance.document">
            <glossterm>Maintenance Document</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An e-doc used to establish and maintain a table record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.message">
            <glossterm>Message</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The full description of a <glossterm linkend="glossary.notification.message"
                        >notification message</glossterm>. This is a specific field that can be
                    filled out as part of the Simple Message or Event Message form. This can also be
                    set by the programmatic interfaces when sending notifications from a client
                    system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.message.queue">
            <glossterm>Message Queue</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Allows administrators to monitor messages that are flowing through the Service
                    Bus. Messages can be edited, deleted or forwarded to other machines for
                    processing from this screen.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>N</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.namespace">
            <glossterm>Namespace</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Namespace is a way to scope both <glossterm linkend="glossary.permission"
                        >Permissions</glossterm> and <glossterm linkend="glossary.entity.attribute"
                        >Entity Attributes</glossterm> Each Namespace instance is one level of
                    scoping and is one record in the system. For example, "KRA" or "KC" or "KFS"
                    could be a Namespace. Or you could further break those up into finer-grained
                    Namespaces such that they would roughly correlate to functional modules within
                    each application. Examples could be "KRA Rolodex", "KC Grants", "KFS Chart of
                    Accounts".</para>
                <para>Out of the box, the system is bootstrapped with numerous Rice namespaces which
                    correspond to the different modules. There is also a default namespace of
                    "KUALI".</para>
                <para>Namespaces can be maintained at runtime through a maintenance document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.note.text">
            <glossterm>Note Text</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A free-form text field for the text of a Note</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.notification.content">
            <glossterm>Notification Content</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This section of a <glossterm linkend="glossary.notification.message"
                        >notification message</glossterm> which displays the actual full message for
                    the notification along with any other content-type-specific fields.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.notification.message">
            <glossterm>Notification Message</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The overall Notification item or Notification Message that a user sees when
                    she views the details of a notification in her Action List. A Notification
                    Message contains not only common elements such as Sender, Channel, and Title,
                    but also content-type-specific fields.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>O</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.ootb">
            <glossterm>OOTB</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Stands for "out of the box" and refers to the base deliverable of a given
                    feature in the system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.optimistic.locking">
            <glossterm>Optimistic Locking</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of "locking" that is placed on a database row by a process to prevent
                    other processes from updating that row before the first process is complete. A
                    characteristic of this locking technique is that another user who wants to make
                    modifications at the same time as another user is permitted to, but the first
                    one who submits their changes will have them applied. Any subsequent changes
                    will result in the user being notified of the optimistic lock and their changes
                    will not be applied. This technique assumes that another update is
                    unlikely.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.optional.rule.extension.attribute">
            <glossterm>Optional Rule Extension Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An Extension Attribute that is not required in a Rule Template. It may or may
                    not be present in a <glossterm linkend="glossary.routing.rule">Routing
                        Rule</glossterm> created from the Template. It can be used as a conditional
                    element to aid in deciding if a Rule matches. These Attributes are simply
                    additional criteria for the Rule matching process.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.org.doc.number">
            <glossterm>Org Doc #</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The originating document number.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.organization">
            <glossterm>Organization</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Refers to a unit within the institution such as department, responsibility
                    center, campus, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.organization.code">
            <glossterm>Organization Code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Represents a unique identifier assigned to units at many different levels
                    within the institution (for example, department, responsibility center, and
                    campus).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>P</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parameter.component.code">
            <glossterm>Parameter Component Code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Code identifying the parameter Component.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parameter.description">
            <glossterm>Parameter Description</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This field houses the purpose of this parameter.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parameter.name">
            <glossterm>Parameter Name</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This will be used as the identifier for the parameter. Parameter values will
                    be accessed using this field and the namespace as the key.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parameter.type.code">
            <glossterm>Parameter Type Code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Code identifying the parameter type. Parameter Type Code is the primary key
                    for its' table.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parameter.value">
            <glossterm>Parameter Value</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This field houses the actual value associated with the parameter.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parent.document.type">
            <glossterm>Parent Document Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Document Type from which another <glossterm linkend="glossary.document.type"
                        >Document Type</glossterm> derives. The child type can inherit certain
                    properties of the parent type, any of which it may override. A Parent Document
                    Type may have a parent as part of a hierarchy of document types.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.parent.rule">
            <glossterm>Parent Rule</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Routing Rule in KEW from which another Routing Rule derives. The child Rule
                    can inherit certain properties of the parent Rule, any of which it may override.
                    A Parent Rule may have a parent as part of a hierarchy of Rules.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.permission">
            <glossterm>Permission</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Permissions represent fine grained actions that can be mapped to functionality
                    within a given system. Permissions are scoped to <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.namespace">Namespace</glossterm> which roughly correlate
                    to modules or sections of functionality within a given system.</para>
                <para>A developer would code authorization checks in their application against these
                    permissions.</para>
                <para>Some examples would be: "canSave", "canView", "canEdit", etc.</para>
                <para>Permissions are aggregated by <glossterm linkend="glossary.role"
                        >Roles</glossterm>.</para>
                <para>Permissions can be maintained at runtime through a user interface that is
                    capable of workflow; however, developers still need to code authorization checks
                    against them in their code, once they are set up in the system.</para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <para>Attributes</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Id - a system generated unique identifier that is the primary key for
                            any Permission record in the system</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Name - the name of the permission; also a human understandable unique
                            identifier</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Description - a full description of the purpose of the Permission
                            record</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Namespace - the reference to the associated <glossterm
                                linkend="glossary.namespace">Namespace</glossterm></para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <orderedlist>
                    <para>Relationships</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Permission to <glossterm linkend="glossary.role">Role</glossterm> -
                            many to many; this relationship ties a Permission record to a Role that
                            is authorized for the Permission</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Permission to <glossterm linkend="glossary.namespace"
                                >Namespace</glossterm> - many to one; this relationship allows for
                            scoping of a Permission to a Namespace that contains functionality which
                            keys its authorization checking off of said </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <para/>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.person.identifier">
            <glossterm>Person Identifier</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The username of an individual user who receives the document ad hoc for the
                    Action Requested</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.person.role">
            <glossterm>Person Role</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Creates or maintains the list used in selection of personnel when preparing
                    the Routing Form document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.pessimistic.locking">
            <glossterm>Pessimistic Locking</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of lock placed on a database row by a process to prevent other
                    processes from reading or updating that row until the first process is finished.
                    This technique assumes that another update is likely.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.plugins">
            <glossterm>Plugins</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A plugin is a packaged set of code providing essential services that can be
                    deployed into the Rice standalone server. Plugins usually contains only classes
                    used in routing such as custom rules or searchable attributes, but can contain
                    client application specific services. They are usually used only by clients
                    being implemented by the 'Thin Client' method</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.post.processor">
            <glossterm>Post Processor</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing component that is notified by the workflow engine about various
                    events pertaining to the routing of a specific document (e.g., node transition,
                    status change, action taken). The implementation of a Post Processor is
                    typically specific to a particular set of Document Types. When all required
                    approvals are completed, the engine notifies the Post Processor accordingly. At
                    this point, the Post Processor is responsible for completing the business
                    transaction in the manner appropriate to its Document Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.posted.date.time.stamp">
            <glossterm>Posted Date/Time Stamp</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A free-form text field that identifies the time and date at which the Notes is
                    posted.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.postal.code">
            <glossterm>Postal Code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Defines zip code to city and state cross-references.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.preferences">
            <glossterm>Preferences</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>User options in an Action List for displaying the list of documents. Users can
                    click the Preferences button in the top margin of the Action List to display the
                    Action List Preferences screen. On the Preferences screen, users may change the
                    columns displayed, the background colors by Route Status, and the number of
                    documents displayed per page.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.primary.delegate">
            <glossterm>Primary Delegation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Delegator turns over full authority to the Delegate. The Action Requests
                    for the Delegator only appear in the Action List of the Primary Delegate. The
                    Delegation must be registered in KEW or KIM to be in effect.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.principal">
            <glossterm>Principal</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Principal represents an <glossterm linkend="glossary.entity"
                        >Entity</glossterm> that can authenticate into the system. One can roughly
                    correlate a Principal to a login username. Entities can exist in KIM without
                    having permissions or authorization to do anything; therefore, a Principal must
                    exist and must be associated with an Entity in order for it to have access
                    privileges. All authorization that is not specific to <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.group">Groups</glossterm> is tied to a Principal.</para>
                <para>In other words, an Entity is for identity while a Principal is for access
                    management.</para>
                <para>Also note that an Entity is allowed to have multiple Principals associated
                    with it. The use case typically given here is that a person may apply to a
                    school and receive one log in for the application system; however, once
                    accepted, they may receive their official login, but use the same identity
                    information set up for their Entity record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.processed">
            <glossterm>Processed</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing status indicating that the document has no pending approval requests
                    but still has one or more pending acknowledgement requests.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>R</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.recipient.type">
            <glossterm>Recipient Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The type of entity that is receiving an Action Request. Can be a user,
                    workgroup, or role.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.required.rule.extension.attribute">
            <glossterm>Required Rule Extension Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An Extension Attribute that is required in a Rule Template. It will be present
                    in every Routing Rule created from the Template.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.responsibility">
            <glossterm>Responsibility</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <glossterm linkend="glossary.responsible.party">Responsible
                        Party</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.responsibility.id">
            <glossterm>Responsibility Id</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A unique identifier representing a particular responsibility on a rule (or
                    from a <glossterm linkend="glossary.route.module">route module</glossterm> This
                    identifier stays the same for a particular responsibility no matter how many
                    times a rule is modified.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.responsible.party">
            <glossterm>Responsible Party</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Reviewer defined on a routing rule that receives requests when the rule is
                    successfully executed. Each routing rule has one or more responsible parties
                    defined.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.reviewer">
            <glossterm>Reviewer</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user acting on a document in his/her <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.action.list">Action List</glossterm> and who has received
                    an <glossterm linkend="glossary.action.request">Action Request</glossterm> for
                    the document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.rice">
            <glossterm>Rice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An abbreviation for Kuali Rice.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.role">
            <glossterm>Role</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Roles aggregate <glossterm linkend="glossary.permission"
                        >Permissions</glossterm> When Roles are given to <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.entity">Entities</glossterm> (via their relationship
                    with Principals) or <glossterm linkend="glossary.group">Groups</glossterm> an
                    authorization for all associated Permissions is granted.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.route.header.id">
            <glossterm>Route Header Id</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Another name for the <glossterm linkend="glossary.document.id">Document
                        Id</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.route.log">
            <glossterm>Route Log</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Displays information about the routing of a document. The Route Log is usually
                    accessed from either the Action List or a Document Search. It displays general
                    document information about the document and a detailed list of Actions Taken and
                    pending <glossterm linkend="glossary.action.request">Action Requests</glossterm>
                    for the document. The Route Log can be considered an audit trail for a
                    document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.route.module">
            <glossterm>Route Module</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing component that the engine uses to generate action requests at a
                    particular <glossterm linkend="glossary.route.node">Route Node</glossterm>.
                        <glossterm linkend="glossary.flexrm">FlexRM</glossterm> (Flexible Route
                    Module) is a general Route Module that is rule-based. Clients can define their
                    own Route Modules that can conduct specialized Routing based on routing tables
                    or any other desired implementation.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.route.node">
            <glossterm>Route Node</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Represents a step in the routing process of a document type. Route node
                    "instances" are created dynamically as a document goes through its routing
                    process and can be defined to perform any function. The most common functions
                    are to generate Action Requests or to split or join the route path. </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Simple: do some arbitrary work</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Requests: generate action requests using a Route Module or the Rules
                            engine</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Split: split the route path into one or more parallel branches</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Join: join one or more branches back together</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Sub Process: execute another route path inline</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Dynamic: generate a dynamic route path</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.route.path">
            <glossterm>Route Path</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The path a document follows during the routing process. Consists of a set of
                    route nodes and branches. The route path is defined as part of the <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.document.type">document type</glossterm>
                    definition.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.route.status">
            <glossterm>Route Status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>The status of a document in the course of its routing:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approved: These documents have been approved by all required reviewers
                            and are waiting additional postprocessing.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Cancelled: These documents have been stopped. The document's initiator
                            can 'Cancel' it before routing begins or a reviewer of the document can
                            cancel it after routing begins. When a document is cancelled, routing
                            stops; it is not sent to another Action List. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Disapproved: These documents have been disapproved by at least one
                            reviewer. Routing has stopped for these documents.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Enroute: Routing is in progress on these documents and an action
                            request is waiting for someone to take action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Exception: A routing exception has occurred on this document. Someone
                            from the Exception Workgroup for this Document Type must take action on
                            this document, and it has been sent to the Action List of this
                            workgroup.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Final: All required approvals and all acknowledgements have been
                            received on these documents. No changes are allowed to a document that
                            is in Final status.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Initiated: A user or a process has created this document, but it has
                            not yet been routed to anyone's Action List.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Processed: These documents have been approved by all required users,
                            and is completed on them. They may be waiting for Acknowledgements. No
                            further action is needed on these documents.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Saved: These documents have been saved for later work. An author
                            (initiator) can save a document before routing begins or a reviewer can
                            save a document before he or she takes action on it. When someone saves
                            a document, the document goes on that person's Action List.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.routed.by.user">
            <glossterm>Routed By User</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The user who submits the document into routing. This is often the same as the
                    Initiator. However, for some types of documents they may be different.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.routing">
            <glossterm>Routing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process of moving a document through its route path as defined in its
                    Document Type. Routing is executed and administered by the workflow engine. This
                    process will typically include generating Action Requests and processing actions
                    from the users who receive those requests. In addition, the Routing process
                    includes callbacks to the Post Processor when there are changes in document
                    state. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.routing.priority">
            <glossterm>Routing Priority</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A number that indicates the routing priority; a smaller number has a higher
                    routing priority. Routing priority is used to determine the order that requests
                    are activated on a route node with sequential activation type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.routing.rule">
            <glossterm>Routing Rule</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A record that contains the data for the <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.rule.attribute">Rule Attributes</glossterm> specified in
                    a <glossterm linkend="glossary.rule.template">Rule Template</glossterm> It is an
                    instance of a Rule Template populated to determine the appropriate Routing. The
                    Rule includes the Base Attributes, Required Extension Attributes, Responsible
                    Party Attributes, and any Optional Extension Attributes that are declared in the
                    Rule Template. Rules are evaluated at certain points in the routing process and,
                    when they fire, can generate Action Requests to the responsible parties that are
                    defined on them.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>Technical considerations for a Routing Rules are:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Configured via a GUI (or imported from XML)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Created against a Rule Template and a Document Type</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The Rule Template and it's list of Rule Attributes define what fields
                            will be collected in the Rule GUI</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Rules define the users, groups and/or roles who should receive action
                            requests</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <para>Available Action Request Types that Rules can route</para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Complete</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Approve</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Acknowledge</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>FYI</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>During routing, Rule Evaluation Sets are "selected" at each node.
                            Default is to select by Document Type and Rule Template defined on the
                            Route Node</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Rules match (or 'fire') based on the evaluation of data on the
                            document and data contained on the individual rule</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <para>Examples</para>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>If dollar amount is greater than $10,000 then send an Approval
                                    request to Joe.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>If department is "HR" request an Acknowledgment from the
                                    HR.Acknowledgers workgroup.</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.rule.attribute">
            <glossterm>Rule Attribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Rule attributes are a core KEW data element contained in a document that
                    controls its Routing. It participates in routing as part of a Rule Template and
                    is responsible for defining custom fields that can be rendered on a routing
                    rule. It also defines the logic for how rules that contain the attribute data
                    are evaluated.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>Technical considerations for a Rule Attribute are:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They might be backed by a Java class to provide lookups and
                            validations of appropriate values.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Define how a Routing Rule evaluates document data to determine whether
                            or not the rule data matches the document data.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Define what data is collected on a rule.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>An attribute typically corresponds to one piece of data on a document
                            (i.e dollar amount, department, organization, account, etc.).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Can be written in Java or defined using XML (with matching done by
                            XPath).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Can have multiple GUI fields defined in a single attribute.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.rule.quickLinks">
            <glossterm>Rule QuickLinks</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A list of document groups with their document hierarchies and actions that can
                    be selected. For specific document types, you can create the rule
                    delegate.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.rule.template">
            <glossterm>Rule Template</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Rule Template serves as a pattern or design for the routing rules. All of
                    the Rule Attributes that include both Required and _Optional_ are contained in
                    the Rule Template; it defines the structure of the routing rule of FlexRM. The
                    Rule Template is also used to associate certain Route Nodes on a document type
                    to routing rules.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>Technical considerations for a Rule Templates are:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They are a composition of Rule Attributes</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Adding a 'Role' attribute to a template allows for the use of the Role
                            on any rules created against the template</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>When rule attributes are used for matching on rules, each attribute is
                            associated with the other attributes on the template using an implicit
                            'and' logic attributes</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Can be used to define various other aspects to be used by the rule
                            creation GUI such as rule data defaults (effective dates, ignore
                            previous, available request types, etc)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>S</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.save">
            <glossterm>Save</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action button that allows the Initiator of a document to save their
                    work and close the document. The document may be retrieved from the initiator's
                    Action List for completion and routing at a later time.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.saved">
            <glossterm>Saved</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing status indicating the document has been started but not yet
                    completed or routed. The Save action allows the initiator of a document to save
                    their work and close the document. The document may be retrieved from the
                    initiator's action list for completion and routing at a later time.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.searchable.attributes">
            <glossterm>Searchable Attributes</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Attributes that can be defined to index certain pieces of data on a document
                    so that it can be searched from the <glossterm
                        linkend="glossary.document.search">Document Search
                    screen</glossterm>.</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>Technical considerations for a Searchable Attributes are:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They are responsible for extracting and indexing document data for
                            searching</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They allow for custom fields to be added to Document Search for
                            documents of a particular type</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They are configured as an attribute of a Document Type</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>They can be written in Java or defined in XML by using Xpath to
                            facilitate matching</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.secondary.delegate">
            <glossterm>Secondary Delegation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Secondary Delegate acts as a temporary backup Delegator who acts with the
                    same authority as the primary Approver/the Delegator when the Delegator is not
                    available. Documents appear in the Action Lists of both the Delegator and the
                    Delegate. When either acts on the document, it disappears from both Action
                    Lists.</para>
                <para>Secondary Delegation is often configured for a range of dates and it must be
                    registered in KEW or KIM to be in effect.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.service.registry">
            <glossterm>Service Registry</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Displays a read-only view of all of the services that are exposed on the
                    Service Bus and includes information about them (for example, IP Address, or
                    Endpoint URL).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.simple.node">
            <glossterm>Simple Node</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of node that can perform any function desired by the implementer. An
                    example implementation of a simple node is the node that generates Action
                    Requests from route modules.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.soa">
            <glossterm>SOA</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An acronym for Service Oriented Architecture.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.special.condition.routing">
            <glossterm>Special Condition Routing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is a generic term for additional route levels that might be triggered by
                    various attributes of a transaction. They can be based on the type of document,
                    attributes of the accounts being used, or other attributes of the transaction.
                    They often represent special administrative approvals that may be
                    required.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.split.node">
            <glossterm>Split Node</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A node in the routing path that can split the route path into multiple
                    branches.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.spring">
            <glossterm>Spring</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The <link xlink:href="http://www.springsource.org/">Spring Framework</link> is
                    an open source application framework for the Java platform.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.state">
            <glossterm>State</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Defines U.S. Postal Service codes used to identify states.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.status">
            <glossterm>Status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>On an Action List; also known as Route Status. The current location of the
                    document in its routing path.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.submit">
            <glossterm>Submit</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action button used by the initiator of a document to begin workflow
                    routing for that transaction. It moves the document (through workflow) to the
                    next level of approval. Once a document is submitted, it remains in 'ENROUTE'
                    status until all approvals have taken place.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.superuser">
            <glossterm>Superuser</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user who has been given special permission to perform Superuser Approvals
                    and other Superuser actions on documents of a certain Document Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.superuser.approval">
            <glossterm>Superuser Approval</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authority given Superusers to approve a document of a chosen Route Node. A
                    Superuser Approval action bypasses approvals that would otherwise be required in
                    the Routing. It is available in Superuser Document Search. In most cases,
                    reviewers who are skipped are not sent Acknowledge Action Requests.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.superuser.document.search">
            <glossterm>Superuser Document Search</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A special mode of Document Search that allows Superusers to access documents
                    in a special Superuser mode and perform administrative functions on those
                    documents. Access to these documents is governed by the user's membership in the
                    Superuser Workgroup as defined on a particular Document Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>T</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.thread.pool">
            <glossterm>Thread pool</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A technique that improves overall system performance by creating a pool of
                    threads to execute multiple tasks at the same time. A task can execute
                    immediately if a thread in the pool is available or else the task waits for a
                    thread to become available from the pool before executing.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.title">
            <glossterm>Title</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A short summary of the notification message. This field can be filled out as
                    part of the Simple Message or Event Message form. In addition, this can be set
                    by the programmatic interfaces when sending notifications from a client
                    system.</para>
                <para>This field is equivalent to the "Subject" field in an email.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>U</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.url">
            <glossterm>URL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An acronym for Uniform Resource Locator.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.user">
            <glossterm>User</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A person who can log in and use the application. This term is synonymous with
                    "Principal" in KIM.  "Whereas Entity Id represents a unique Person, Principal Id
                    represents a set of login information for that Person." </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>V</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.viewer">
            <glossterm>Viewer</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user(s) who views a document during the routing process. This includes users
                    who have action requests generated to them on a document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>W</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.web.service.client">
            <glossterm>Web Service Client</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of client that connects to a standalone KEW server using Web
                    Services.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.wildcard">
            <glossterm>Wildcard</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A character that may be substituted for any of a defined subset of all
                    possible characters.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.workflow">
            <glossterm>Workflow</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Electronic document routing, approval and tracking. Also known as Workflow
                    Services or Kuali Enterprise Workflow (KEW). The Kuali infrastructure service
                    that electronically routes an e-doc to its approvers in a prescribed sequence,
                    according to established business rules based on the e-doc content. See also
                        <glossterm linkend="glossary.kew">Kuali Enterprise
                    Workflow</glossterm>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.workflow.engine">
            <glossterm>Workflow Engine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The component of KEW that handles initiating and executing the route path of a
                    document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.workflow.quickLinks">
            <glossterm>Workflow QuickLinks</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <para>A web interface that provides quick navigation to various functions in
                        KEW. These include:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Quick EDoc Watch: The last five Actions taken by this user. The user
                            can select and repeat these actions.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Quick EDoc Search: The last five EDocs searched for by this user. The
                            user can select one and repeat that search.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Quick Action List: The last five document types the user took action
                            with. The user can select one and repeat that action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>X</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.xml">
            <glossterm>XML</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See also <glossterm linkend="glossary.xml.ingester">XML
                    Ingester</glossterm>.</para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>An acronym for Extensible Markup Language.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Used for data import/export.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.xml.ingester">
            <glossterm>XML Ingester</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow function that allows you to browse for and upload XML data.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="glossary.xml.ruleAttribute">
            <glossterm>XML RuleAttribute</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Similar in functionality to a RuleAttribute but built using XML only</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
</glossary>
