<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0"
    xml:lang="en-US">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <section>
        <title/>
        <para role="Body Text">This guide provides information about using OLE system administration
            functions available via the user interface. All of these functions are accessible from the <emphasis
                role="bold">Admin</emphasis> menu tab in the Open Library Environment (OLE). </para>
        <para role="Body Text">The content of this guide is organized as follows.</para>
        <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">The first section summarizes OLE’s system administration functions and
                    indicates how they are grouped on the Admin Menu. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Each of the remaining sections presents background information and
                    instructions specific to a group of functions on the menu. These sections are divided into
                    subsections covering individual functions in the menu grouping. For each function, the applicable
                    subsection presents a breadcrumb trail showing you how to access the function, information about the
                    layout of and fields on the applicable screen(s), and where appropriate, additional information to
                    help you use the screen(s).</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <note>
            <para> In order to work efficiently, you need to understand the basics of
                the OLE’s user interface. For information and instructions about logging on and off,
                navigating, understanding the components of screens, and performing basic operations
                in the screens, see the <link
                    xlink:href="../../../webhelp/BASICS/content/pr01.html"
                    >OLE Basic Functionality and Key Concepts.</link>
            </para>
            <para> This guide as well as guides to other OLE modules are available for
                download from the <link xlink:href="../../../html/Index.html">OLE Documentation
                    Portal</link>.</para>
        </note>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Accessing System Administration Functions</title>
        <para role="Body Text">The Kuali Open Library Environment (OLE) enables users with proper
            authorization to perform powerful functions that affect the entire system. These functions, which
            are accessible via the <emphasis role="bold">Admin</emphasis> menu tab, allow you to:</para>
        <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Support the Kuali Identity Management (KIM) module and implement security
                    based on accounting line attributes</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Define basic types of location and reference information</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Control the running of batch jobs</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Support the Kuali Enterprise Workflow (KEW) module and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Enable authorized users to perform a variety of other functional and
                    technical activities. </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <note>
            <para> Only members of OLE-SYS Manager and KR-SYS Technical Administrator roles may
                initiate most documents in the Admin Menu. Other users may look up values from the lookup screens
                but may not be able to access other options at all.</para>
        </note>
    </section>
</chapter>
