<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2013 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="intro_to_uif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"  version="5.0">    
    <title>Introduction to the UIF</title>
    <section>
        <title>Overview of the UIF </title>
        <para>The KRAD User Interface Framework (UIF) allows application developers to rapidly
            create rich and powerful user interfaces. KRAD builds on concepts of the KNS (Kuali
            Nervous System) and the KS (Kuali Student) UIF to create a framework capable of
            generating modern Web 2.0 interfaces with a simple declarative configuration. In the
            next few chapters, we will explore the architecture and features of the UIF, and also
            see some of the exciting possibilities for future growth!</para>
        <para>As mentioned in 'A Need for KNS Version 2', the KRAD effort was spawned based on the
            need to expand the current Rice development framework for meeting requirements of the
            Kuali Student project. Although the Rice KNS module has many great concepts that had
            worked well up to date, it was determined that in order to meet the new requirements and
            to continue making overall improvements, portions of the framework would need to be
            redesigned and rewritten. The majority of this work focused on UI generation, with some
            enhancements to other feature areas of the KNS. The following lists the primary goals of
            this effort:</para>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Goal: Rich UI Support</title>
            <para>Over the past few years, web-based user interfaces have taken off. Many of these
                technologies have leveraged browser-based JavaScript and Cascading Style Sheets to
                create impressive effects or to radically increase interactivity by communicating
                with a web-server in between the normal request/response page cycle. Because of
                these huge advances, today's web application users have much higher expectations of
                interactivity.</para>
            <para>The KRAD UIF aims to allow the development of rich web interfaces by offering a
                variety of rich components and behavior. This includes components like lightbox,
                suggest boxes, menu/tabs, and grid (table) features. Some of the 'behavioral'
                features include partial page refreshes, progressive disclosure, client-side
                validation, and AJAX queries. This is just a subset of the way that richer user
                interface functionality is offered by KRAD. Chapters 8 and 11 cover these features
                and more in detail. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> UIF Goal: More Layout Flexibility </title>
            <para>One of the features of the Nervous System users pick up on quickly is the fact
                that so many screens can be generated purely through configuration. A business
                object lookup and inquiry, as well as the screen for maintenance documents: all can
                be generated entirely from an XML file. Freeing developers from having to concern
                themselves with the particulars of the HTML generation for these screens makes the
                user interface of Kuali applications more consistent, to say nothing of the boost to
                developer productivity it gives.</para>
            <para>However, there were other screens which could not be so easily generated.
                Transactional documents depended on perhaps several JSP files, supported by
                hierarchies of traditional taglets. Non-document screens had to be coded in JSP as
                well. The KNS provided a standard library of taglets - such as documentPage, tab,
                htmlControlAttribute, and so on - which eased the development task a bit, but the
                hard fact was that developers still had to spend much more time coding these pages. </para>
            <para>It should therefore be of little surprise that one of KRAD's major goals is
                improving this situation. If transactional documents and non-document screens could
                make use of the Rich UI support through configuration, that would make it much
                easier to develop these incredibly important pieces of functionality.</para>
            <para>However, as any KNS developer knows, transactional documents are much more
                flexible than lookups or maintenance documents. Maintenance documents are almost
                always stacks of two or four columns, perhaps broken up by a standard sub-collection
                interface. Conversely, a transactional document can look like practically
                anything.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> UIF Goal:  Easy to Customize and Extend </title>
            <para>We have all had the experience of working with development frameworks to meet some
                special need that the framework did not provide 'out of the box'. In many cases,
                this is a painful process, requiring the developer to get inside the 'black box' and
                figure out many intricate details of the framework. Furthermore, once a solution is
                found, it might require we modify the core of the framework, causing maintenance and
                upgrade issues.</para>
            <para>Similar issues were encountered when using the Rice KNS framework. In particular,
                the use of tags was problematic, in that there was no way to customize tag logic
                without breaking the upgrade path. In addition, the objects used for UI modeling
                were not extensible or customizable without modifying the Rice code. Therefore, an
                important goal for the UIF is to allow new UI features to be added, and current
                features to be modified without modifying Rice code. As we will see later, this is
                accomplished using a component framework and the power of Spring bean
                configuration.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Goal: Improved Configuration and Tooling</title>
            <para>A lot of user feedback about the Kuali Nervous System centered on the repetitive
                tasks of setting up configuration. Every business object has an object-relational
                mapping and an entry in the data dictionary; that entry is made up of field
                configurations, which gets tediously long fairly quickly.  And then there's building
                the corresponding Java code to be the actual business  object. Even more pieces are
                added to this recipe when attempting to put together a document. </para>
            <para>KRAD is adopting a series of design principles to alleviate some of the work
                required for this configuration. KRAD intends to introduce a series of simple-to-use
                tools to generate configuration based on defaults, letting developers focus on
                tweaking the configuration to match business logic.</para>
            <para>KRAD is also simplifying configuration in general. The idea of "convention over
                configuration" will mean that standard defaults will be provided for what had to be
                manually configured before. These defaults can be overridden, but if they fit the
                needs of the application, no further configuration will be necessary. This will cut
                down a huge amount on the "XML push-ups" required by KRAD application developers,
                but still provide a great deal of flexibility.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Dictionary</title>
            <para>The UIF builds on the KNS concept of using Spring bean XML to build UIs. XML files
                are created to configure and assemble UIF objects (called components). These files
                are then processed and loaded into the Data Dictionary container.</para>
            <para>More Information: Although the UIF configuration is loaded into the same container
                as the Data Dictionary, conceptually we think of them as separate. A current
                practice within Rice is to have a resource directory for data dictionary files, and
                a resource directory for UIF files (per module). In addition, care was taken to
                allow for separate containers to be created (if desired at some point).</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The UIF and UIM</title>
            <para>We will see that technically, using the UIF is very easy, since most things can be
                accomplished by a simple XML configuration. However, there is a challenge in knowing
                how to put the pieces together. To accomplish the amount of flexibility necessary,
                the UIF introduces a lot of concepts that will take some time to learn. Taken all
                together, these form a language for how Rice developers and UX leads will discuss,
                prototype, and finally build user interfaces. To help with this process, the UIM
                (User Interaction Model) was developed. The UIM is a collection of pages that
                document how to best make use of the UIF functionality. Such things as when to use
                one component over another, various configurations of a component, and overall UX
                concerns are documented within the UIM. Investing time to read through the UIM will
                help developers get up to speed with the UIF much quicker. </para>
            <para>You can find the latest version of the UIM at the following URL: <link
                    xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/STUDENT/User+Interaction+Model"
                    >https://wiki.kuali.org/display/STUDENT/User+Interaction+Mode</link>
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section role="NotInToc">
        <title>Recap</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The UIF (User Interface Framework) is the KRAD module used to generate User
                    Interfaces</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Goals of the UIF are:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Rich UI Support</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>More Layout Flexibility</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Easy to Customize and Extend</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Improved Configuration and Tooling</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The UIM (User Interaction Model) is documentation on how page developers
                    should use the UIF for designing views</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Component Design </title>
        <para>Central to all of the UIF is the component framework. Components provide the mechanism
            for which functionality is implemented in a customizable and extensible fashion. In
            short, they are the bread and butter of KRAD!</para>
        <para>So what is a component? A component to KRAD is anything that can be used to build a
            web page. Many of these have a visual presence on the screen, such as text. However,
            some do not, and instead provide behavior with a script. Treating all these as
            components, gives us a uniform approach to developing the UIF framework, in addition to
            providing a very customizable and easy to contribute modality. This section will explore
            the design of components from a high level. Later on in this chapter, we will learn
            about the various types of components, and in chapters 6-9 we will look at the specific
            components KRAD provides out of the box.</para>
        <section>
            <title> Parts of a Component</title>
            <para> A component is made up of three different artifacts (see <xref linkend="fig6"/>). The first of
                these is a Java class. The Java class defines the properties and behavior the
                component can have. As we will see later on, the properties are what we can use to
                configure the component, while the behavior includes things such as how the
                component interacts with other components. As with any class, the properties can be
                primitive or collection types, or types of other objects. In this case of a
                component, these objects may be other components. Therefore components can be nested
                (or a composition). In addition, components may extend from other components to
                inherit properties and behavior. This forms a component hierarchy. The component
                class may exist anywhere on the class path.</para>
            <para><figure xml:id="fig6">
                <title>Building Blocks</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/componentParts.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject></figure></para>
            <para>The second artifact for a component is its rendering template. The template is a
                FreeMarker file that renders HTML/JS contents for the component instance. The
                template is an optional artifact. Components may 'self-render', which means the
                component object will be invoked to return the HTML/JS contents (note FreeMarker
                content cannot be used in this mode). However, most UIF components use templates as
                they are much easier and cleaner to implement. We will learn all about templates in
                the next section.</para>
            <para>The final piece of a component is its Spring bean definition. Spring bean XML is
                the mechanism by which developers configure and assemble UIF components. Creating a
                bean definition for the component (sometimes known as the 'base' definition) allows
                us to specify defaults for properties, in addition to giving the component a unique
                name within the bean container (note that it would be possible to use the component
                without a base definition, but then the class would have to be specified each time
                it is used).</para>
            <para>One important property that is configured with the base definition is the
                template. The template property (available on all components) is the path to the
                template FreeMarker file that will render the component. Specifying the template
                through the bean configuration provides loose coupling of the component class and
                template. This is very important to the flexibility of the system. The template can
                be located anywhere in the web root for the application.</para>
            <para>The base component definition also does a couple more things for us. One of these
                is setting up the component with scope prototype. All UIF components maintain state,
                so they must be marked as prototype within Spring. Finally, it is recommended the
                base definition be setup with an abstract parent bean. This setup looks like the
                following:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="componentName" parent="componentName-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="componentName-parentBean" abstract="true" class="edu.myedu.Sample.Component" scope="prototype">
...
&lt;/bean>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>This allows the base definition to be changed without having to copy the entire
                original configuration. Recall that Spring allows us to override a bean definition
                by specifying a bean with the same id. Therefore, if an institution wanted to change
                the default property for a component, they would simply include the following in the
                institutional spring files:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="componentName" parent="componentName-parentBean">
    &lt;property name="propertyName" value="overrideValue"/>
&lt;/bean>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Without the abstract parent bean, all of the initial property configuration would
                need to be copied (since setting the parent to "componentName" would cause a
                circular dependency).</para>
            <para>When defining base definitions we are not limited to just one. In many cases, it
                is useful to provide different configurations of a component as different bean
                configurations. For example, one component we will learn about is the TextControl.
                The text control renders a HTML input of type text and has a size property, which
                configures the display size for the input. First, we might setup a bean definition
                that looks like the following:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl" parent="Uif-TextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" class="org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.control.TextControl" scope="prototype">
    &lt;property name="template" value="/krad/WEB-INF/ftl/components/control/text.ftl"/>
    &lt;property name="size" value="30"/>
&lt;/bean>     </programlisting></para>
            <para>The control can then be used by bean references or inner beans:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="control">
    &lt;bean parent="Uif-TextControl" p:size="10"/>
&lt;/property>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Notice here we are overriding the size property because we need a small input.
                Seeing this, we might decide we want to have a standard size for small, medium, and
                large inputs. Therefore we set the following bean configurations:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl" parent="Uif-TextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;beanid="Uif-TextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" class="org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.control.TextControl" scope="prototype">
    &lt;property name="template" value="/krad/WEB-INF/ftl/components/control/text.ftl"/>
    &lt;property name="size" value="30"/>
&lt;/bean>
&lt;bean id="Uif-SmallTextControl" parent="Uif-SmallTextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-SmallTextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" parent="Uif-TextControl">
    &lt;property name="size" value="10 "/>
&lt;/bean>
&lt;bean id="Uif-MediumTextControl" parent="Uif-MediumTextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-MediumTextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" parent="Uif-TextControl">
    &lt;property name="size" value="30 "/>
&lt;/bean>
&lt;bean id="Uif-LargeTextControl" parent="Uif-LargeTextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-LargeTextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" parent="Uif-TextControl">
    &lt;property name="size" value="100 "/>
&lt;/bean>     </programlisting></para>
            <para>Now when we need a small text control, we can reference the 'Uif-SmallTextControl'
                bean and not specify the size:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="control">
    &lt;bean parent="Uif-SmallTextControl"/>  
&lt;/property>      </programlisting></para>
            <para>Many of the components provided by the UIF have multiple base bean
                definitions.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Customizing and Extending the UIF</title>
            <para>We know that a major goal of the UIF is to provide a high level of flexibility.
                Furthermore, we have seen the central concept of components. So how does this
                component design achieve our goal?</para>
            <para>To answer this question, let's first take a look at what criteria we should look
                for in a highly flexible system.<orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Can we customize all parts of the system, or are there places that are
                            'unreachable'?</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If we can customize something, can we do that outside of the original
                            codebase so that we do not hinder our upgrade path?</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>What level of understanding do we need to customize the system? Is
                            each customization different? Does it require us to get deep inside the
                            black box?</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Can we add to the system? If so, do those additions act as first class
                            citizens, or require some alternate approach to use?</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist></para>
            <para>Recall besides the base 'plumbing' of the UIF, a set of components is provided to
                build pages with. Each of these components brings a piece of functionality to the
                framework. Thus we can think of them as 'building blocks' for the framework as shown
                in <xref linkend="fig7"/>.</para>
            <para><figure xml:id="fig7">
                <title>Building Blocks</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/componentBuildingBlocks.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject></figure></para>
            <para>Now let's suppose we want to customize a 'core' component.  To do this, we simply
                change one of the component parts (class, bean, or template). We saw previously how
                we can change the bean configuration for a component by providing another bean
                configuration with the same id. Using the abstract parent bean, we can inherit all
                of the original configuration and then change or add configuration as needed. </para>
            <para>For an example of this, let's use the UIF 'required' message field which has the
                following definition:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-RequiredMessage" parent="Uif-RequiredMessage-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-RequiredMessage-parentBean" abstract="true" parent="Uif-MessageField" 
    scope="prototype" p:messageText="*" p:messageType="REQUIRED">
...
&lt;/bean>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>We decide for our application we want the required message to actually display the
                text 'required' instead of the configured asterisk. To do this we include a bean
                with the same id in our application (or institutional spring) file:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-RequiredMessage" parent="Uif-RequiredMessage-parentBean" p:messageText="required" />    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Now everywhere the required message field is used the text 'required' will display
                instead of '*'. </para>
            <tip><para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Adding Spring Files: </emphasis> Adding Spring files to the
                container can be done using the KRADConfigurer. </para></tip>
            <para>Next let's consider the component template. Remember the template is a FreeMarker
                file located in the web root (or classpath) and generates the HTML/JS contents for
                the component. If we wish to change this rendering, we can create another template
                in a web location of our choosing. </para>
            <para>Depending on the level of customization we need to implement, we might start by
                copying the current template contents, or create one from scratch. One we have the
                template that renders the component how we want, then we override the bean
                configuration as described previously and override the template property specifying
                the location for the new template. Besides the source location for the template,
                there is the templateName property which specifies a name for the template in the
                host language (the name by which the template is invoked). This must be unique, so
                that when overridding a template, we must also give a unique name for the template
                (unless we are overriding the base bean definition
                itself):<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl" parent="Uif-TextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" class="org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.control.TextControl" scope="prototype">
    &lt;property name="template" value="/krad/WEB-INF/ftl/components/control/text.ftl"/>
    &lt;property name="templateName" value="uif_text"/>
    &lt;property name="size" value="30"/>
&lt;/bean>
&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl" parent="Uif-TextControl-parentBean">
    &lt;property name="template" value="/myapp/WEB-INF/ftl/components/text.ftl"/>
    &lt;property name="templateName" value="myapp_text"/>
&lt;/bean>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>The last part of the component we have to customize is the Java class itself.
                Modifying the Java class would allow us to add new properties and behavior to the
                component. For this, we can create a new class that extends the original component
                class. This new class can be anywhere in the classpath. New properties can be made
                available by adding properties to our extension class (with getters and setters).
                Customization of behavior can be modified by overriding the various lifecycle
                methods. These methods will be covered in Chapter 9. Once we have the new class, we
                associate it with the component by again overriding the bean definition:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl" parent="Uif-TextControl-parentBean"/>
&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl-parentBean" abstract="true" class="org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.control.TextControl" scope="prototype">
    &lt;property name="template" value="/krad/WEB-INF/ftl/components/control/text.ftl"/>
    &lt;property name="size" value="30"/>
&lt;/bean>
&lt;bean id="Uif-TextControl" parent="Uif-TextControl-parentBean" class="edu.myedu.Sample.TextControl">
    &lt;property name="additionalProperty" value="foo"/>
&lt;/bean>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Now that we have seen how to customize a component, how do we go about adding a
                new component? We can add a component using the same process we saw for
                customization. The difference between adding and customizing are:<orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>We will create a new base Spring definition (not overriding an
                            existing)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The Java class will not extend a core component, but one of the
                            provided base classes (described later on in this chapter)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist></para>
            <para>Essentially we need to create the three artifacts for the component just like the
                core components. Once created, using custom components is no different than using
                the provided components.  Therefore as depicted in <xref linkend="fig8"/>, core and custom
                components work together as part of the framework. </para>
            <para><figure xml:id="fig8">
                <title>Building Blocks</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/componentBuildingBlock2.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject></figure>
                </para>
            <tip>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Planned Feature</emphasis></para>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Component 'Drop In': </emphasis> In the future KRAD
                    might support a plugin facility for 'dropping' in new components. A component
                    'bundle' could be downloaded and dropped into the plugin directory, eliminating
                    the need to copy the base bean definition, template file, and Java class. </para>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>RECAP</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Components are a central piece to the UIF and are critical for customizing
                        and extending the framework</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Each component is made up of three parts:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Java Class – defines the properties and behavior</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>FreeMarker Template – renders HTML/JS content for a component
                                    instance </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>XML Definition(s) – provides default properties for a
                                    component (including the template) and assigns an ID for using
                                    the component</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KRAD provides several components for use 'Out of the Box'</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>We can customize a component by changing its bean definition, writing a
                        new template, or extending the Java class to add properties or
                        behavior</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>We can create our own components by creating the three necessary artifacts
                        (outside of the Rice code)</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Building Templates with FreeMarker </title>
        <section>
            <title>Variable Markup</title>
        <para>Given that the goal of the UIF is to produce web pages (HTML, Image, and JS content);
                the component template provides a very important role. This section will help us
                understand templates better, and how they are built using the FreeMarker templating
                engine.</para>
        <para>Before looking at templates in KRAD, let's step back and think about the job of
                building a web UI framework. We know web pages are rendered by a browser from HTML
                markup, along with other resources such as script and image files. So ultimately,
                the result from our framework is this markup that will be streamed back as the
                response to a request by the user. This is the output of the framework. The input to
                the framework will be XML configuration provided by an application developer. So how
                do these get connected? </para>
        <para>Based on our Spring knowledge, we know the XML metadata will get used to create
                Objects in the Spring container, so these objects' instances now contain the
                developer's configuration. We can then expose these objects to the FreeMarker
                templates, which will combine the object values with static contents to produce the
                resulting markup (see <xref linkend="fig6"/>).</para>
        <para>Templates within KRAD are created using the FreeMarker framework. FreeMarker is a
            templating framework that allows template files to be assembled at runtime. To create a
            template in FreeMarker, we start by creating a file with extension .ftl. This can be
            anywhere in the application web directory or classpath.</para>
        <para>Now we can add static HTML content (just like creating an HTML page) along with
            dynamic content using the FreeMarker
            language:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;html>
  &lt;head>&lt;title>${KualiForm.title}&lt;/title>&lt;/head>
  &lt;body>
    &lt;table>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td colspan="2">${KualiForm.header}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td>${menu}&lt;/td>
        &lt;td>${body}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td colspan="2">${KualiForm.footer}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
    &lt;/table>
  &lt;/body>
&lt;/html>     </programlisting></para>
        <para>Notice within this file the use of '${}' notation. This is known as an interpolation,
                and is where data will be inserted. This data comes from a model we expose to
                FreeMarker before rendering the templates. The model is a map of objects that can be
                referenced within the FreeMarker templates. The map key gives the name by which the
                object is identified. In KRAD, one object that is exposed by default is the form
                object. This object is a wrapper for all the data that needs to be present for
                rendering the page, and is given the identifier 'KualiForm'. </para>
        <para>Other objects exposed through the model are:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The Http Request Object exposed with identifier 'request'</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The Rice UserSession object exposed with identifier 'userSession'</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A Map of Rice configuration parameters exposed with identifier
                        'ConfigProperties'</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <tip>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Spring ModelAndView</emphasis>
            </para>
            <para>The web tier of KRAD is implemented using the Spring MVC framework. Spring
                provides an object named ModelAndView that we build and return from our controller
                methods. The model part of this object serves the same purpose as the FreeMarker
                model. In fact, when using the freemarker view resolver, Spring pulls the model out
                of this object for configuring FreeMarker. Therefore, for exposing additional
                objects in the templates, we can add those objects to the ModelAndView object we
                return. </para>
        </tip>
        <para>Now suppose we want to pull out part of our FreeMarker content into a separate file,
            so that it can be reused between different templates. First we create another file with
            .ftl extension. Let's call this file body.ftl. Now we add the FreeMarker content to our
            template
            file:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;h2> This is the page body &lt;/h2>
${KualiForm.body}</programlisting></para>
        <para>Next, we can bring in the contents of body.ftl into our main template by using the
            FreeMarker directive named <code>include</code>. To use the include directive we specify
            the absolute or relative path to the template file that should be included using the
            path
            attribute:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;html>
  &lt;head>&lt;title>${KualiForm.title}&lt;/title>&lt;/head>
  &lt;body>
    &lt;table>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td colspan="2">${KualiForm.header}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td>${menu}&lt;/td>
        &lt;td>
           &lt;#include path="body.ftl"/>
        &lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td colspan="2">${KualiForm.footer}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
    &lt;/table>
  &lt;/body>
&lt;/html>     </programlisting></para>
        <para>Interpolations may also contain expressions (see below). For example, we can add two
                numeric properties together and render the result as follows:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">${KualiForm.numProp1 + KualiForm.numProp2}</programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>With FreeMarker we are not limited to just reading properties from the model, but also
            may invoke methods! This is done using the method name within the expression, followed
            by list of values to send as parameters. The parameter values may reference another
            model property or variable:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">${KualiForm.retrieveTaxAmount(taxNumber, 'T')} </programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>In addition to accessing dynamic data within the model, we can create new dynamic
            variables within the template. To create a new variable the <code>assign</code>
            directive is used. Following the assign keyword, the name and value for the variable are
            given separated by an
            equal:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#assign myVar="Hello!"/></programlisting></para>
        <para>Similar to model properties, the value for a variable can be written to the output
            stream using the ${}
            notation:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;td>${myVar}&lt;/td> &lt;#-- prints &lt;td>Hello!&lt;/td> --></programlisting></para>
      
        <para>When assigning a variable value, we may also use an expression. Freemarker supports
                all of the standard expression operators. The only notable difference is Freemarker
                does not support the alpha operator representation ('eq', 'ne', 'lt', 'or').
                Operators are specified with the usual '==', '!=', '&amp;&amp;', '||' and so on. The
                one exception in Freemarker is for '&gt;','&lt;','&gt;=','&lt;=" operators, the
                alpha operator can be given as well. The full list of expression operators is found
                    <link xlink:href="http://freemarker.sourceforge.net/docs/dgui_template_exp.html"
                    >here</link>. </para>
        <para>Let's take a simple case of addition as an example:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#assign groupOneTotal=50/>
&lt;#assign groupTwoTotal=100/>
&lt;#assign totalBothGroups=groupOneTotal + groupTwoTotal/></programlisting>
        </para>
        
        <tip>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Watch out for Nulls!</emphasis></para>
            <para>When a variable or property expression is null, by default FreeMarker will not
                convert to an empty string but instead throw an exception. To prevent FreeMarker
                from throwing an exception (and instead output nothing) an exclamation mark must be
                added after the variable. For example: ${variable!}</para>
        </tip>
    </section>
    
        <section>
            <title>FreeMarker DataTypes</title>
            <para>When working with model properties or variables, it is important to know the
            underlying datatype. The datatype determines how the variable can be used within the
            markup (for example in expressions, interpolations, and passing macro
            parameters).</para>
        <para>The datatypes used by FreeMarker are String, Number, Boolean, and Date (Scalars);
            Hash, Sequence, and Collection (Containers); Methods and Custom Directives
            (Subroutines); and Node. </para>
        <para>
            <tip>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Java Objects</emphasis></para>
                <para>Note that model properties that represent Objects are treated as a Hash in
                        FreeMarker. This goes for the model itself that is exposed for
                        rendering.</para>
            </tip>
        </para>
        <para>Datatypes are implied by FreeMarker in one of two ways. For model properties, the
                datatype is derived from the underlying Java type. For variables, the datatype will
                be derived based on the assigned value. All string values must be quoted. If value
                is not quoted, the datatype will be determined based on the format. The keywords
                true and false are used to indicate a boolean type.</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#assign var="Hello"/> &lt;#-- string datatype -->
&lt;#assign var=3/> &lt;#-- numeric datatype -->
&lt;#assign var=true/> &lt;#-- boolean datatype -->
&lt;#assign comp=model.comp/> &lt;#-- assuming model.comp is object, hash datatype --></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Interpolations may only be used for variables/properties that are scalars. FreeMarker
            converts number and date types to a string format based on the environment settings.
            Boolean types must be explicity converted to a string using the built-in
            '?string'.</para>
        <para>When passing parameter values for macro invocations, we must also be aware of the
            datatypes expected by the macro. Passing a quoted parameter value where the macro
            expects a number or boolean will cause an error. In the following example, the macro
            with name 'grid' expects a parameter named 'rowCount' of type number:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro grid rowCount>
  ...
&lt;/#macro>

Incorrect Invocation:
&lt;@grid rowCount="3"/>

Correct Invocation:
&lt;@grid rowCount=3/></programlisting>
        </para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Control Statements</title>
            <para>FreeMarker allows us to conditionally evaluate a block of markup, or to evaluate a
                block of markup multiple times through the use of control statements. A control
                statement is implemented using one of the following directives:</para>
        <para><emphasis>if, else, elseif</emphasis></para>
        <para>We can conditionally evaluate a block using the if directive. Following the if or
                elseif directive is an expression to evaluate. If the expression evaluates to true,
                the corresponding block will be included, otherwise the block given by the else
                directive (or the next expression) is evaluated if an elseif directive follows. The
                general syntax is as follows:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#if expression1>
  // block
&lt;#elseif expression 2>
  // block
&lt;#elseif expression n>
  // block
&lt;/#if></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>In the following example we have a variable named colCount which holds an
            integer:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#if colCount == 1>
  // block 1
&lt;#elseif colCount == 2>
  // block 2
&lt;#else>
  // block 3
&lt;/#if></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>In this example, we first check if the variable colCount is equal to 1, if so block 1
            is evaluated. If not, we check whether colCount is equal to 2 and if so evaluate block
            2. If neither conditions are true, block 3 will be evaluated.</para>
        <para><emphasis>list</emphasis></para>
        <para>The list directive allows us to loop through a variable (or model property) which is a
                sequence (array) type and evaluate a block within each iteration. This is a useful
                control statement for rendering items like a table or repeated sections. The list
                directive is used by specifying the variable/model name followed by a variable to
                expose each item under. The general syntax is as follows:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#list sequenceName as item>
   // block
&lt;/#list></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Let's take an example where we assume we have a model property named 'foods' that is a
            List. Within the list body, the item being iterated over will be exposed with the
            variable 'food':</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#list foods as food>
  Name: ${food.name}, Type: ${food.type}
&lt;/#list></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>If the datatype to iterate over is a Map, we can iterate using the list directive to
            iterate over the keys of the map like the following example:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#list map?keys as parm>
  ${map[parm]}
&lt;/#list></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Here the loop variable gives the key for the map entry we are iterating over.</para>
        <para>In addition to the loop variable exposed by the list directive, two additional
            variables are exposed. The first gives the index for the item and is retrieved by adding
            '_index' to the loop variable. The second indicates whether there are more items to
            iterate over and is retrieved by adding '_has_next' to the loop variable. </para>
        <para>Finally, the <code>break</code> directive exists to exit the list directive early, as
                the following example demonistrates:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#list seq as x>
  ${x}
  &lt;#if x = "spring">&lt;#break>&lt;/#if>
&lt;/#list>    </programlisting>
        </para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Context and Macros</title>
            <para>By default, templates that are executed (by include directives) all belong to the
                same namespace. This means each template has access to read and write the same
                variables. A change to the value of a variable in one template, will change the
                value of the variable in another. This namespace shared by templates is known as the
                global namespace.</para>
            <para>To execute FTL code in a separate namespace, FreeMarker allows the creation of
                    <code>Macros</code>. Macros are created using the macro directive and are given
                a name that can be used for invocation. For example, we can change our previous
                body.ftl to become a macro as
                follows:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro body>
  &lt;h2> This is the page body &lt;/h2>
  ${KualiForm.body}
&lt;/#macro></programlisting></para>
            <para>The name for the macro follows the #macro keyword. In this example we have named
                our macro 'body'. Between the macro start and end tag we can add FreeMarker content
                just as we would for a general template file. Each time the macro is invoked, this
                FreeMarker content will be evaluated. Therefore macros give us a way to reuse
                FreeMarker markup.</para>
            <para>Within the macro we can define new variables. As with a general template, we can
                use the <code>assign</code> directive to create a variable in the global namespace.
                However, since a macro has its own namespace, we can create a variable that is
                scoped to it as well. This is done using the <code>local</code> directive. The
                syntax for using the local directive is the same as the assign directive.</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro body>
  &lt;#local locVar="is only visible within macro"/>
&lt;#macro></programlisting>
            </para>
            <para>If a global variable exists with the same name, the local variable will override
                within the context of the macro. </para>
            <para>Macros may parameterize the content by accepting parameters. These parameters are
                given when the macro is invoked and are used within the macro body for evaluating
                the final output. Each parameter has a name by which it is identified. Therefore, to
                declare macro parameters, we simply list their identifying names on the macro
                directive after the macro name. Each parameter name is separated by a space:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro macroName parm1 parm2 parm3 parm4 ...></programlisting>
            </para>
            <para>Within the macro the parameters become local variables. We can print the parameter
                value to the output stream, use in a conditional statement, or use in any other way
                supported by variables. For example, let's add a header, bodyContent, and footer
                parameter to our body macro:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro body header bodyContent footer>
  &lt;body>
    &lt;table>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td colspan="2">${header}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td>${menu}&lt;/td>
        &lt;td>
           ${bodyContent}
        &lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
      &lt;tr>
        &lt;td colspan="2">${footer}&lt;/td>
      &lt;/tr>
    &lt;/table>
  &lt;/body>  
&lt;/#macro></programlisting>
            </para>
            
            <para>Notice in this example we are writing out the values of the given macro parameters
                using the ${} notation. Our body macro serves as a wrapper for the content.</para>
            <para>For each macro parameter we can also specify whether a value is required to be
                given by the caller, and if not a default value to use. A default value is indicated
                by placing an equal sign after the parameter name, followed by the default value
                (which can be an expression). If a default value is not given, the parameter is
                assumed to be required. All required parameters must be given before parameters that
                have defaults. Let's take a look at an example:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro body bodyContent header="Header One" footer="">
...</programlisting>
            </para>
            <para>Here we have changed the body macro to make the bodyContent a required parameter,
                but not the header or footer. If the header parameter is not specified by the
                caller, it will have a value of "Header One". Likewise, if the footer is not given,
                it will have a value of the empty string.</para>            
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Invoking Macros</title>
            <para>When a macro is loaded, it becomes a variable within the associated namespace. The
                macro name (identifier given after the macro declaration) becomes the variable name,
                and the assigned namespace is derived from the surrounding namespace of the
                FreeMarker file (see <link linkend="ftl_includes" endterm="ftl_includes.title"
                />).</para>
            <para>If the macro belongs to the global namespace, it can be invoked with the text
                '&lt;%' followed by the macro name. Any parameter values are then given after the
                macro name (separated by a space). Each parameter specification includes the
                parameter name, followed by the equal sign, followed by the parameter value (which
                can be an expression). The macro invocation is completed with the closing greater
                than sign.</para>
            <para>As an example, let's invoke our body macro created in the previous section,
                passing a value for the 'bodyContent' parameter:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;@body bodyContent="Hello KRAD World!"/></programlisting>
                
                
            </para>
            <para>or </para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#assign content="Hello KRAD World!"/>
&lt;@body bodyContent=content/></programlisting>
            </para>
            <para>When the macro is associated with a namespace, we must specify the namespace
                before the macro name, using a dot to separate each. Let's assume our body macro was
                associated with the namespace 'myapp'. We would then invoke the macro as
                follows:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;@myapp.body bodyContent=content/></programlisting>
            </para>
        </section>   
        
        <section >
            <title>Other Features of Macros</title>
            <para>Macros are very powerful constructs that allow great flexibility! Up to this point
            we have invoked macros by simply passing parameter values. A macro may also allow us to
            pass FreeMarker markup within the body of the macro tag. The macro can then render this
            content in one or more locations of the macro. To indicate where this content should be
            rendered, we use the <code>nested</code> directive. The nested directive may be used
            more than once within the macro definition:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro wrapTd>
  &lt;td>
  &lt;#nested/>
  &lt;/td>
&lt;/#macro>

Invocation:
&lt;@wrapTd>
  &lt;#if renderHeader>
    ${header}
  &lt;#else>
    ${footer}
  &lt;/#if>
&lt;/@wrapTd></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Assuming renderHeader is true, and the header variable is 'Header One', the following
                would be output:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;td>
Header One
&lt;/td></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Another feature available for macros is varargs (variable number of arguments). To
            indicate a macro accepts a variable number of arguments, the last parameter declaration
            must end with '...':</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro loop parms...>
  &lt;#list param.keys as key>
    ${parm[key]}
  &lt;/#list>
&lt;#macro>

Invocation:
&lt;@loop parm1 parm2/>
&lt;@loop parm1 parm2 parm3/></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>The parameter 'parms' becomes a hash, where the name for each additional parameter is
            the hash key and the corresponding parameter value the hash value. The macro may include
            other named parameters that are listed before the varargs declaration.</para>
        <para>Finally, FreeMarker provides the ability to create macro functions. These are macros
            that will run not to render output, but to calculate and return a value. These are
            created using the <code>function</code> directive. The function directive is used the
            same as the macro with a few exceptions. First the function directive is assumed to
            return a value. Any variable that is created within the function (or a global variable)
            may be returned using the <code>return</code> directive. The return directive is used by
            giving the variable name after the return keyword (we also may return an expression that
            will be evaluated as the function return value). </para>
        <para>Let's build an example function that returns the max of two numbers:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#function max number1 number2>
  &lt;#if number1 > number2>
    &lt;#return number1/>
  &lt;#else>
    &lt;#return number2/>
  &lt;/#if>
&lt;#function></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Functions also differ from Macros in how they are called. Recall functions return a
            value, therefore we can use them anywhere a value is expected. This includes within an
            interpolation, an expression, or variable assignment. In addition, passing parameter
            values is done using function syntax '(parm1, parm2, ...)' rather than key/value pairs.
            The following shows examples of invoking the max function above:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">${max(number1, number2)}
&lt;#assign maxNum=max(number1, number2)/>
&lt;#if number3 > max(number1, number2)>
   // block
&lt;/#if></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>Similar to macros, functions may be associated with a non-global namespace. When this
                is so, the namespace must be given before the function name, and a colon separates
                each.</para>
            
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Built-Ins</title>
            <para>Freemarker provides several utility functions called Built-Ins that can be applied
            to a variable or expression. The built-ins that can be used depend on the underlying
            datatype, as shown by the grouping below. To invoke a built-in, we add the question
            character ('?') after the variable (or expression), followed by the built-in name and
            any parameters. The following shows the general form:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">${someVariable?builtIn(parms)}</programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>The return value of the built-in invocation becomes the value for the
            expression:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#assign name='Joe Smith'/>
${name} &lt;#-- prints 'Joe Smith' -->
${name?upper_case} &lt;#-- prints 'JOE SMITH' --></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para> The following are other examples of built-ins provided.</para>
        <para><emphasis>String Built-Ins</emphasis></para>
        <para>substring(from, toExclusive) - Returns a substring of a given string starting at the
                given from index up to the given toExclusive index.</para>
        <para>html - Escapes html markup</para>
        <para>js_string - Escapes the string according to JavaScript string literals</para>
        <para>length - Returns the number of characters in the string</para>
        <para>lower_case - Lower cases the string</para>
        <para>left_pad(length) - Left pads the string with spaces until it reaches the given
            length</para>
        <para>right_pad(length) - Same as left pad, but pads with spaces to the right</para>
        <para>contains(substring) - Returns true if the string contains the given substring</para>
        <para>matches(regex) - Return true if the string matches the given regular expression</para>
        <para>replace(stringToReplace, replacement) - Replaces all occurances of stringToReplace in
            the string with the given replacement string</para>
        <para>split(splitString) - Splits a string into an array on occurances of the given
                splitString parameter</para>
        <para>starts_with(string) - Returns true if the string starts with the given string
            parameter</para>
        <para>trim - Removes leading and trailing whitespace</para>
        <para>upper_case - Upper cases the string</para>
        <para><emphasis>Boolean Built-Ins</emphasis></para>
        <para>string - Converts the boolean to a string using "true" as true and "false" as
            false</para>
        <para>string("yes", "no") - Converts the boolean to a string using the first string
                parameter if the boolean is true, and the second string parameter if the boolean is
                false</para>
        <para><emphasis>Other Built-Ins</emphasis></para>
        <para>has_content - Returns true if the variable is not null and is not empty (meaning if
                the variable has a size or length)</para>         
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="ftl_includes">
            <title xml:id="ftl_includes.title">Including FTL Files</title>
            <para>A template file may pull markup from another template file using the
                <code>include</code> directive. The include directive takes the path to the file as
            an argument, which may be expressed as a relative or absolute path:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#include '../footer.ftl'/>
&lt;#include '/krad/templates/footer.ftl'/></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>FreeMarker also supports a second way of including template files for the purpose of
                library (or namespace) creation. This is done using the <code>import</code>
                directive. Again, we must give the path to the file as an argument. We can also give
                an additional argument that will identify the namespace the template contents should
                be associated with. In the next example we include a freemarker template file that
                contains several macro definitions, and associate them with the namespace
                'myapp':</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#import 'myapp.ftl' as 'myapp'/></programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>All the macros contained in myapp.ftl will be associated with the myapp namespace and
            must be invoked through that namespace. Note when using import, any output generated by
            the included template will be ignored.</para>      
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Component Templates</title>
        <para>Each component within the KRAD UIF has a template file that defines a macro for
                rendering the component. The template location and the macro name are then
                configured with the component definition. Each time an instance of the component is
                encountered, the macro will be invoked with the component instance.</para>
        <para>Generally, the component macros do the following:</para>
        <para><orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                    <para>Insert values from the component properties with static markup</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Invoke rendering for child components</para>
                </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Coarse-Grained Parameters</title>
            <para>An important consideration when setting up a macro is how to setup the parameters.
            To help explain this, let's take a look at a sample text
            control:<programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;@spring.input id="${id}" path="${path}" disabled="${disabled}" size="${size}" maxlength="${maxLength}"/>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>This snippet is invoking a spring input macro, which will then output the HTML
                input tag. We see some of the attributes this macro provides are id, path, disabled,
                size, and maxlength. Since this template is generic (in the sense that it should
                render all instances of the TextControl) the values for these attributes need to be
                variable. Now based on our knowledge of macros, we can create an input macro which
                will allow values for these variables (or attributes) to be specified by the calling
                template. This would look like the following:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro uif_input id path disabled size maxLength>
  &lt;@spring:input id="${id}" path="${path}" disabled="${disabled}" size="${size}" maxlength="${maxLength}"/>  
&lt;/#macro>  </programlisting></para>
            <para>The calling template would then be:
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;@uif_input id="${component.id}" path="${component.path}" disabled="${component.disabled}" 
size="${component.size}" maxLength="${component.maxLength}"/>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Here the component variable is the component instance that has been exported to
                the page. </para>
            <para>Now let's suppose that a developer wishes to override the component class and
            template to provide a 'readonly' property. The template now looks like this:
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro uif_input id path disabled size maxLength readOnly>
  &lt;@spring.input id="${id}" path="${path}" disabled="${disabled}" size="${size}" maxlength="${maxLength}"
    readOnly="${readOnly}"/>  
&lt;/#macro>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>In order for the readonly attribute to be passed in, the developer must also
                change the calling template and pass the corresponding component property value.
                This not only adds to the amount of work required for customizing a component, but
                also leads to general maintenance issues within the framework.</para>
            <para>To solve this problem, KRAD passes the full component to the templates and not the
            individual properties of the component. Passing the full component makes changes our
            original macro to:
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro uif_input component>
  &lt;@spring.input id="${component.id}" path="${component.path}" disabled="${component.disabled}" size="${component.size}"/>
&lt;/#macro>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Now for the custom template, we simply make use of the new property without any
            changes to the calling template:
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;#macro uif_input component>
  &lt;@spring.input id="${component.id}" path="${component.path}" disabled="${component.disabled}" size="${component.size}"
                 readOnly="${component.readOnly}"/>
&lt;/#macro>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>In addition to providing more template flexibility, using the course grained
                parameters gives us a uniform way of invoking templates (as we will see in a bit,
                the framework provides a generic macro that can be used to render any component).
                Depending on the type of component, other parameters may be sent as well. The
                standard macro contracts are as follows:</para>
            
            <table frame="all" tabstyle="striped">
                <title>Macro Parameter Contracts</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Component Type</entry>
                            <entry>Macro Parameters</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>View</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>view: the view component instance</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Group</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>group: the group component instance</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Field</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>field: the field component instance</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Element</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>element: the element component instance</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Control</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>control: the control component instance</member>
                                    <member>field: the input field component instance</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Widget</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>widget: the widget component instance</member>
                                    <member>parent: the component instance that contains the widget</member>
                                    <member>additional parameters depending on widget</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Layout Manager</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <simplelist>
                                    <member>items: the group's items</member>
                                    <member>manager: the layout manager instance</member>
                                    <member>container: the container instance the layout manager is associated with</member>
                                </simplelist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            
            <para>Note that the macro parameter that contains the component instance is exposed
                under different names (group, field, element, ...), depending on the component type.
                The name is specified by the <code>getComponentTypeName()</code> method on the
                component.</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>The KRAD Macro Library</title>
        <para>KRAD also comes with macros that provide utility functions for creating templates.
                These can be referenced by the component macros to help with building content. For
                example, the div and span macros generate the corresponding HTML tags with standard
                attributes (such as id and class). These macros are exposed under the krad
                namespace, and are available by default to all component templates. The following
                shows an example of using the script wrapper tag:</para>
        <para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;@krad.script value="alert('hello');"/></programlisting>
        </para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Template Macro</title>
            <para>In Chapter 8 we will learn how to assemble UIF components into a View. The View is
                a component itself that, among other things, encapsulates all other components for
                our UI. It can also be thought of as a tree of components. The rendering processes
                starts by invoking the configured view template macro. The view template macro then
                in turn renders its child components, and so on, until the complete tree has been
                traversed. Therefore, the responsibility of a template is to not only render the
                necessary markup, but to invoke rendering for its child components. To help with
                this, KRAD provides the template macro.</para>
            <para>The template macro requires the component parameter to be specified. This is the
            child component that should be rendered:</para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">
&lt;@krad.template component=childComponent/&gt;
            </programlisting>
          
            <para>The template macro will then create the call for invoking the component macro, and
                passing the component parameter (and any additional parameters). <xref linkend="KRAD_Rendering_Process"/>
                depicts the rendering process.</para>
            <figure xml:id="KRAD_Rendering_Process">
                <title>KRAD Rendering Process</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/KRAD_Rendering_Process.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Besides invoking the template for the child component, the template macro performs
            the following:</para>
        <para><orderedlist>
            <listitem><para>Setup progressive rendering or component refresh</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Output content from self-rendering components</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Generate event script (onblur, onchage, ...)</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Generate component tooltip script</para></listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>
        </section>
        
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Templates dynamically create HTML markup based on the components.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Templates within KRAD are created using the FreeMarker framework.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Within templates we can use the interpolation syntax '${}' to output dynamic values.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>By default the UIF Form object, request object, user session, and configuration properties are made
                    available to templates.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>FreeMarker supports all the standard expressions for variable assignment, logic tests, and interpolation.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>FreeMarker allows us to create variables within the template using the <code>assign</code> directive.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>FreeMarker has the following datatypes: String, Number, Boolean, Date, Hash, Sequence, Collection,
                          Method, and Node.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>FreeMarker provides the <code>if,else,elseif</code> control directive for conditionally including
                    template content.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>FreeMarker provides the <code>list</code> control directive for looping over template content one
                    or more times.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Macros provide the ability to create reusable template content that can be parameterized and create
                    variables in a local namespace.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Macros are created using the #macro directive, followed by a name for the macro, followed by zero or
                    more parameter names. The template content that should be rendered when the macro is invoked is given between
                    the opening and closing #macro tags.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Variables created within a macro that should have local scope are created using the <code>local</code> directive.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Default values can be specified for parameters by adding an equal and then the default value after the
                    parameter name. If a parameter does not have a default value defined it becomes a required parameter.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Macros are invoked using the '@' symbol followed by the macro name.
                        Parameter values are given after the macro name with key=value pairs
                        (parameterName=parameterValue).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>When the macro is associated with a namespace, we must specify the namespace
                        before the macro name, using a dot to separate each.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Macros can render content passed through the invocation body using the
                            <code>nested</code> directive.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A type of macro that returns a value is a function. Functions are created using the <code>function</code> directive
                    and return a value using the <code>return</code> directive.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Freemarker provides several utility functions called Built-Ins that can be applied
                        to a variable or expression.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A template file may pull markup from another template file using the
                        <code>include</code> directive.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Each component within the KRAD UIF has a template file that defines a macro for
                        rendering the component.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Each component macro receives the component instance as a
                        parameter.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The template macro can be used to invoke rendering of a component.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>    
    
    <section>
        <title>The Component Interface </title>
        <para>Over the next few sections, we will look deeper into UIF components and the properties
            they have. These components are defined by their Java class. The class declares how a
            component can be used and how it works with other components. As in all object-oriented
            designs, these classes model the domain objects in our problem area, which is building
            web pages! Thus the component classes found should be mostly familiar to anyone who has
            worked with the web (controls, labels, containers, buttons, links, ...). </para>
        <para>To become a UIF component, a class must implement the
            org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.component.Component interface. This interface defines standard
            getters/setters for properties all components should have, in addition to methods that
            are invoked during the view lifecycle. Along with the Component interface, the abstract
            implementation org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.component.ComponentBase is provided which can be
            extended to build new components. Other than default implementations for lifecycle
            methods which we will explore later, this class is essentially a POJO (Plain Old Java
            Object) for the common properties. </para>
        <section>
            <title>Common Component Properties </title>
            <para>We have already learned about one very important property that all components have
                – the template and template name. The template is the path to the FreeMarker file
                that will perform the rendering process (creating of HTML markup) for the component.
                The template name is the name of the macro by which the rendering can be invoked.
                Now let's look at some other properties that we get from ComponentBase:</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Id</emphasis> – All components must have a unique identifier
                within a view. This id plays a critical role both server side and on the client. On
                the server, the id is used to pull a component from its containing view. A view can
                contain many components that are deeply nested. Iterating through this tree to find
                a particular component can require a lot of coding and add up to many wasted cycles.
                With the id we can 'index' the view such that a component can be retrieved in a
                single call. </para>
            <para>On the client, the id becomes even more important. As is the case for many of the
                server side component properties, the id is used to populate the id attribute on the
                HTML element. This results in unique ids for all elements on the page. These ids can
                then be referenced by a script created by the framework or by the developer.
                Furthermore, it is also possible to build CSS based on the ids (although this is not
                the recommended strategy). </para>
            <para>For generating the id values, there are a few options KRAD provides. First, the id
                can be assigned by the developer, or it can by generated by the framework. Manual
                assignment can furthermore be done in one of two ways. The first is to set the id by
                using the bean property tag. For example:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean parent="Component">
    &lt;property name="id" value="ks34"/>  </programlisting></para>
            <para>The second way to manual assign the component id is by using the bean id
                attribute:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="ks34" parent="Component"&gt;  </programlisting></para>
            <para>Since the id bean attribute is already required in most beans (top level beans),
                it is often most convenient to take this approach. If both the bean id attribute and
                the id property are specified, the id property value will be used. </para>
            <para>Note that when a bean inherits a bean definition, an id specified with the
                property tag will be inherited, while the id attribute of the bean tag will not. </para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="ks34" parent="Component">
...
&lt;/bean>

&lt;!-- this bean will not have a configured id -->
&lt;bean parent="ks34">
...
&lt;/bean>   </programlisting>
            <para>If an id is not configured by one of the above mechanisms, the framework will
                generate and assign a unique id for the component. Ids are generated using a
                sequence that starts at 1 each time the view lifecycle is run (each request), and
                prefixed with 'u'. For example, the first few generated ids would be 'u1', 'u2', and
                'u3'. </para>
            <para>The component ids are assigned by the framework at the beginning of the lifecycle
                (the 'initialize' phase). This guarantees all components will have an id throughout
                the view lifecycle (important for script generation in addition to many other
                things). There is one twist, however. Some components are dynamically created while
                processing the view data (the 'applyModel' phase). For example, all collection row
                fields cannot be created until the collection data is available. In these cases, the
                configured component represents a 'prototype' for creating the dynamic components.
                The prototype will have an id that was manually or automatically assigned. For
                creating the dynamic component, the prototype is copied and then adjusted. This
                means the id value will be copied as well. In order to give the copy a unique id,
                the id is suffixed. In the example of collection rows, each id is suffixed with the
                line ('l0', 'l1', 'l2'...). For example, if the prototype has an id of 'u56', the
                field in the first collection line will have id 'u56_l0', in the second 'u56_l1',
                and so on. Other id suffixes used in the framework will be discussed in the various
                component sections. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="bold">Factory Id:</emphasis> Another property we find on ComponentBase is
                        <emphasis role="keyword">factoryId</emphasis>. This is used to hold the
                    original id for components that are copies of prototypes (dynamically) created.
                    The property is necessary when we need to get a new instance of component using
                    the ComponentFactory. Because the component was dynamically created, the
                    ComponentFactory is not aware of it. However, it is aware of its prototype.
                    Using the factoryId, we can get a new instance of the prototype and then adjust
                    as necessary. </para></tip>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Title</emphasis> – For most components, we can specify the
                title property. This property gives extra information for the component that will be
                available in the user interface. This is an example of a property that many
                components have, but is used differently between components. For example, one of the
                component types we will learn about in the next section is a <emphasis role="keyword"
                    >Container</emphasis>. Components generally begin with a header (using the HTML
                header tag) and use the title property for the header text. Other types of
                components include <emphasis role="keyword">Fields</emphasis> and <emphasis role="keyword"
                    >Controls</emphasis>. The component types use the title property as the title
                attribute on the corresponding element they produce:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;element title="component title property value"/&gt;  </programlisting></para>
            <para>The title attribute value is most often shown as a tooltip when the user hovers
                over the element. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Title Property:</emphasis> The reason we say title property
                can be specified for 'most' components is that there are some that do not use this.
                Since the overwhelming majority do, it was added to ComponentBase for convenience. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Render</emphasis> – The render property is a Boolean that
                indicates whether the HTML markup should be generated for the component. When this
                is set to false, the configured template will not be invoked during the rendering
                process. By using conditional expressions to set the render property, we can make
                our view much more dynamic. Essentially the render property allows us to display or
                not display a component based on runtime conditions. </para>
            <para> For example in the following configuration only field1 will be rendered:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean parent="Uif-InputField"
    p:propertyName="field1"/> &lt;bean parent="Uif-InputField"
    p:propertyName="field2" p:render="false"/>  </programlisting></para>
            <para>The default value for render is true, so if the render property is not specified
                the component will be rendered. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Hidden</emphasis> – The hidden property is similar to the
                render property in that it configures whether or not the component is displayed.
                However, when a component is hidden (and render is set to true), the corresponding
                template will be invoked to generate markup. The content is then surrounded with a
                div that contains a style of display none. This keeps the content from being
                visible. The content can be displayed by changing the CSS display style through
                script. This provides a mechanism for toggling the display of a component on the
                client. Later on, we will learn about jQuery, which among many other things, allows
                us to flip the visibility of an element by invoking the show or hide function. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">ReadOnly</emphasis> – It is common to use the UIF for
                building forms that will collect data and perform a process on behalf of the user.
                There are a variety of components, such as controls and widgets, that allow the user
                to input data. These components have a state of editable (user input is allowed) or
                read only (user input is not allowed). To indicate a component should be in the read
                only state we can set the readOnly property to true. Again, this is a property that
                expressions are generally used for that sets the state based on a condition. </para>
            <para>Since it varies how components allow user input, the impact of setting a component
                as read only varies. For example, read-only controls simply display the control
                value as HTML text. An action field, on the other hand (button, link, image), will
                not render when set to read only. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">More Info:</emphasis> Components such as controls and action
                fields also support the disabled property. When these components are disabled they
                are in a read only state (no user input is allowed), however they are presented
                differently. Although the disabled appearance can be modified, generally the
                component appears as it does when editable (for example the actual control or button
                appears) but appears dimmed. The UIM provide guidelines for when to use disabled
                over readOnly. </para>
            <para>By default, the component base bean definitions have the readOnly property set as
                a condition on the read only status of the parent. Recall that our View represents a
                tree of components, where each component contains zero or more child components.
                This is often referred to as a parent-child relationship. All components with the
                exception of the View have a parent. Thus if the parent is read only, the child will
                be as well. </para>
            <para>One example of the parent-child relationships is the Container component. The
                purpose of a container is to hold other components and provide a layout. Therefore,
                the components in the container are child components, and the container is the
                parent component. Setting the container component as read only will make all
                components within the container read only. This is a convenient feature that
                simplifies configuration. For example, if we needed to make a group of fields read
                only, we can add the readOnly="true" property to the container component instead of
                adding the property to each field. Furthermore, since the View contains all the
                components, we can add readOnly="true" to make our entire web page read only. </para>
            <para>Some views are always read only. One example of this is the Inquiry view which
                displays information about a data object instance. The InquiryView base bean has the
                readOnly property set to true. Therefore all components added to a view of this type
                will be read only without having to specify the property. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Required</emphasis> – When a component allows user input,
                the required property indicates whether the user must provide a value (or complete
                the input/action). This is most typically used with input fields that have a
                control, but can also be used with a container (group) to indicate a section must be
                completed (fields in the section must have input). Other components may use the
                required attribute in a way that is appropriate for the component. </para>
            <para>In the case of input fields, setting required to true will do a couple of things.
                First, a message will be displayed to the user indicating if it is required (by
                default an asterisk '*'). Second, the framework will perform validation client side
                and/or server side that checks a value was given. If the value is empty, an error
                message is created and presented to the user. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Style and Style Classes</emphasis> – KRAD provides a lot of
                flexibility to make your web applications look great! All UIF components have a
                configured style class that performs the visual treatment. These style classes are
                provided within the CSS files that come with KRAD. However, if needed, using the
                style properties we can add or override CSS configuration for each component. </para>
            <para>Inline style configuration can be specified using the style property. The value is
                then placed as the style attribute value for the corresponding HTML element.
                Likewise, style classes can be specified using the styleClasses property. This
                property is a list type with each list item specifying a style class. The configured
                style classes are concatenated into a string using a space delimiter, then output as
                the class attribute value for the corresponding element. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Progressive and Refresh</emphasis> – Component base contains
                several properties that relate to configuring progressive disclosure or component
                refresh functionality. This is covered in detail in Chapter 11. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Order</emphasis> – KRAD adds some abilities to the Spring
                configuration system, including more control over collection merging. In a base bean
                definition that contains a collection, each component in the collection can have an
                order specified. When inheriting the collection property in child beans, components
                can be specified with the same order to replace items in the parent list or given an
                order that inserts the component between two items of the parent collection. This
                feature in covered in more detail at the end of this chapter. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="keyword">Read Only</emphasis>: As stated above, the feature of read only
                    inheritance is done by setting an expression on the readOnly property which is
                    inherited. This configuration is as follows:
                    <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="readOnly" value="@{#parent.readOnly}"/&gt;     </programlisting></para>
            <para>However, the readOnly property can be overridden to specify another condition, or
                    to explicitly make the component editable. This can be useful for cases when a
                    few of the child components need to be editable, but the majority should be read
                    only. We can set the parent as readOnly="true" which will make all child
                    components read only. Then we can add readOnly="false" to the few components
                    that should be editable. </para>
            </tip>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Skip In Tab Order</emphasis> – By default, tabbing will
                follow the natural order of the elements and include each element that can accept
                focus. When needed, the element corresponding to the KRAD component can be taken out
                of the tab order (will not be tabbed to) by setting the skipInTabOrder Boolean to
                true. An example of where this might be needed is a widget. The widget might contain
                several elements that work together as one focusable item. Within the item, keyboard
                shortcuts can be provided for navigating to the various elements. The user can
                simply tab again to get out of the widget (instead of having to tab possibly several
                times). </para>
            <para>More finely grained control over the tabbing order can be configured as well using
                the tabIndex property of Control. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Finalize Method To Call</emphasis> – Although you can do a
                great number of things using XML, you also have the option of assembling components
                with code. One way to invoke code is with the finalizeMethodToCall. This is the name
                of a method on the ViewHelperServiceImpl that should be called during the finalize
                phase of the view lifecycle. Standard arguments to this method are the component
                instance and the model (view data). Two additional properties,
                finalizeMethodAdditionalArguments and finalizeMethodInvoker, exist for greater
                flexibility on invoking a method. Code support is covered in detail in Chapter 10. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Self-Render and Render Output</emphasis> – As described in
                the section on templates and Apache Tiles, most components are rendered by a
                FreeMarker file that combines parameters from the components with static content to
                produce HTML markup. Components may render without a template by generating the
                markup through code. This is done by setting the selfRender flag to true. When this
                flag is turned on, instead of invoking a template, the method getRenderOutput will
                be invoked on the component instance to return the markup that should be output. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="keyword">Self-Rendered Content</emphasis>: The markup returned by a self-rendered
                    component may not include dynamic markup (FreeMarker content). The string is
                    written directly to the response without going through FreeMarker processing,
                    therefore only HTML markup must be returned. </para></tip>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Component Security</emphasis> – KRAD allows for fine-grained
                security to be defined, which integrates with the KIM (Kuali Identity Management)
                module. Security restrictions are indicated by setting a flag on an <emphasis
                    role="keyword">org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.component.ComponentSecurity</emphasis>
                instance. When a flag is set, the framework will check a KIM permission (setup for
                that restriction type) and, if not granted to the user, the restriction will be
                activated. Particular security flags will be discussed while looking at each
                component. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Component Modifiers</emphasis> – Component modifiers are
                classes that can be configured on a component to modify its properties through code.
                A component may have one or more component modifiers that get applied in the order
                they are configured. Modifiers can be useful in many cases. For example, the
                maintenance framework supports a comparison view where an 'old' and 'new' field is
                presented for each field. To achieve this, a component modifier was created that
                reads the configured group fields copying each to make the 'old' field. Then a base
                bean was created with the component modifier configured. All maintenance groups then
                extend this bean and inherit the comparison feature. </para>
            <para>Component modifiers can also have a condition that determines whether it should
                run (the <emphasis role="keyword">runCondition</emphasis>). In the example of the
                maintenance modifier, we only want to show the comparison when doing an edit
                operation (not for a new or copy). Therefore, the run condition is setup to check
                that the maintenance action is edit. The framework will evaluate this condition and
                only invoke the modifier if the condition succeeds. </para>
            <para>There are many other things that can be done with component modifiers which will
                be covered in Chapter 10. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Template Options</emphasis> – Besides the properties a
                component class has, some component templates support options that can be configured
                using the <emphasis role="keyword">templateOptions</emphasis> map. These can be thought
                of as 'pass-through' parameters since the component class is not aware of them. </para>
            <para>Template options are used primarily with Widgets that invoke a jQuery plugin. All
                jQuery plugins have a standard options map (or object since this is JavaScript) that
                configures the plugin options. This options map is created from the template
                options. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="keyword">Template Options</emphasis>: The generic template options map allows
                    parameters to be added by the template without modifying the class. This can be
                    useful when creating custom templates with options not originally supported by
                    the component. In addition, this allows us to change our plugin implementations
                    more easily. The options for the new plugin can be configured through the XML
                    without having to change the class.</para></tip>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Property Replacers</emphasis> – Another tool provided by the
                UIF for component configuration are property replacers. A property replacer allows
                us to exchange the value for a bean (component) property based on a condition. For
                example, we can change the control for a field from a text control to a checkbox
                control if some condition is true. Or, we might want to change out a complete list
                of container fields with another. In a sense, property replacers give us the
                capability to have if statements in our XML. </para>
            <para>A component may have one or more property replacers defined. In addition, one or
                more property replacers can be configured for the same property. Each property
                replacer whose condition passes will be applied, so the order in which they are
                configured can matter. Property replacers will be covered in Chapter 10. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="keyword">Context</emphasis> – One very powerful feature of the UIF is
                the ability to use EL (Expression Language) statements in XML. The expressions are
                evaluated using the Spring EL framework. Spring EL allows us to define variables
                that can be referenced within the expressions. The UIF provides these variables from
                the component context map. </para>
            <para>Each entry of the context map represents a variable, where the map key is the name
                of the variable (how it will be referenced in the expression), and the map value is
                the value Spring should use for the variable. The framework adds standard variables
                to the context for all components. Some examples include the 'view' and 'component'
                variables. Additional variables are added based on the component. For example,
                components within a collection group receive the variables 'line' and 'index' for
                referring to the current line. Finally, custom variables can be added to the context
                either through the XML configuration for a component, or by code. More information
                on expressions will be covered in Chapter 10. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> Script Event Support </title>
            <para>In addition to implementing the Component interface, ComponentBase implements the
                org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.component.ScriptEventSupport interface. This allows a
                component to specify whether a given jQuery event is supported, and to retrieve or
                set the JavaScript code for that event. For example, let's take the onblur event. If
                a component supports this event, it will implement the getSupportsOnBlur method and
                return true. Script for the onblur event can then be set through the XML by using
                the onBlurScript property. Finally, when rendering the component, the template tag
                will retrieve the onBlurScript and associate with the onblur event. A listing of all
                events and examples will be given in Chapter 11. </para>
        </section>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A UIF Component is anything that can be used to build the application user
                        interface. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>To become a UIF component, a class must implement the interface
                        org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.component.Component. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The component interface defines properties and behaviors all components
                        must provide. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Components can extend org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.component.ComponentBase
                        which provides properties and default implementations for the component
                        interface. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The id property is a unique identifier for the component which can be
                        assigned in the xml with the property tag or by the bean id attribute. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The component id is used as the id for the element that is generated from
                        the component. On the client it can be used for scripting and styling. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The render property specifies whether html output for the component should
                        be generated. When set to false the component template is not invoked.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The render property along with expressions give us the ability to
                        conditionally determine how a page will be displayed. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>For components that allow the user to interact with them, such as form
                        controls, the readOnly property can be set to not allow user interaction.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>By default, the read-only state is inherited by a component from its
                        parent. This allows us to easily set a group of components or the entire
                        page as read-only. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Any component can be styled by using the style and styleClasses
                        properties. The style property allows an inline style to be applied, while
                        the styleClasses allows us to apply one or more css classes to the
                        component. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Component base contains properties for configuring progressive disclosure
                        and component refresh functionality. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Although many things can be accomplished just with xml, code can be used
                        to set the component state by specifying a finalize method to call. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Components can output their html marked directly instead of using a
                        template. This is done by setting the selfRender property to true. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Component modifiers are classes that perform a modification on component
                        state. One or more modifiers can be configured for a component. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>In addition to the properties defined by a component, the template can
                        have options that are passed through using the template options map. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Property replacers can be used to replace the value for a component
                        property based on a condition. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>All components hold a context map which contains variables that can be
                        used for expressions that are evaluated for properties of that component.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Components can indicate that they support a jQuery (JavaScript) event
                        which allows script to be configured for that event. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Types of Components </title>
        <para>Within the UIF component landscape, there are groupings of components which share
            similar properties and behaviors. With each component grouping, the framework provides
            an interface (extending Component) and base class. This allows sharing of properties and
            behavior for components within these groupings. In particular, the base classes are
            important for the view processing, known as the view lifecycle. </para>
        <para>Another way to think of these component types is how we use them to build our web
            page. Recall that each component is rendered to produce HTML markup (including script),
            thus our components are really a model HTML. Therefore, to understand the how the
            component groupings are formed, it is helpful to first breakdown the various HTML tags
            and how they are assembled. </para>
        <section>
            <title>Content Elements </title>
            <para>HTML provides us tags (known as 'elements') we can specify that will be read by
                the browser to render some type of content. Examples of this include: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;a&gt; tag - Defines a hyperlink </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;button&gt; tag - Defines a clickable button </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;h1&gt; to &lt;h6&gt; tag - Defines HTML headings </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;img&gt; tag - Defines an image </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;label&gt; tag - Defines a label for an input element </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>As we see by the tag descriptions, these tags and others like them generate some
                content that is visible to the user. The components that represent these tags (or
                will render these tags) are known as Content Elements. The following is a mapping of
                the above tags to its UIF component: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;a&gt; - ActionLink </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;button&gt; - ActionButton </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;h1&gt; to &lt;h6&gt; - Header </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;img&gt; - Image </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;label&gt; - Label </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Controls </title>
            <para>A special type of content element is one that allows the user to provide data
                input. These elements are known as Form Elements or Controls. Controls are only
                valid within an HTML form which will collect the data and post to a configured
                server location. Controls come in different types that determine how the user can
                provide data. Some HTML control examples are as follows: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;input&gt; - a control that allows the user to input data by typing
                            the value. Several different types of input controls are provided which
                            are configured by using the type attribute. Some available types include
                            'checkbox', 'file', 'hidden', 'image', 'radio', 'submit', and 'text'.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;textarea&gt; - a special type of input that renders a multi-line
                            text input </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;select&gt; - a control that allows the user to select a value from
                            a list of options </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Within the UIF, these types of components are also known as controls. Unlike the
                previous content elements, there is not a one-to-one mapping between the tag and
                control component. Instead, the UIF provides a component for each input type. Some
                examples include: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;input type="text"&gt; - TextControl </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;input type="file"&gt; - FileControl </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;input type="checkbox"&gt; - CheckboxControl </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;textarea&gt; - TextAreaControl </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>&lt;select&gt; - SelectControl </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Controls all implement the org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.control.Control interface,
                which has the base class org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.control.ControlBase. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Fields </title>
            <para>Besides the various content elements HTML provides us, we also can use tags that
                allow us to group content for layout purposes. One such element is the span. The
                span element defines a section of the document and includes one or more content
                elements. Essentially, it is a wrapper for other elements. </para>
            <para>Spans are very important for layout purposes. They give us the ability to put
                together more than one element and have it treated as a 'block' in the layout being
                employed. A good example of this is the pairing of a label and control, where the
                label should appear above the control. If we wanted several of these pairings to
                align in a horizontal row, we would need to resort to a table. Wrapping each pairing
                in a span, however, tells the browser these elements work together and should take
                up one place in the layout. Furthermore, the default display property for span
                elements is inline, so additional spans will align in a horizontal row. </para>
            <para>In the UIF, these span wrappers are known as Fields. There are several different
                Field components provided which have preset content elements, therefore, you don't
                have to do the work of composing a content element with a Field. Some examples
                include: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>InputField – Field that contains a control, information text, and
                            several other elements </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>ActionField – Field that contains an action button or action link
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>LinkField – Field that contains a link </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>In addition to wrapping content elements, the Field component also provides a
                label. This is a label for the span contents, and its placement is configurable. </para>
            <para>All Fields implement the org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.field.Field interface, which has
                the base class org.kuali.rice.krad.uif.field.FieldBase. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Containers </title>
            <para>So far in this section, we learned about the basic HTML content elements and the
                span wrapper. We could write a page with these elements, and the browser would
                render it based on the order of these elements and their styling. However, in many
                cases we want to form larger groupings with their own layouts. For this, HTML
                provides the div element. </para>
            <para>The div element is similar to span in that it wraps elements. However, div
                elements are generally used to divide larger sections of the page and can include
                content elements, along with the span element. The UIF generates the div element
                using the <emphasis role="keyword">Group</emphasis> component. </para>
            <para>The group component is an implementation of a more general type of UIF component
                named <emphasis role="keyword">Container</emphasis>. The main job of container
                components is to hold a configured list of components and render them using a
                layout. A container is divided into three parts: the header, the body, and the
                footer. Generally, these appear in the user interface as show by <xref linkend="KRAD_Container_Parts"/>. </para>
            <figure xml:id="KRAD_Container_Parts">
                <title>KRAD Container Parts</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/KRAD_Container_Parts.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Besides the group component, another type of container is a View. Views do many
                things in the framework that will be discussed throughout this manual, including the
                container duty. A view instance actually contains all other components of an
                interface. That is, a view is at the root of the component tree and is not contained
                within any other component. In addition, the container items we configure for a view
                must be groups (conceptually known as 'Pages'). </para>
            <para>Containers may restrict the types of components they can hold. For example, KRAD
                provides a LinkGroup which is a type of group that only allows link components to be
                configured. Generally, these containers restrict the components they can hold so
                that they can provide more specialized properties and behavior. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="bold">How do groups differ from fields?</emphasis> A field produces a span
                    that wraps content elements, and a group produces a div element that wraps both
                    content and span elements. They seem very similar! The important difference is a
                    field is a preset composition of elements with a preset layout, while the group
                    component and its layout can be configured. It is helpful to think of the field
                    components as our palette to choose from, and the group component as our canvas! </para></tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Widgets </title>
            <para>Today we have the ability to do a lot more in our web applications, beyond using
                the basic HTML elements. With the use of JavaScript and frameworks such as jQuery,
                we can have features such as menus, tabs, trees, and dialogs in our user interface.
                These features are achieved by composing the HTML elements with script. Within the
                UIF, components that generate such content are known as Widgets. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="bold">Widget Templates:</emphasis> Although the majority of delivered widgets
                    use jQuery, a widget template may invoke any script method or make use of other
                    frameworks. </para></tip>
            <para>This is a component type that has a lot of variety. However, the commonality is we
                typically create widgets not by rendering HTML elements and attributes, but instead
                by invoking script. To be more specific, most widget templates invoke a jQuery
                plugin passing in parameters from the templateOptions map. </para>
            <para>We can also think of widgets as client side components. Unlike the other UIF
                components that generate their HTML markup server side, widgets generate content on
                the client during page load. Widgets are explained further in Chapter 8. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Composition and Containers </title>
            <para>Just as HTML elements can be composed, so can the UIF components. These
                compositions can be fixed based on the property type, or variable. For example, the
                LinkField is a fixed composition of a Link component with the Field component:
                <programlisting>public class LinkField extends FieldBase {
    ...
    private Link link;
}   </programlisting></para>
            <para>An example of a variable composition is the Group container with the items list
                that can accept any component:
                <programlisting>public class Group extends ComponentBase { 
    ...
    private List&lt;Component> items;
}</programlisting></para>
            <para>Although it is possible to have any composition of components between the various
                types, there are certain guidelines: </para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Fixed Composition <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>All components can be composed of groups, fields,
                                        elements, and widgets </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Input fields can be composed of controls </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Variable Composition (Container) <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Views are top level components and may not be contained in
                                        other components </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>A View can contain one or more groups </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>A Group can contain one or more groups, one or more
                                        fields, and one or more content elements with the exception
                                        of controls </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Groups and views may NOT contain widgets </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Groups and views may NOT contain controls </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>The below figure depicts the composition of components.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>KRAD Component Hierarchy</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/KRAD_Component_Hierarchy.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The UIF contains groupings of components that have similar properties and
                        behavior </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Each component grouping has an interface and base class </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Content elements are components that generate an html content element
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A control is a special type of element component that allows the user to
                        provide data input </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A field is a component that wraps one or more content elements in a div </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Fields have an associated label </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A container is a component that holds other components and applies a
                        layout </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A container is divided into three parts: header, body, and footer </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A group is a type of container that generates a div and lays out its
                        components using a layout manager </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A view is the top most component and, among many things, holds groups
                        known as pages </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A widget is a component that invokes a script to create the UI elements
                        client side </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Widgets are typically implemented using jQuery </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Components may be composed with components of other types </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>UIF Constants </title>
        <para>Besides the component classes, the UIF contains other services and utility classes
            that are helpful to be aware of. One of these is the UifConstants class. This contains
            constants that are used throughout the UIF. Some of these are constants that represent
            configuration options, while others are used by the code. For those that can be used for
            configuration, the constant can be referenced using an expression and the 'UifConstants'
            variable. For example @{#UifConstants.Placement.LEFT} refers to the LEFT enum value in
            the UifConstants class. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Position</emphasis> – The Position enum has values BOTTOM, LEFT,
            RIGHT, and TOP. This is used to configure where an element should be placed in relation
            to another. One use of this is for the field label. We can choose to put the label to
            the left of the contained field element, on top, to the right, or on the bottom. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Orientation</emphasis> – The Orientation enum has values
            HORIZONTAL and VERTICAL. This is used primarily by the Box layout manager to configure
            whether the elements should be aligned in a horizontal or vertical row. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">View Type</emphasis> – The View Type enum gives the available
            types of view. A View Type (discussed in 13) is a subclass of the View or FormView
            components that provides specialized behavior. The out of the box view types are
            DEFAULT, DOCUMENT, INQUIRY, LOOKUP, MAINTENANCE, and INCIDENT. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Control Type</emphasis> – The Control Type enum gives the
            available controls and is used primarily when creating components through code. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Workflow Action</emphasis> – The Workflow Action enum gives
            available workflow document actions and is used primarily within the Document
            controllers. Values are SAVE, ROUTE, BLANKETAPPROVE, APPROVE, DISAPPROVE, CANCEL, FYI,
            and ACKNOWLEDGE. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Method To Call Names</emphasis> – This is an inner constants
            class that specifies the name of methodToCall parameter values (which map to controller
            names). </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Action Events</emphasis> – This is an inner constants class that
            specifies action event names. Action events are a way of grouping types of actions that
            can then be used for logic or authorization. An example action event is "addLine". </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Id Suffixes</emphasis> – This is an inner constants class that
            declares id suffixes that are used throughout the framework. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">View Phases</emphasis> – This is an inner constants class that
            names the three view phases: INITIALIZE, APPLY_MODEL, and FINALIZE. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">View Status</emphasis> – This is an inner constants class that
            names the three view states: C (CREATED), I (INITIALIZED), and F (FINAL). </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Context Variables Names</emphasis> – This is an inner constants
            class that holds the names for variables that can be used in expressions. These
            variables are listed in Appendix E. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Refresh Caller Types</emphasis> – This is an inner constants
            class that holds names of refresh callers. These can be used in return methods to
            determine what type of view called the refresh. Values are LOOKUP, MULTI_VALUE_LOOKUP,
            and QUESTION. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">EL Placeholder Prefix and Suffix</emphasis> – These constants
            specify the placeholders that indicate an expression in the XML. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="keyword">Binding Prefixes</emphasis> – These constants specify prefixes
            that can be used within expressions for binding paths. Options are covered in Chapter
            10. </para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Other Constant Files</emphasis> - In addition to UifConstants,
            there are the following constant files:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>CssConstants – Constants for CSS strings </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>UifParameters – Constants for request parameter names. Some examples
                        include methodToCall, formKey, viewId, and pageId. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>UifPropertyPaths – Constants for property binding paths. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KRADConstants – General constants for the KRAD module. These constants can
                        be referenced in XML by using the Constants variable. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>UifConstants provides enums and constant classes for configuration and
                        code strings </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>UifParameters contains constants for request parameter names </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KradConstants provides constants for the KRAD module </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>UifConstants can be referenced in XML by using the UifConstants variable
                        (@{#UifConstants.constantname}), likewise KradConstants can be referenced
                        using the Constants variable (@{Constants.constantname}). </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>UIF Bean Files </title>
        <para>As we learned in the UIF overview, each component has at least one base Spring bean
            definition and in many cases has more than one. KRAD ships with several base beans that
            are divided into files for better management and easier browsing. All of these 'base
            bean' files are located in the resource folder (src/main/resources) of the KRAD web
            module. Within the resources folder they are contained in the package
            org.kuali.rice.krad.uif. The below screen shot shows this package in the Intellij
            project pane. </para>
        <figure>
            <title>KRAD Intellij Project Pane</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/kradProjectPane.png"/> 
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Configuration Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions that are related to component configuration.
                That is, the beans don't represent components, but classes that are used to
                configure a component. Some examples include component modifiers, history, binding
                info, and filters. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Control Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for control components. Examples include
                TextControl, CheckboxControl, FileControl, and the SelectControl. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Document Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions that are related to the Document view type.
                This includes the Document View bean, common document group and field beans. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Field Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the various field components. Examples
                include DataField, InputField, ActionField, and ImageField. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Group Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the various group components. Multiple
                bean definitions are provided for the group component that configure different
                layout managers. Examples include VerticalBoxGroup and HorizontalBoxGroup. In
                addition, bean definitions exist for the group level (page, section, and
                sub-section). Finally beans exist for the disclosure option and special types of
                groups like the TreeGroup. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Header Footer Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for header and footer groups. Headers and
                footers are defined for various group levels (page, section, and sub-section), along
                with collection groups. Finally the basic h1 through h6 header components are
                defined. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Incident Report Definitions </title>
            <para> This file contains bean definitions that are related to the incident report view. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> UIF Inquiry Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions that are related to the Inquiry view. This
                includes the Inquiry View bean, and definitions for inquiry groups. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Layout Managers Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the provided layout managers. In addition,
                common layout manager configurations are provided as separate beans. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Lookup Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the Lookup view. This includes the Lookup
                View bean, and definitions for lookup groups. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Maintenance Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the Maintenance view. This includes the
                Maintenance View bean, and definitions for the maintenance groups. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Rice Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for other Rice modules. Examples include the
                KIM person and KIM Group controls. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF View Page Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the various view and page components. This
                includes the default View, Form View, and Page beans. Also included is the
                configuration for the base theme. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>UIF Widget Definitions </title>
            <para>This file contains bean definitions for the various widget components. Examples
                include DatePicker, Lightbox, Breadcrumbs, and Tree. </para>
            <para> Note that a full listing of beans contained in the above files is given in
                Appendix A. </para>
        </section>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para> The UIF provides several bean definitions that are divided into files
                        based on type </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Styling and themes </title>
        <para>KRAD doesn't stop with just rendering the HTML markup, but also provides CSS to make
            your web applications look great! With the 2.0 release, you can choose to use one of two
            look-and–feels (known as <emphasis role="keyword">Themes</emphasis>). Each theme has been
            created with default styling for all the delivered components. However, if you wish to
            change styling or create new components, all the hooks are provided for doing so. This
            section will explore the themes and how custom styling can be added. </para>
        <section>
            <title>View Theme </title>
            <para>See <xref linkend="viewthemes"/></para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Modifying Themes </title>
            <para>Themes can easily be modified on an application basis, view basis, or component
                basis. There are two ways to modify a theme. First, we can create additional style
                sheets and script files that are included with our views. These files may set
                anywhere within the application web directory, or they can be accessed through a
                different web server. To add the additional files, we use the additionalCssFiles and
                additionalScriptFiles properties on the view component:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="MyView" parent="Uif-FormView"> 
    ...
    &lt;property name="additionalCssFiles">
        &lt;list>
            &lt;value>/css/myView.css&lt;value> &lt;value>http://server.com/css/myView.css&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>
    &lt;property name="additionalScriptFiles">
    &lt;list>
        &lt;value>/script/myView.js&lt;/value>
        &lt;value>http://server.com/script/myView.js&lt;/value> 
     &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>
&lt;/bean>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>Using bean inheritance, we can setup a new base view with the additional CSS
                and/or script files that other views inherit. Furthermore, individual views can add
                files as needed. </para>
            <para>Within the additional style sheets, we can override the provided style classes
                (see 'Base Styles and Conventions'), or add new style classes. For example, we might
                want to add a new style class to all input fields, or buttons, or a new component we
                have developed. Once we have defined the style class, we must then associate it with
                a component. We can do this by using the styleClasses property. </para>
            <para>The styleClasses property is provided for all components, and holds a list of
                class names that should be applied for that component. We can configure this
                property using the Spring list tag:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="MyActionButton" parent="Uif-PrimaryActionButton">
    ...
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>customStyleClass&lt;value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>
&lt;/bean>   </programlisting></para>
            <para>Recall that in order to inherit collection configuration from a parent bean, we
                must using the Spring tags and add merge="true". It is recommended that the default
                style classes always be inherited. </para>
            <para>The configured styleClasses are then specified as the class attribute on the
                rendered HTML element:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;button id="MyActionButton" class="uif-primaryActionButton customStyleClass"  ... /&gt;  </programlisting></para>
            <para>Notice the uif-primaryActionButton class. This was inherited from the
                Uif-PrimaryActionButton bean. </para>
            <para>The second way to modify themes is by providing inline styling information. This
                is accomplished by using the style property that is available on all components.
                This property is then used to set the corresponding style attribute on the rendered
                HTML element (known as inline styling). </para>
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean parent="Uif-BoxGroupSection" p:style="border: 1px;"&gt; 
...    </programlisting>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> Base Styles and Conventions </title>
            <para>All of the provided components have a style class configured by default. These
                style classes are configured in the base bean definition(s) for the component.
                Similar to the naming convention employed for the bean ids (starting with 'Uif-'),
                the class names all begin with 'uif-'. After the prefix, the class names closely
                match the bean name (with the exception of casing). As an example let's look at a
                few of the provided action definitions:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-ActionImage" ...
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-actionImage&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>

&lt;bean id="Uif-PrimaryActionButton" ... 
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-primaryActionButton&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>

&lt;bean id="Uif-SecondaryActionButton" ...
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-secondaryActionButton&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>   
    &lt;/property>      

&lt;bean id="Uif-ActionLink" ... 
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-actionLink&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>     </programlisting></para>
            <para>Notice the style class configured for each bean. </para>
            <para>In addition to providing the style class per component, the base beans are also
                setup to inherit classes from the parent (with the merge="true"). A good example of
                this is the stacked collection group section:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-StackedCollectionSection" parent="Uif-StackedCollectionGroup">
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-stackedCollectionSection&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>   </programlisting></para>
            <para>As in the previous examples, we are applying a style class for the component named
                'uif- stackedCollectionSection'. Now, let's walk up the bean hierarchy and look at
                the style classes we are adding:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="Uif-StackedCollectionGroup" parent="Uif-CollectionGroupBase">
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-stackedCollectionGroup&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>
    
&lt;bean id="Uif-CollectionGroupBase" parent="Uif-GroupBase"/>
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;value>uif-collectionGroup&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>

&lt;bean id="Uif-GroupBase">
    &lt;property name="styleClasses">
        &lt;list>
            &lt;value>uif-group&lt;/value>
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>    </programlisting></para>
            <para>So we can see the combined list of style classes applied will be 'uif-group
                uif-collectionGroup uif-stackedCollectionGroup uif-stackedCollectionSection'. This
                gives us a tremendous amount of flexibility for styling, since we have many levels
                at which to define styling. We can configure styling that applies to all groups
                (uif-group), then all collection groups (uif-collectionGroup), then all collection
                groups that have the stacked layout (uif-stackedCollectionGroup) and finally all
                collection groups with stacked layouts that are rendered at the section level
                (uif-stackedCollectionSection). At each level, we can add or modify styling. </para>
            <para>Suppose we had declared the following styles in our CSS file:
                <programlisting>uif-group { 
    padding : 10px;
    margin : 10px;
}

uif-collectionGroup {
    padding : 20px; 
}

uif-stackedCollectionGroup {
    border : 1px;  
}   </programlisting></para>
            <para>The applied styling for the generated element will then have a padding 20px,
                margin 10px, and border 1px. </para>
            <tip><para><emphasis role="bold">Do we need all these style classes?</emphasis> As you have likely
                    determined by now, there are a lot of these bean definitions provided by KRAD,
                    and therefore that means there are many style classes applied. Many of these
                    style classes do not have a corresponding definition within the CSS files.
                    However, they are provided to give greater flexibility for custom CSS. For
                    example, suppose the default theme did not add styling for action link.
                    Therefore, a style class was not declared in the bean. Now a KRAD application
                    wishes to add styling for action links. They would first need to override the
                    bean definition to add the class for the component. Instead with it already
                    being provided, they can just add the declaration in their custom style sheets
                    without any modifications to the application code!</para></tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Fluid Skinning System </title>
            <para>KRAD also comes bundled with the Fluid Skinning System <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.fluidproject.org/">(http://www.fluidproject.org/</link>).
                The skinning system contains a set of CSS files with classes that can be used for
                styling and layout. For example, there are many useful classes for text styling
                (size, color). Any of these may be used by adding the class name in the styleClasses
                property. More information on using Fluid for CSS layouts will be covered in Chapter
                7. </para>
        </section>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A base set of CSS and script files is configured in a view theme object,
                        which is then set on the view component </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KRAD provides two themes in the 2.0 release. One is a legacy theme based
                        on the KNS framework. The second is a new theme based on the KNS open look
                        and feel </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Additional CSS and script files can be added to the view using the
                        additionalCssFiles and additionalScriptFiles properties </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A list of style classes that should be applied are configured on the
                        component using the styleClasses property </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Inline styles can be declared for a component using the style property
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Each UIF base bean has a style class configured by default. Each class
                        name begins with 'UIF-'</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Style classes are inherited by parent bean definitions resulting in
                        multiple applied classes </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The multiple style classes provide flexibility to configure styling at
                        different levels (corresponding to the bean inheritance) </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KRAD includes the fluid skinning system which can be used for additional
                        styling needs and CSS layouts </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Spring Extensions </title>
        <para>KRAD implements a few extensions to the Spring configuration system that allow for
            easier configuration of collections and more flexibility on merging. As we saw in
            Chapter 1, configuring collections requires the use of special Spring tags. These
            additional tags add a lot to the overall verboseness of the XML, and the time spent
            writing it. KRAD helps with this problem by allowing List and Map values to be specified
            as a string using established delimiters. </para>
        <para>For populating a list with a single string value the individual entries are delimited
            using a comma. For example:
            <programlisting>p:listProperty="item1,item2,item3"    </programlisting> or
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="listProperty" value="item1,item2,item3"/&gt;</programlisting>
            is equivalent to:
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="listProperty">
    &lt;list>
        &lt;value>item1&lt;/value>
        &lt;value>item2&lt;/value>
        &lt;value>item3&lt;/value>
    &lt;/list>
&lt;/property>     </programlisting></para>
        <para>As a consequence of using the comma delimiters, list entries that contain a comma may
            not use the shorthand configuration, but must instead using the Spring list tag. </para>
        <para>Maps can also be populated using the shorthand string configuration. Similar to a
            list, each entry is delimited by a comma. For each entry, the key and value parts are
            separated using a colon. For example:
            <programlisting>p:mapProperty="key1:value1,key2:value2,key3:value3"    </programlisting>
            or
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="mapProperty" value="key1:value1,key2:value2,key3:value3" /&gt;     </programlisting>
            is equivalent to:
            <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;property name="mapProperty">
    &lt;map>
        &lt;entry key="key1" value="value1"/>
        &lt;entry key="key2" value="value2"/>
        &lt;entry key="key3" value="value3"/>
    &lt;/map>
&lt;/property>   </programlisting></para>
        <para>If any of the map keys or values contains a comma or colon, we must use the Map tag
            instead of the shorthand configuration. </para>
        <para>When using the shorthand notation, two other limitations should be understood. The
            first is that when this is used on a child bean, any entries specified on a parent bean
            will be overridden. That is, this is like leaving the merge attribute of the collection
            tag, or specifying merge="false". Therefore, when entries need to be merged with the
            parent bean definition, the Spring collection tags must be used. </para>
        <para>The second limitation is with generics (Java 1.5). When populating a collection,
            Spring will read generic information to determine how to convert the configured value.
            For example, suppose we had a List&lt;Integer> property type. Spring will then attempt
            to convert each list value to an Integer type. When using the shorthand string
            configuration, no type conversion on the entries is performed. Therefore, only
            collections of string type are supported (for example List&lt;String> or just List). </para>
        <tip><para><emphasis role="bold">Property Value Type Conversion</emphasis>: The shorthand configuration
                being described here was implemented using a feature of Spring that allows us to
                specify PropertyEditor classes that can be used to convert values configured in the
                XML. A PropertyEditor is a core Java interface that is invoked to convert a value of
                one type to another type. Two property editor implementations were created and
                configured with the bean container. The first converting a String to List, and the
                second converting a String to Map. Property editors are also used to provide
                formatting of values in the UI. This will be discussed in Chapter 6. </para></tip>
        <section>
            <title>Merge Ordering </title>
            <para>When inheriting configuration from a parent bean definition (using the parent
                attribute), we can merge collection entries from the child to parent definition by
                adding merge="true" to the collection tag. Spring performs the merging by adding the
                entries on the child definition to the end of the entries of the parent. For
                example, if our parent bean specifies entries 'item1' and 'item4', then the child
                specifies items 'item3' and 'item5', the resulting collection will have entries with
                the following order: 'item1','item4','item3','item5'. In the majority of cases this
                is fine. However, when the order of items within the collection make a functional
                difference, only being able to merge entries at the end of the collection can be a
                hindrance. </para>
            <para>Within the UIF, many collections do represent a case where the order matters. One
                example is the Group component which has a list of component items and a Layout
                Manager. These items will be rendered on the page based on the order in which they
                appear in the collection. </para>
            <para>Therefore a property named 'order' was added to all components (ComponentBase)
                that can be used to declare where the component should be placed in the collection
                when merging. </para>
            <para>To make use of this functionality, we must first setup the collection items in the
                base bean to have an order value:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="MyPage" parent="Uif-Page">
    ...
    &lt;property name="items">
        &lt;list>
            &lt;bean id="Section1" parent="Uif-GridSection" p:order="100">
            &lt;bean id="Section2" parent="Uif-GridSection" p:order="200">
            &lt;bean id="Section3" parent="Uif-GridSection" p:order="300">
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>
    &lt;property name="itemOrderingSequence" value="101"/>   </programlisting></para>
            <para>Notice a couple of things here. First, the order was specified for each item such
                that there is a range of integers that fall between each (&lt;100, 100-200, 200-300,
                >300). The second is the property value of 101 for itemOrderingSequence. </para>
            <para>Now, let's assume we want to create a page that extends from 'MyPage'. For our
                page, we need to add two sections. However, when these sections are rendered, the
                first section should be between 'Section1' and 'Section2', and our second section
                should be after 'Section3'. This can be done as follows:
                <programlisting linenumbering = "numbered">&lt;bean id="AnotherPage" parent="MyPage">
    ...
    &lt;property name="items">
        &lt;list merge="true">
            &lt;bean id="Section4" parent="Uif-GridSection">
            &lt;bean id="Section5" parent="Uif-GridSection" p:order="320">
        &lt;/list>
    &lt;/property>   </programlisting></para>
            <para>That's it! So what happened? First, we need to understand the rules of merging
                when the order property is given: <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If a component item does not have an order value, it will be assigned
                            a value starting with the specified itemOrderingSequence. This sequence
                            gets incremented by one each time it is used to assign an order value.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The combined collection of items is then sorted by ascending order
                            values. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If an item from the child bean has the same order as an item from the
                            parent bean, it will replace that item. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist></para>
            <para>Applying these rules to our example we see that 'Section4' will get an assigned
                order value or '101', thus it will be placed between 'Section1' and 'Section2' which
                have order values of 100 and 200 respectively. Finally 'Section5' will be placed
                after 'Section3' since it has an order of 320 which is greater than 300. The final
                ordering is 'Section1, Section4, Section2, Section3, Section5'. </para>
        </section>
        <section role="NotInToc">
            <title>Recap</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KRAD provides extensions to spring that allow for easier configuration of
                        collections and more flexibility</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>List and map property values can be specified using a string value </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>For lists, each entry is delimited using a comma </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>For maps, each entry is delimited using a comma, with each key/value pair
                        delimited using a colon </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Shorthand string configuration cannot be used if merging is required
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Shorthand string configuration cannot be used if list or map entry types
                        are non-string </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>For lists of components, the order property can be given to control where
                        in the merged list the component will be placed </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Component items from a parent bean can be overridden with a child item by
                        using the same order value </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
