<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2013 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <info>
        <title>Guide to the OLE System Administration Module</title>
    </info>
    <preface>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para role="Body Text">This guide provides information about using OLE system administration
            functions available via the user interface.  Users with proper authorization are able to
            perform powerful functions that affect the entire system. These functions, which are
            accessible via the <emphasis role="bold">Admin</emphasis> menu tab, allow you to:</para>
        <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Support the Kuali Identity Management (KIM) module and
                    implement security based on accounting line attributes</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Define basic types of location and reference
                    information</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Control the running of batch jobs</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Support the Kuali Enterprise Workflow (KEW) module
                    and</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">Enable authorized users to perform a variety of other
                    functional and technical activities. </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <note>
            <para> Only members of OLE-SYS Manager and KR-SYS Technical Administrator
                roles may initiate most documents in the Admin Menu. Other users may look up values
                from the lookup screens but may not be able to access other options at all.</para>
        </note>
        <para role="Body Text">This guide is organized to follow the layout of the Admin tab. Please
            note that some submenus are not covered in this guide.</para>
        <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
            <listitem>
                <para role="C1H Bullet">System provides access to KIM identy (roles and permissions)
                    and locations, as well as identy management references (maintenance documents
                    associated with KIM identities). </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Location provides access to creating and maintaining locations and location
                    levels for the maintenance of library records.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Batch allows users to upload files used by various OLE batch jobs, run batch
                    jobs and see files generated by those jobs for Financial Processing, General
                    Ledger, and System processes. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Batch Framework submenu allows users to perform a variety of functional and
                    technical activities that process cataloging records in batch. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> Kuali OLE Modules submenu allows you to perform a variety of functional and
                    technical activities that affect the entire system. This includes uploading XML
                    and People Flow rules to modify workflows. Users may also access the Staff
                    Upload interface. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>KRMS Rules provides access to agendas, context, attribution, term and category
                    lookups.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Global Configuration Settings provide access to administering export and
                    global import services.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Configuration provides access to high level configuration options.  Users may
                    modify workflows and parameters for OLE.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Monitoring provides access to the Kuali Service Bus and additional workflow
                    documentation.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>These sections are divided into subsections covering individual functions in the menu
            grouping. For each function, the applicable subsection presents a breadcrumb trail
            showing you how to access the function, information about the layout of and fields on
            the applicable screen(s), and where appropriate, additional information to help you use
            the screen(s).</para>
        <note>
            <para> In order to work efficiently, you need to understand the basics of
                the OLE’s user interface. For information and instructions about logging on and off,
                navigating, understanding the components of screens, and performing basic operations
                in the screens, see the <link
                    xlink:href="../../../webhelp/BASICS/content/go01.html"
                    >OLE Basic Functionality and Key Concepts.</link>
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>This guide as well as guides to other OLE modules are available for download from the
            <link xlink:href="../../../html/Index.html">OLE Documentation Portal</link>.</para>
        <tip>
            <para> Bookmark any page within OLE.  This will allow you to easily navigate back to an
                interface or e-doc in one click, just log in. </para>
        </tip>
    </preface>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/batchFrameworkAdministrativeDocuments.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/monitoringAdministrativeDocuments.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/servicesAndFunctions.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/SystemConfigurationAdministrativeDocuments.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/WorkflowAdministrativeDocuments.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/KRMSRulesAdministrativeDocuments.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/systemAdministrationDocuments.xml"/>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="../admin-guide/systemAdminMaintenanceDocuments.xml"/>
</book>
