<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:lang="en-US"><title>OLE Describe overview</title><para role="No Spacing"><emphasis role="bold">September 2014, Milestone Release
        1.5</emphasis></para><section><title/><section>
            <title> </title>
            <para role="Normal">Cataloging is the term most commonly used in libraries for what OLE
                defines as Describe and Manage activities. Cataloging involves the creation and
                maintenance of various kinds of core metadata that are used to support the business
                activities of the library as well as the library’s OPAC.</para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <para role="Normal">The OLE Describe-Manage module incorporates the creation and
                management of bibliographic, OLE Instance (holdings and item) records as well as
                electronic Instances. Support is confined to MARC 21 but will extend to Dublin Core
                in a later release. Ultimately OLE will be flexible to support multiple formats of
                bibliographic and holdings records along with licenses and authority records.
                Reporting functionality will also be included within OLE but methodology and details
                are yet to be determined.</para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <para role="Normal">Describe-Manage features:</para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">All cataloging activities using widely available web
                        browsers without the need to download a client onto the user’s
                        workstation.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Manually creating and updating bibliographic,
                        holding and item records using a record editor.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Bibliographic and holdings records, in multiple
                        formats. Item records for circulation and inventory control.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Importing batch records from vendors and ingesting
                        single records from external sources such as OCLC.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Up to five levels of hierarchically-related
                        locations (e.g., institution, campus, library, collection, and
                        shelving).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Internal linking to the OLE Select and Acquire and
                        Deliver modules.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">“Staff only” flagging and record ownership (allowing
                        only authorized staff to modify records)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">“Bound-withs” and “analytics”.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Cataloging Record Types</title>
            <para role="Normal"><inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/InstanceDiagram.png" scalefit="1" width="100%"
                            contentdepth="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
            <section>
                <title>Bibliographic records </title>
                <para role="Normal">MARC and Dublin Core are supported but eventually bibliographic
                    records can be in a variety of formats. The MARC Editor has undergone extensive
                    modifications since 0.8; the Dublin Core Editor remains available as a proof of
                    concept. It is anticipated that support for additional or newer formats (such as
                    BIBFRAME) will be added later as required by the OLE member community. OLE is
                    also compliant with Unicode standards.</para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                        xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch01s02.html">bibliographic records</link> and
                        how to create and modify them, see the <link xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/pr01.html"
                                ><emphasis>Guide to the OLE Describe and Manage
                            Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>E-Instances</title>
                <para role="No Spacing">OLE E-Instances (Electronic Instances) store and view data
                    about individual titles that make up an E-Resource purchase. The E-Instance
                    record stores data that is unique to the title level, such as URL, coverage
                    dates, and post-cancellation access dates. The E-Instance also inherits data
                    from its parent E-Resource record. This inherited data can be customized with
                    the E-Instance editor. In future releases, the link to the parent E-Resource
                    will provide a convenient link to the license, trial, access, and purchase
                    information that pertains to the E-Instance.</para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                        xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch01s04.html">E-Instance records</link>
                        and how to create and modify them, see the <link
                            xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to the OLE Describe and
                                Manage Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>OLE Instances</title>
                <para role="No Spacing">OLE Instances serve as containers for Holdings and Item
                    records.</para>
                <section>
                    <title>Holdings records</title>
                    <para role="Normal">OLE Holding Records store information about particular
                        copies, including “base” call numbers and shelving locations. In OLE 1.5,
                        holdings are maintained in a format specific to OLE called “OLE holdings”
                        which also provides the ability to record summary holdings information. In
                        the future, other types of holdings formats (collectively referred to as
                        “source holdings”) will be supported. “OLE holdings” records have a field
                        for summary holdings statements. Thus, some sites may find that they can use
                        “OLE holdings” exclusively without the need to create MARC holdings records.
                        At the present time, it is anticipated that a cataloger would be able to
                        convert an “OLE holdings” record to a MARC holdings record by clicking on a
                        button, but not vice-versa.</para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Item records</title>
                    <para role="Normal">Item records support the traditional functions of
                        circulation and inventory control. Barcode numbers for physical items are
                        recorded here and may be subject to a validation routine according to
                        site-configurable parameters. There is a provision for public and staff
                        notes. </para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">Cataloging Record Features:</para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Full authority control (will be available in
                                a future release).</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Internal linkages to acquisitions and
                                circulation records.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">URL links to external resources from any
                                level of the cataloging record hierarchy (bibliographic, holdings,
                                or item).</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Ability to flag records as “staff only” so
                                that they can be excluded from public indexes but displayed in the
                                library’s discovery layer.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                            xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch01s03.html">Instance
                                records</link> and how to create and modify them, see the <link
                                    xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to the OLE Describe and
                                    Manage Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>OLE Cataloging Record Relationships</title>
            <section>
                <title>Loading/Importing Records</title>
                <para role="Normal">Bibliographic records may enter OLE in a variety of ways:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Batch imports of large number of records
                            simultaneously.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Downloaded individual records from a
                            bibliographic utility such as OCLC (a cataloger may download a number of
                            records into a single file on his or her workstation, and then upload
                            all of the records in the file at once).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Manual creation of individual records using the
                            editor. While this might typically be done by a cataloger, it might also
                            be done by someone in an acquisition unit of by a staff member at a
                            circulation desk. Brief bibliographic records created by circulation
                            staff will be flagged as “fast add” records so they can be reviewed
                            later by catalogers and corrected and upgraded to fuller records if
                            necessary.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Batch imports and single record downloads may overlay existing
                    bibliographic records rather than create new ones. Records to be overlaid can be
                    identified by a number of match points. When downloading a single record, a
                    cataloger may overlay an existing record that he or she has called up on the
                    screen without needing to specify a match point. When bibliographic records are
                    overlaid, certain fields in the original record may be protected from overlay
                    and replacement so that they are retained in the updated record and not
                    lost.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Import Features:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Downloading bibliographic records one at a time
                            from external data sources such as OCLC.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Importing batch files of bibliographic records
                            such as those that might be received from a vendor.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about single record importing, see the <link
                            xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch03s01.html">Import Bibliographic
                            Records</link> section of <link
                            xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to the OLE
                                Describe and Manage Module</emphasis></link>. </para>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                            xlink:href="../webhelp/ADMIN/content/ch01.html">importing batch
                            records</link> (Batch Processes), see the relevant section of <link
                            xlink:href="../webhelp/ADMIN/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to the
                                OLE System Administration Functions</emphasis></link>.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                        xlink:href="../webhelp/CIRC/content/ch02s01.html#_FastAdds">fast adds</link>, see the
                        relevant section of <link xlink:href="../webhelp/CIRC/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to
                                the OLE Deliver Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
                </note>
                <para role="Normal"/>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Editors</title>
            <para role="Style1"/>
            <para role="Normal">OLE stores MARC records in the form of MARCXML. Catalogers add or
                update MARC records using an editor that hides the details of the XML stored behind
                the scenes.</para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <para role="Normal">In OLE, multiple copies of an individual volume shelved in the same
                location can be handled by attaching multiple items to the same holdings record, one
                for each copy. Alternatively, multiple copies in the same location can be handled by
                creating a separate holdings record for each copy. If the different copies are in
                different locations, then separate holdings records <emphasis>must</emphasis> be
                created. </para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <para role="Normal">Editor Features:</para>
            <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Audit trail of changes to bibliographic records
                        (planned for a future release).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Validation of bibliographic data. Initially, OLE
                        will support a “light” validation with limited requirements (e.g. does this
                        MARC record have a 245 field?). Subsequently, an option for full MARC
                        validation is planned for a future release.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">The ability to make global changes to OLE Instance
                        holdings records.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Locally defined status codes (e.g. “Not yet
                        cataloged” or “Cataloged”) for bibliographic records. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <note>
                <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the <link
                    xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch01s02.html">OLE MARC Editor</link>, see the Editor
                    section of <link xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to the OLE
                            Describe and Manage Module</emphasis></link></para>
                <para role="Normal"> To learn more about OLE’s prerelease <link
                    xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch01s01.html">Dublin Core Editor</link>, see
                    the Dublin Core Editor section.</para>
            </note>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <section>
                <title>Bound-withs and Analytics</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE offers flexibility to cater to each library’s needs. With
                    that flexibility includes “bound-withs”, a physical object that contains two or
                    more titles. The requirement of “bound withs” can be satisfied by having one
                    item record linked to a holdings record which is in turn linked to two or more
                    bibliographic records. When a library wishes to have a bibliographic record for
                    a series as well as separate bibliographic records (“analytics”) for the
                    individual titles in the series, this requirement can be met by having one item
                    record linked to two or more holdings records, with each holdings record linked
                    to a different bibliographic record. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about how <link
                        xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch02s02.html">bound-withs</link> function in
                        OLE, see the Bound-Withs section of <link xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/pr01.html"
                                ><emphasis>Guide to the OLE Describe and Manage
                            Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about how <link
                        xlink:href="../webhelp/CG/content/ch02s01.html">analytics</link> function in
                        OLE, see the Analytics section.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Locations</title>
            <para role="Normal">Locations<emphasis role="bold"> </emphasis>in OLE are defined by
                each partner site at the time of implementation. Locations are defined in terms of a
                hierarchy of up to five levels. As delivered, the levels (from broadest to most
                specific) are:</para>
            <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Institution</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Campus</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Library</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Collection</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Shelving location</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <para role="Normal">An OLE site may rename these levels and need not use all of them.
                All locations must be unique. Thus, if an OLE site has two libraries, and each
                library has a “stacks” location, two different stacks locations would have to be
                defined in OLE, one for each library.</para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <para role="Normal">Locations are ordinarily recorded in holdings records, and only one
                location may be used per record. Typically it would be the lowest level in the
                location hierarchy that is known. Higher levels of location may be inferred from the
                level specified in the record because of the hierarchy that has been defined in the
                OLE maintenance documents. The location recorded in a holdings record is the place
                where something is ordinarily shelved or housed. Shelving locations are sometimes
                also recorded in item records; the “item” location is a temporary location for the
                item, such as “Reserve.” </para>
            <note>
                <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                    xlink:href="../webhelp/CIRC/content/ch04s10.html">Locations</link> and <link
                        xlink:href="../webhelp/CIRC/content/ch04s11.html">Location Levels</link>, see
                    the relevant section of <link xlink:href="../webhelp/CIRC/content/pr01.html"><emphasis>Guide to
                            the OLE Deliver Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search Workbench</title>
            <para role="Normal">OLE records are saved in the <emphasis role="bold">Document
                    Store</emphasis> (DocStore). The DocStore can be searched from the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Search Workbench</emphasis> button available at the top of each
                module tab. </para>
            <para/>
            <para role="Body Text"><inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/DescribeNoTitlePage-14.png" scalefit="1"
                            width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
            <para/>
            <para role="Normal">Catalogers may do searches against bibliographic records, holdings
                records, and item records, using the standard Boolean operators AND, OR, and NOT. An
                asterisk may be used as a truncation symbol or as a wildcard within a word. Response
                sets can be sorted by title (A-Z or Z-A), author (A-Z or Z-A), publication date
                (newest to oldest or oldest to newest), or relevance. Response sets can also be
                further limited by facet. </para>
            <para role="Normal">Search Workbench Features:</para>
            <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Quick record search and retrieval via a variety of
                        access points.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Real-time indexing using Apache Solr.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Improved performance with data now stored in an
                        RDBMS.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para role="List Paragraph">Unicode compliance.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para role="Normal">The use of DocStore technology allows OLE to rely exclusively on
                real-time indexing instead of having to defer some or all indexing for large batch
                loads to off-hours processing.</para>
            <para role="Normal"/>
            <note>
                <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the <link
                    xlink:href="../webhelp/BASICS/content/ch02s04.html#_Describe_Workbench">Search Workbench</link>
                    in OLE, see the relevant section in the <link xlink:href="../webhelp/BASICS/content/pr01.html"
                            ><emphasis>Guide to OLE Basic Functionality and Key
                        Concepts</emphasis></link>. </para>
            </note>
            <para role="Normal"/>
        </section></section></article>
