<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
     <title>Introduction to OLE</title>
    <para role="No Spacing"><emphasis role="bold">May 2016, Release 3.0</emphasis></para>
    <para>The user documentation is broken down into 6 chapters and also includes the Technical
        Documentation and the Glossary of Terms</para>
    <note>
        <para>The Technical Documentation continues to be developed.  Works in progress are
            available in <link
                xlink:href="https://drive.google.com/drive/#folders/0B4DWNTr-9s9XZDBkOGNmZDUtZjJkOS00NDNjLTg0MjUtMjllNzhlZmI5YWVi/0B1dW7BM9X5-rNDIzYmE3MTAtMWUzMi00OWFiLWExYzEtZTJkNmVmNjA5N2Yx/0B-Cs4Q8X_DXJc3AxU3FoZC1SYUk"
                >Google Drive</link> (however you will need a KIS account to access this folder -
            see <link
                xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/New+Members+-+Getting+Started+with+OLE"
                >New Members - Getting Started with OLE</link>).</para>
    </note>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Introduction to OLE - This chapter provides links to information about getting
                involved and additional resources. It includes a licensing statement and then
                introduces the 3 modules for functional users: Deliver, Describe and Manage, and
                Select and Acquire. These overviews are brief introductions but provides links to
                the more in-depth user documentation found in following chapters.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>OLE Basic Functionality - This chapter provides information about general OLE
                concepts and gives instructions for performing core functionality. This chapter is
                organized in this manner:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The first section gives information for navigating through the OLE system.
                        This includes OLE's tabs, screen elements, logging on and off the system,
                        and some sample users for the test environment.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>OLE E-Doc Fundamentals provides information about the structure of OLE's
                        e-documents. This includes a description of the standard tabs, such as Notes
                        and Attachments and Route Log, and an explanation of performing basic
                        operations and searches. Search Workbench documentation is included in this
                        section.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>OLE Maintenance Document Fundamentals provides information abou the
                        structure of OLE's maintenance documents. This includes a description of the
                        standard tabs, an explanation of performing basic operations, as well as
                        some fiscal year information and extended attribute notes carried over from
                        KFS.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The next section gives general information about workflows within OLE and
                        explains the Route Log and Action List.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> The final section gives information on importing accounting information
                        for Select and Acquire and provides links to sample data to be used in the
                        test environment.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Deliver Module - The Deliver Module covers the interactions between the library
                and its patrons. The Deliver processes include check in, check out, renew, request,
                hold, manage patron accounts, notices, fines and fees, interlibrary loan and course
                reserves.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Describe Module - The Describe Module strives to achieve two goals: 1) To describe
                the library’s materials so staff and the public can find them and access their
                contents. 2) To manage the library’s physical and electronic inventory so that it is
                accurately represented in the system. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Select and Acquire Module - The Select and Acquire module encompasses selection,
                purchasing, receiving, and payment for all library materials, both print and
                electronic.  Full financial and budgeting structures, batch importing of vendor and
                bibliographic recors, and tools supporting the lifecycle of electronic recourses are
                incorporated in the module.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Administrative Functions - This chapter provides information about using OLE
                system administration functions available via the user interface.  Batch processing
                of records is also included in this section.</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>The Modules (chapters 3 - 6) are organized to follow the layout of their tab, followed by
        the associated maintenance documents (located on the <emphasis role="bold"
            >Maintenance</emphasis> tab). Section titles within the chapters correspond with a
        heading on the associated tab. These sections are divided into subsections covering
        individual functions. For each function, the applicable subsection presents a breadcrumb
        trail showing how to access the function and information on the layout and fields on the
        related screen(s). As appropriate, some subsections include business rules and routing
        information for e-docs and/or special instructions for performing activities.</para>
    <note>
        <para>In order to work efficiently in the system’s tabs and screens, you need to understand
            the basics of the user interface. For information and instructions on logging on and
            off, navigating, understanding the components of screens, and performing basic
            operations in the screens, see <link linkend="OLEBasic">OLE
                Basic Functionality.</link>
        </para>
    </note>
    <tip>
        <para> Bookmark any page within OLE.  This will allow you to easily navigate back to an
            interface or e-doc in one click, just log in. </para>
    </tip>
    <section>
        <title>Test Drive OLE</title>
        <para>Test drive Kuali OLE here: <link xlink:href="http://demo.oleproject.org/portal.jsp"
                >http://demo.oleproject.org/portal.jsp</link></para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Learn More and Get Involved</title>
        <tip>
            <para>If there is anything missing in the documentation, please let us know in <link
                    xlink:href="https://openlibraryenvironment.atlassian.net/projects/OLEFDBK/"
                    >OLEFDBK</link>.</para>
            <para>For instructions on creating an issue, see <link
                xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/Reporting+an+Issue+in+OLE"
                >Reporting an Issue in OLE</link>.</para>
        </tip>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="https://kis.kuali.org/projectTeams/team/190">Technical User
                        Group</link> Allows you to ask technical questions about the software to the
                    community (without membership). Create a KIS account or Login to add or remove
                    yourself from this group.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="https://kis.kuali.org/projectTeams/team/273">Functional User
                        Group</link> Allows you to ask functional questions about the software or
                    project to the community (without membership).  Create a KIS account or Login to
                    add or remove yourself from this group.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Visit the Kuali OLE website <link xlink:href="https://www.kuali.org/ole"
                    >https://www.kuali.org/ole</link></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="http://kualiole.tumblr.com/">Follow our blog</link></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="http://kuali.org/kd/">Attend Kuali Days</link></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/Home">OLE Wiki</link>
                    includes information about the project, developer documentation, and more </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="https://jira.kuali.org/browse/OLE">Track OLE Jira
                    Issues</link></para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <section>
            <title>Additional Resources</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><link xlink:href="http://www.kuali.org/ole/roadmap">OLE
                        Roadmap</link></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><link
                            xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/OLE+Published+Documentation"
                            >OLE Published Documentation wiki page</link></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Release Notes - for each of the current release's notes, see the linked
                        pages on <link
                            xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/OLE+Current+Release+Status+Report"
                            >OLE Current Release Status Report</link>.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Licensing and Intellectual Property</title>
            <section>
                <title>Software</title>
                <para>Kuali software is licensed for use pursuant to theEducational Community
                    License v.2.0. You may obtain a copy of the license <link
                        xlink:href="http://opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php">here</link>.  See the
                    License for the specific language governing permissions and limitations.</para>
                <para>If you have any questions about Kuali Intellectual property, please contact
                    the Kuali Foundation at <link xlink:href="mailto:licensing@kuali.org"
                        >licensing@kuali.org</link>.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Documentation</title>
                <para>Kuali documentation is licensed under a<link
                    xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5">Creative
                    Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.5 License</link>. </para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Module Overviews: Introducing 3 modules</title>
        <section>
            <title>OLE Deliver Overview</title>
            <para role="Normal">This section is intended to provide a basic overview of OLE’s
                circulation features and functions of interest to the circulation librarian. It
                therefore assumes familiarity with commonly used terms or phrases (e.g., “patron”,
                “borrower”, “shelving location”, “recall”, “checkin”, “checkout”, etc.). More
                detailed descriptions of functionality and instructions on using the circulation
                staff interface are provided in the <link linkend="DeliverModule"><emphasis>Deliver
                        Module</emphasis></link>.</para>
            <section>
                <title>Introduction</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE circulation is based on the ability to link patron data to
                    item data in various combinations under various circumstances and conditions.
                    While the combinations are often common to all libraries, circumstances and
                    conditions vary considerably. Therefore, OLE allows each library to select a
                    wide range of options to meet local circulation policy requirements, e.g.,
                    patron-related blocks, item-related blocks, loan periods, notice types and
                    notice frequency, etc. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Like many other library systems, OLE circulation rules are based
                    on the combination of:</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron type (e.g., “undergraduate”, “graduate”,
                            “faculty”, “staff”, etc.)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">An item’s shelving location (e.g., “Main
                            Library”, “Bookstacks”, etc.)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">An item’s item type (e.g., “Book”, “DVD”, “Map”,
                            etc.)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">OLE allows as many patron types, locations, and item types as
                    your institution may need, as well as the creation of infinite circulation
                    rules. Each institution or library could set up ONE policy that applies to all
                    patron types, all item types, and all shelving locations, or they could set up a
                    policy for each unique combination of the three elements. Each institution could
                    also set up a limited number of policies for various groupings of the three
                    elements—this being the option that most libraries will probably follow. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Libraries apply circulation policies by using the Loan, Return,
                    and Request functions.</para>
                <section>
                    <title>Basic Functions</title>
                    <para role="Normal">OLE provides the features/functions that most circulation
                        librarians would consider essential for any modern, up-to-date system. These
                        include (but are not limited to):</para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Patron Records </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Item Records/Fast Adds</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Circulation Desk</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Loans/Renewals </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Returns </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Requests</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Notices and Other Batch Processes</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">“My Account” Features for Patrons</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Patron Records</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE allows for the batch ingest of patron records from external
                    sources with the ability to set overlay rules. Operators can also create and
                    update records manually online. Key patron record data includes (but is not
                    limited to):</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">unique system-generated ID</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">photo image (optional)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">name</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">street address(es)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">email address(es)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">telephone number(s) (texting options available
                            for cell phones in a future release)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">patron type</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">active/expire dates</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">unique barcode</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">data source (to identify external sources)
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">general blocks (for any reason)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">flags to permit delivery, paging or courtesy
                            notice privileges</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">proxies</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">locally defined statistical category,
                            department/institution affiliation, etc.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Multiple addresses include a flag to indicate the preferred
                    address for receiving notices and deliveries. Libraries can by default grant
                    delivery and paging privileges by patron type, but turn these on or off for any
                    individual patron. (See <link linkend="_Requests">Requests</link> for more
                    information on delivery and paging.) Patrons can also elect to NOT receive
                    courtesy notices (e.g., return reminders when items near their due date/time). </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">The patron barcode is the identifier when a patron initiates a
                    circulation transaction. Patron barcodes are unique, can be distinguished from
                    item barcodes, and can be subject to check-digit routines (local option). </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Patron">patron
                            records</link> and how to create and modify them, see that section under
                        the <emphasis>Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Item Records/Fast Adds</title>
                <para role="Normal">Item records in OLE contain the unique barcode which identifies
                    each physical object presented for a circulation transaction. Item barcodes can
                    be distinguished from patron barcodes and can be subject to check-digit routines
                    (local option). </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal"> Item records also contain other circulation-related data such
                    as shelving location, item type, item status, piece count (at Return, a number
                    of pieces &gt; 1 results in a prompt to count the pieces in the item), and
                    checkin note (appears at Return to prompt the operator to follow special
                    directions/procedures for this item). </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Items, along with bibliographic and holdings records, can be
                    searched for from the Deliver Item Search.  Different from the Search Workbench,
                    the Deliver Item Search allows you to search using parameters that are specific
                    to the needs of Circulation staff. </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> For more information about the <link linkend="_Item_Search"
                            >Deliver Item Search</link>, see the section under the <emphasis>Deliver
                            Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">From the Loan screen, operators can quickly create a brief
                    bibliographic and item record for any item presented without a barcode. Such
                    records are flagged as “fast add” and require entry of a checkin note to the
                    item so that upon Return the item can be routed to the appropriate staff for
                    follow-up. </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> For instructions on how to create <link linkend="_FastAdds"
                            >fast adds</link>, see the section under the <emphasis
                            >Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
                <para role="Normal"/>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Circulation Desk</title>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Circulation Desks are the work areas that provide services for
                    items in designated shelving locations. Desks can be established to handle any
                    circulation transactions for any item at any shelving location or be limited to
                    items from designated shelving location. Each shelving location is assigned to a
                    Circulation Desk as its “home”. If so configured, items returned to a Desk other
                    than its “home” will be put into an “in transit” status for routing to its
                    “home”. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Operators are authorized to work at designated Circulation Desks
                    and identify at login the Circulation Desk at which they work (or accept the one
                    assigned by default). Supervisors authorized for multiple Circulation Desks can
                    thus switch back and forth as needed. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Each Circulation Desk has certain parameters, those to highlight
                    are:</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">whether it is a pick-up location (see <link
                                linkend="_Requests">Requests</link> for more information)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">length of time an item stays “on hold” (see
                                <link linkend="_Requests">Requests</link> for more
                            information)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">average time between Return and reshelving (see
                                <link linkend="_ReturnOverview">Return</link> for more information)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">whether it prints circulation slips</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">unique email addresses for patron notice
                            replies</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">OLE requires library staff to establish at least one Circulation
                    Desk but they can establish as many as they need to. </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Circulation_Desk_1"
                            >circulation desks</link>, see the section under the <emphasis
                            role="italic">Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Loan/Renew</title>
                <para role="Normal">An operator can perform check-out and renew transactions from
                    the Loan Interface. A loan transaction is completed with the relevant data
                    displaying for the operator including the due date, etc. if appropriate
                    circulation policies are applied and no blocks exist on either the patron
                    account or item record. Any successful loan transaction also updates the item
                    status in the item record. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">When the system cannot determine an applicable circulation
                    policy, the operator can still loan the item by entering a due date/time
                    manually. Also, authorized operators can change due dates by editing the loan
                    transaction. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">The Loan screen will displays all items previously loaned to the
                    patron with the click of the button "Show All Items Currently Checked Out".
                    Selecting any one of the items currently checked out, permits the operator to
                    perform a renewal (assuming that the circulation policy permits renewals and
                    there are no applicable blocks on the patron or the item). OLE supports the
                    ability of patrons to perform their own renewals. See <link
                        linkend="_-My_Account-_Features">My Account Features for Patrons </link>for
                    more details. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">The Loan screen also allows the operator to mark an item on loan
                    as “claims returned” when the patron believes the item has been returned. A note
                    is included to explain any details.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Loans or renewals can be blocked for a number of reasons. Most
                    of the values that cause blocks are locally defined. A partial list of blocks
                    includes:</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron record has expired </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron record has a general block</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron has the maximum number of items on
                            loan</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron has the maximum number of overdue
                            items</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron has the maximum number of overdue
                            recalled items</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Patron owes an amount in excess of the maximum
                            allowed</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Item cannot be loaned by policy</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Item cannot be renewed by policy</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Item has been renewed the maximum number of
                            times</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Item cannot be loaned at this Circulation
                            Desk</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> For instructions on <link linkend="_Loan">loaning</link>
                        and <link linkend="_Renew">renewing</link>, see the sections under the
                            <emphasis>Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_ReturnOverview"/>Return</title>
                <para role="Normal">An operator initiates a Return transaction by entering the item
                    barcode. Assuming no notifications or exceptions, the system displays details of
                    the returned item and then allows for entry of the next item barcode. Operators
                    can back-date the return due dates/time as needed (often used to process items
                    returned while the library was closed). </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">If an item is visibly damaged, the operator can open the item
                    record from the return screen and record this information.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Returning an item removes the loan transaction (i.e., the link
                    between patron and item is removed) and creates a circulation history record
                    that archives all the necessary data about the loan. An option exists to include
                    or exclude patron-specific data from the history record. Another option is to
                    create a temporary circulation history record for the purpose of allowing
                    patrons to view their previous loans. This record, if it exists, does include
                    patron-specific data; these can be purged by a batch process run on a
                    locally-determined schedule limited to records of a specified age. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Returning an item also updates the item status in the item
                    record. If the Circulation Desk has defined an interval between return and
                    reshelving, the item status becomes “Recently Returned” (or whatever literal is
                    wanted). After the interval, a batch process changes the item status to
                    “Available” (or whatever literal is wanted). </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">During Return, the system also applies any overdue policies that
                    may be in effect, e.g., if fines are charged per day/hour, the Return
                    transaction calculates the amount and creates an overdue fine bill; this is then
                    sent to the patron after running a batch process. See <link
                        linkend="_Notices_and_Other">Notices and Other Batch Processes</link> for
                    more information.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Return also captures any pending request(s) for a returned item
                    and prompts the operator to act accordingly. Check-in notes in an item also
                    appear to the operator at the time of Return. </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> For instructions on <link linkend="_Return"
                            >returning</link> materials, see the section under the <emphasis
                            role="italic">Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the Deliver Module’s Batch Processes,
                        see <link linkend="BatchProcesses">batch processes</link> under the
                            <emphasis>Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
                <para/>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><phrase role="Heading 1 Char"><anchor xml:id="_Requests"
                    />Requests</phrase></title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE allows requests of various types to be placed on items. The
                    request types are:</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Recall/Hold: allows a patron to request an item
                            on loan to another patron, thereby potentially shortening that patron’s
                            loan period; when returned, the item is placed “on hold” at the
                            Circulation Desk (i.e., the “pick-up location”) specified by the
                            requesting patron; an availability notice is sent to the patron.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Recall/Delivery*: allows a patron to request an
                            item on loan to another patron, thereby potentially shortening that
                            patron’s loan period; when returned, item is automatically loaned to the
                            requesting patron, a mailing label is generated, and the item is
                            physically sent to the requesting patron’s preferred street address.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Hold/Hold: allows a patron to request an item on
                            loan to another patron without shortening that patron’s loan period;
                            when returned, item placed “on hold” at the Circulation Desk (i.e., the
                            “pick-up location”) specified by the requesting patron; an availability
                            notice is sent to the patron.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Hold/Delivery*: allows a patron to request an
                            item on loan to another patron without shortening that patron’s loan
                            period; when returned, item is automatically loaned to the requesting
                            patron, a mailing label is generated, and the item is physically sent to
                            the requesting patron’s preferred street address.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Page/Hold*: allows a patron to request that an
                            available item be paged; when retrieved, item is placed “on hold” at the
                            Circulation Desk (i.e., the “pick-up location”) specified by the
                            requesting patron; an availability notice is sent to the patron.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Page/Delivery*: allows a patron to request that
                            an available item be paged; when retrieved, item is automatically loaned
                            to the requesting patron, a mailing label is generated, and the item is
                            physically sent to the requesting patron’s preferred street
                            address.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Copy: allows a patron to request that a print or
                            electronic copy be made of an item (or portion thereof). Copy requests
                            are routed to designated staff for manual fulfillment. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal">*Delivery and/or paging privileges may be set to apply—or
                        not—to all patrons or all patrons of a particular borrower type. These
                        privileges may also be granted on an individual basis (e.g., a physically
                        disabled patron) as desired.</para>
                </note>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">OLE supports the ability of patrons to place their own requests.
                    See <link linkend="_-My_Account-_Features">My Account Features for
                        Patrons</link> for more details. </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> For instructions on <link linkend="_Request">placing
                            requests</link>, see the section under the <emphasis
                            >Deliver Module.</emphasis></para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_Notices_and_Other"/>Notices and Other Batch
                    Processes</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE provides a number of batch processes to generate patron
                    notices, bills, and perform other maintenance functions. Notices and bills can
                    be emailed or printed for mailing. Batch process schedules are locally
                    configurable to support a variety of institutional needs and notices can be
                    customized to fit the needs of each circulation desk.  Batch processes
                    include:</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <orderedlist numeration="arabic" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Overdue notices, due date reminder notices*,
                            expired hold notices*, on hold notices</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Replacement fee bills (for lost items, i.e.,
                            long-overdue items with the maximum number of overdue notices sent) and
                            overdue fine bills (recorded at the time of Return)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Changing “Recently Returned” item status to
                            “Available” after the designated interval for each Circulation
                            Desk</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Purging temporary circulation history
                            records</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Generating a report of on hold items now beyond
                            the expiration date</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <tip>
                    <para role="Normal">*Considered “courtesy” notices, libraries can decide to send
                        these or not. Also, if such are sent, a flag in the patron record can be set
                        so that no courtesy notices are generated for that patron. </para>
                </tip>
                <note>
                <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the Deliver Module’s Batch Processes, see
                            <link linkend="BatchProcesses">batch processes</link> under the
                            <emphasis>Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_-My_Account-_Features"/>“My Account” Features for
                    Patrons</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE has been designed so that certain circulation-related
                    functions can be performed by patrons themselves using a library’s public user
                    interface. This includes login, renewing loaned items, making requests, viewing
                    lists of previously borrowed items, viewing a list of bills, requesting or
                    making address changes, etc. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">In order to offer these functions, a library’s public user
                    interface will need to be properly configured so that it can exchange messages
                    and data with OLE using NCIP (<emphasis>NISO Circulation
                        Interchange Protocol</emphasis>). </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>OLE Describe and Manage overview</title>
            <section>
                <title>Introduction</title>
                <para role="Normal">Cataloging is the term most commonly used in libraries for what
                    OLE defines as Describe and Manage activities. Cataloging involves the creation
                    and maintenance of various kinds of core metadata that are used to support the
                    business activities of the library as well as the library’s OPAC.</para>
                <para role="Normal">The OLE Describe-Manage module incorporates the creation and
                    management of bibliographic, holdings and item records as well as electronic
                    holdings (E-Holdings). Support is confined to MARC 21 but will extend to Dublin
                    Core in a later release. Ultimately OLE will be flexible to support multiple
                    formats of bibliographic and holdings records along with licenses and authority
                    records. Reporting functionality will also be included within OLE but
                    methodology and details are yet to be determined.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Describe-Manage features:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">All cataloging activities using widely available
                            web browsers without the need to download a client onto the user’s
                            workstation.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Manually creating and updating bibliographic,
                            holding and item records using a record editor.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Bibliographic and holdings records, in multiple
                            formats. Item records for circulation and inventory control.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Importing batch records from vendors and
                            ingesting single records from external sources such as OCLC.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Up to five levels of hierarchically-related
                            locations (e.g., institution, campus, library, collection, and
                            shelving).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Internal linking to the OLE Select and Acquire
                            and Deliver modules.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">“Staff only” flagging and record ownership
                            (allowing only authorized staff to modify records).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">“Bound-withs” and “analytics”.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Cataloging Record Types</title>
                <para role="Normal"><inlinemediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/InstanceDiagram.png" scalefit="1"
                                width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </inlinemediaobject></para>
                <section>
                    <title>Bibliographic records </title>
                    <para role="Normal">MARC and Dublin Core are curently supported; eventually
                        bibliographic records can be in a variety of formats. The Dublin Core Editor
                        is only available as a proof of concept. It is anticipated that support for
                        additional or newer formats (such as BIBFRAME) will be added later as
                        required by the OLE member community. OLE is also compliant with Unicode
                        standards.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about bibliographic records and how to
                            create and modify them, see the MARC and Dublin Core information under
                                <link linkend="DescribeCataloging">Create/Edit Titles, Holdings, or
                                Items</link>, available under the <emphasis>Describe
                                and Manage Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>E-Holdings</title>
                    <para role="No Spacing">OLE E-Holdings (Electronic Holdings) store and view data
                        about individual titles that make up an E-Resource purchase. The E-Holdings
                        record stores data that is unique to the title level, such as URL, coverage
                        dates, and post-cancellation access dates. The E-Holdings also inherits data
                        from its parent E-Resource record. This inherited data can be customized
                        with the E-Holdings editor. The link to the parent E-Resource will provide a
                        convenient link to the license, access, and purchase information that
                        pertains to the E-Holdings.  Access to trials will be available in a future
                        release.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_EInstanceEditor"
                                >E-Holdings records</link> and how to create and modify them, see
                            the section under the <emphasis>Describe and Manage
                            Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>OLE Holdings and Item Records</title>
                    <section>
                        <title>Holdings records</title>
                        <para role="Normal">OLE Holding Records store information about particular
                            copies, including “base” call numbers and shelving locations. In OLE
                            3.0, holdings are maintained in a format specific to OLE called “OLE
                            holdings” which also provides the ability to record summary holdings
                            information. In the future, other types of holdings formats
                            (collectively referred to as “source holdings”) will be supported. “OLE
                            holdings” records have a field for summary holdings statements. Thus,
                            some sites may find that they can use “OLE holdings” exclusively without
                            the need to create MARC holdings records. At the present time, it is
                            anticipated that a cataloger would be able to convert an “OLE holdings”
                            record to a MARC holdings record by clicking on a button, but not
                            vice-versa.</para>
                    </section>
                    <section>
                        <title>Item records</title>
                        <para role="Normal">Item records support the traditional functions of
                            circulation and inventory control. Barcode numbers for physical items
                            are recorded here and may be subject to a validation routine according
                            to site-configurable parameters. There is a provision for public and
                            staff notes. </para>
                        <para role="Normal"/>
                        <para role="Normal">Cataloging Record Features:</para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                            <listitem>
                                <para role="List Paragraph">Full authority control (will be
                                    available in a future release).</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para role="List Paragraph">Internal linkages to acquisitions and
                                    circulation records.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para role="List Paragraph">URL links to external resources from any
                                    level of the cataloging record hierarchy (bibliographic,
                                    holdings, or item).</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para role="List Paragraph">Ability to flag records as “staff only”
                                    so that they can be excluded from public indexes but displayed
                                    in the library’s discovery layer.</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <note>
                            <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                                    linkend="_Instance_Editor_1">Holdings and Item records</link>
                                and how to create and modify them, see the section under the
                                    <emphasis role="italic">Describe and Manage
                                Module</emphasis>.</para>
                        </note>
                    </section>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>OLE Cataloging Record Relationships</title>
                <section>
                    <title>Loading/Importing Records</title>
                    <para role="Normal">Bibliographic records may enter OLE in a variety of
                        ways:</para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Batch imports of large number of records
                                simultaneously.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Downloaded individual records from a
                                bibliographic utility such as OCLC (a cataloger may download a
                                number of records into a single file on his or her workstation, and
                                then upload all of the records in the file at once).</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Manual creation of individual records using
                                the editor. While this might typically be done by a cataloger, it
                                might also be done by someone in an acquisition unit of by a staff
                                member at a circulation desk. Brief bibliographic records created by
                                circulation staff will be flagged as “fast add” records so they can
                                be reviewed later by catalogers and corrected and upgraded to fuller
                                records if necessary.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">Batch imports and single record downloads may overlay
                        existing bibliographic records rather than create new ones. Records to be
                        overlaid can be identified by a number of match points. When downloading a
                        single record, a cataloger may overlay an existing record that he or she has
                        called up on the screen without needing to specify a match point. When
                        bibliographic records are overlaid, certain fields in the original record
                        may be protected from overlay and replacement so that they are retained in
                        the updated record and not lost.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">Import Features:</para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Downloading bibliographic records one at a
                                time from external data sources such as OCLC.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Importing batch files of bibliographic
                                records such as those that might be received from a vendor.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about single record importing, see the
                                <link linkend="_Importing_Bibliographic_Records">Import
                                Bibliographic Records</link> section of under the<emphasis
                                role="italic"> Describe and Manage Module</emphasis>. </para>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                                linkend="batchProcessesAdminDocuments">importing batch
                                records</link> (Batch Processes), see the Batch Processes
                            Administrative Documents section of <emphasis
                                >Administrative Functions</emphasis>.</para>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_FastAdds">fast
                                adds</link>, see the section under the <emphasis
                                >Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Editors</title>
                <para role="Style1"/>
                <para role="Normal">OLE stores MARC records in the form of MARCXML. Catalogers add
                    or update MARC records using an editor that hides the details of the XML stored
                    behind the scenes.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">In OLE, multiple copies of an individual volume shelved in the
                    same location can be handled by attaching multiple items to the same holdings
                    record, one for each copy. Alternatively, multiple copies in the same location
                    can be handled by creating a separate holdings record for each copy. If the
                    different copies are in different locations, then separate holdings records
                        <emphasis>must</emphasis> be created. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Editor Features:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Audit trail of changes to bibliographic records
                            (planned for a future release).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Validation of bibliographic data. Initially, OLE
                            will support a “light” validation with limited requirements (e.g. does
                            this MARC record have a 245 field?). Subsequently, an option for full
                            MARC validation is planned for a future release.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">The ability to make global changes to holdings
                            records.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Locally defined status codes (e.g. “Not yet
                            cataloged” or “Cataloged”) for bibliographic records. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Editor">OLE MARC
                            Editor</link> and how to create and modify them, see the section under
                        the <emphasis>Describe and Manage Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about OLE’s prerelease <link
                            linkend="DublinEditor">Dublin Core
                            Editor</link>, see the Dublin Core Editor section.</para>
                </note>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <section>
                    <title>Bound-withs and Analytics</title>
                    <para role="Normal">OLE offers flexibility to cater to each library’s needs.
                        With that flexibility includes “bound-withs”, a physical object that
                        contains two or more titles. The requirement of “bound withs” can be
                        satisfied by having one item record linked to a holdings record which is in
                        turn linked to two or more bibliographic records. When a library wishes to
                        have a bibliographic record for a series as well as separate bibliographic
                        records (“analytics”) for the individual titles in the series, this
                        requirement can be met by having one item record linked to two or more
                        holdings records, with each holdings record linked to a different
                        bibliographic record. </para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about how <link linkend="_Bound_Withs"
                                >bound-withs</link> function in OLE, see the Bound-Withs section of
                            the <emphasis>Describe and Manage
                            Module</emphasis>.</para>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about how <link
                                linkend="_analytics">analytics</link>
                            function in OLE, see the Analytics section.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Locations</title>
                <para role="Normal">Locations in OLE are defined by each partner site at the time of
                    implementation. Locations are defined in terms of a hierarchy of up to five
                    levels. As delivered, the levels (from broadest to most specific) are:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Institution</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Campus</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Library</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Collection</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Shelving location</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">An OLE site may rename these levels and need not use all of
                    them. All locations must be unique. Thus, if an OLE site has two libraries, and
                    each library has a “stacks” location, two different stacks locations would have
                    to be defined in OLE, one for each library.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Locations are ordinarily recorded in holdings records, and only
                    one location may be used per record. Typically it would be the lowest level in
                    the location hierarchy that is known. Higher levels of location may be inferred
                    from the level specified in the record because of the hierarchy that has been
                    defined in the OLE maintenance documents. The location recorded in a holdings
                    record is the place where something is ordinarily shelved or housed. Shelving
                    locations are sometimes also recorded in item records; the “item” location is a
                    temporary location for the item, such as “Reserve.” </para>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Location"
                            >Locations</link> and <link linkend="_Location_Level">Location
                            Levels</link>, see the relevant sections of the <emphasis
                            >Deliver Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Search Workbench</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE records are saved in the <emphasis role="bold">Document
                        Store</emphasis> (DocStore). The DocStore can be searched from the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Search Workbench</emphasis> button available at the top of each
                    module tab. </para>
                <para/>
                <para role="Body Text"><inlinemediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/DescribeNoTitlePage-14.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </inlinemediaobject></para>
                <para/>
                <para role="Normal">Catalogers may do searches against bibliographic records,
                    holdings records, and item records, using the standard Boolean operators AND,
                    OR, and NOT. An asterisk may be used as a truncation symbol or as a wildcard
                    within a word. Response sets can be sorted by title (A-Z or Z-A), author (A-Z or
                    Z-A), publication date (newest to oldest or oldest to newest), or relevance.
                    Response sets can also be further limited by facet. </para>
                <para role="Normal">Search Workbench Features:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Quick record search and retrieval via a variety
                            of access points.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Real-time indexing using Apache Solr.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Improved performance with data now stored in an
                            RDBMS.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Unicode compliance.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para role="Normal">The use of DocStore technology allows OLE to rely exclusively on
                    real-time indexing instead of having to defer some or all indexing for large
                    batch loads to off-hours processing.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the search workbench, see <link
                            linkend="_Describe_Workbench">Search Workbench</link> under <emphasis
                            role="italic">OLE Basic Functionality</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
                <para role="Normal"/>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>OLE Select and Acquire Overview</title>
            <section>
                <title>Introduction</title>
                <para role="Normal">The Select &amp; Acquire module encompasses Financial,
                    Selection, Acquisitions, Receiving, Payment/Invoicing, Licensing, and Electronic
                    Resource Management (ERM), a component that support operational processes for
                    demand-driven acquisitions of library resources. The module manages pre-order
                    and selection of all types of order requests for library materials, and upholds
                    the complete purchasing, receiving and payment operations of ordered library
                    materials. Select &amp; Acquire components also provide workflow design and
                    functionality to encompass print and electronic serials, subscriptions, interval
                    check-in, and productivity reports. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Financial and budgeting structures within the system allow
                    flexibility for library materials to be purchased outright, leased, or licensed.
                    OLE offers fully automated EDI features for direct data exchange with vendors.
                    The ERM component supports the lifecycle of electronic resources and packages
                    including licensing, purchasing, and daily administration. The Global Open
                    Knowledgebase (GOKb), a community-managed knowledge base of subscribed
                    resources, is tightly integrated with OLE for ingesting and maintaining acquired
                    electronic books and serials. </para>
                <section>
                    <title>Overview Diagram</title>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal"><inlinemediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata width="622px" depth="271px"
                                    fileref="../images/OLESelectAcquireMEROverviewForUsersRevised-3.png"
                                />
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">Select and Acquire Features:</para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Re-examines library business
                                operations</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Focuses on digital-based workflows</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Interoperates and integrates with other
                                enterprise and network-based systems</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Ability to ingest bibliographic information
                                from Webform</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Ability to ingest files of bibliographic
                                records and orders</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Financial </title>
                <para role="Normal">In the OLE environment, all acquisitions transactions require
                    fund structures, financial processing, and accurate maintenance of the OLE
                    General Ledger. OLE has adapted Kuali Financial System (KFS) Budget Adjustment
                    documents and Fiscal Year End e-documents to manage budgets. OLE uses the
                    adapted KFS Pre-Disbursement Processor (PDP) to export encumbrances,
                    expenses/invoices, credits, and prepayment requests/disbursement vouchers to
                    university financial systems. In a future release, OLE will be developing an
                    import/incoming financial integration tool that allows the library to receive
                    updates from the university financial office.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Financial Features:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Chart of Accounts/Financial Structures</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Budget Adjustment, Transfers,
                            Pre-Encumbrance</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Accounts: Block, Restrict, SFC, +/-, Fund
                            checks, Access Security</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Fiscal Year Rollover transactions</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Foreign Currency exchange</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Vendor/Publisher record management</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Will communicate with campus financial
                            system</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Load budgets, account structures</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">OLE Attributes of Legacy Fund Codes,
                            Stewardship</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <section>
                    <title>Chart of Accounts</title>
                    <para role="Normal">Acquisitions transactional documents within OLE require a
                        fund to pay for items in the order process. OLE relies on a variety of Chart
                        of Accounts (COA) tables to function. These tables define attributes and
                        values used by the system to validate transactions. They also control the
                        often complex relationships between elements in the Chart of Accounts that
                        must be leveraged for internal and external reporting. For example, tables
                        store basic information such as the sub-fund groups to which new accounts
                        may be assigned and the calendar month that correlates to the first month of
                        your institution's fiscal year. This type of flexibility is one of the
                        features that make OLE a highly configurable application to support
                        Acquisitions.</para>
                    <section>
                        <title>Sufficient Funds Check</title>
                        <para role="Normal">OLE adds over and under tolerances for encumbrances and
                            for expenses. Sufficient funds checking for encumbrances and expenses
                            are formulated differently within OLE. OLE allows sufficient funds check
                            options like KFS (at Object Code, Object Level, Consolidation, Account,
                            Cash), but also allows users to set a block when the fund check equals
                            the set limit, block/notify within a %/$ range of depletion, or allow
                            overages to a $/%.  Sufficient fund checks can occur on Requisitions
                            (REQ), Purchase Orders (PO), Purchase Order Amend (POA), Invoices
                            (PRQS), Payment or Prepayment Requests (PREQ/PPRQ).</para>
                        <para role="Normal"/>
                        <note>
                            <para role="Normal"> To learn more about managing <link
                                    linkend="_StandardCOAEdocs">Chart of Accounts</link> and the
                                associated E-documents, see the Standard COA e-docs section of the
                                    <emphasis>Select and Acquire
                                Module</emphasis>.</para>
                        </note>
                    </section>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>General Ledger</title>
                    <para role="Normal">OLE is adapting the KFS General Ledger (GL) for use in the
                        generation of offsets and the posting of transactions to the balance tables,
                        from various acquisitions transactions. The GL is the official repository
                        for all of OLE financial and budget information. It stores account balance
                        and budget information for multiple fiscal years and stores a detailed
                        record of all financial transactions. Users interact with the GL by creating
                        electronic documents that, when fully approved, are posted to the GL. The
                        OLE General Ledger is a batch processing application that expects all GL
                        pending transactions to be collected in batch form from the GL entry files.
                        The daily batch contains transactions generated in OLE as well as
                        transactions created in external applications and converted to the GL entry
                        format.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the <link
                                linkend="GeneralLedgerIntro">General Ledger</link> and the
                            associated E-documents, see the relevant section of the <emphasis
                                role="italic">Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Financial Processing</title>
                    <para role="Normal">The Financial Processing (FP) component allows users to
                        create and maintain a variety of e-documents (maintenance and
                        transactional), generate reports, and upload data in batch. Many of the
                        financial processing documents are not dependent on other financial
                        processing module documents and independent of other OLE modules. For
                        example, the Disbursement Voucher is for processing payments that are not
                        transacted through the Acquisitions module of OLE. </para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about Financial Processing within OLE,
                            see the <link linkend="_others">Others</link> section of the <emphasis
                                role="italic">Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Selection</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE Selection supports procuring decisions that library
                    collection managers, patrons or acquisitions staff make through acquisitions
                    workflows. In OLE, select functions are often considered Pre-orders, wherein
                    Requisitions become placeholders for future acquisitions review. Requisitions
                    are managed through action lists, and the Order Holding Queue. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Selection Features: </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph"><emphasis>Webform</emphasis> allows patrons to
                            enter a request for an item the library does not own </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Manual requisition allows staff to create an
                            order for an item</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Enhanced Pre-Order selection</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Title search capability (Docstore)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Initiate patron requests and workflows</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Order Holding Queue </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Import Bibliographic records only </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Import slips</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Requisitions"
                            >Requisitions</link> and the <link linkend="_Order_Holding_Queue">Order
                            Holding Queue</link>, see the relevant sections under the <emphasis
                            role="italic">Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                            linkend="batchProcessesAdminDocuments">importing batch records</link>
                        (Batch Processes), see the Batch Processes Administrative Documents section
                        of <emphasis>Administrative Functions</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Acquisitions</title>
                <para role="Normal">The Acquisitions module or purchasing functions encompass all
                    related encumbrance, expense, ordering, receiving, and payment for titles in a
                    variety of formats. Depending on the format, the acquisition of an item may have
                    an associated license/registry that the system is equipped to manage and
                    document as described in <link linkend="_Licensing">OLE Electronic Resource
                        Management Overview- License Requests</link> documentation. Brief
                    bibliographic records are created or edited/linked in the system and an order is
                    created for acquisition. The order is received and paid for upon receipt from
                    the supplier.</para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">The Acquisitions module is used to order, receive and process
                    payments for library materials. Invoices and Credit Memos are sent to the
                    Pre-Disbursement Processing Module (PDP) for disbursement. It includes several
                    e-documents to help libraries manage its acquisitions and accounting processes.
                    OLE users may initiate Requisition e-documents (“Pre-Orders”) to suggest titles
                    for ordering. Fully approved Requisition e-documents are then processed through
                    workflows and become Purchase Orders. Under certain conditions (specified by
                    your library’s business rules in OLE), fully approved Requisitions may become
                    Purchase Orders automatically without any additional processing. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Requisitions"
                            >Requisitions</link> and <link linkend="_Purchase_Order">Purchase
                            Orders</link>, see the relevant sections under the <emphasis
                            role="italic">Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
                <section>
                    <title>Serials Acquisitions</title>
                    <para role="Normal">Serials Acquisitions support the selection and acquisitions
                        of continuing resources. OLE accommodates receipts for the variety of
                        publishing schedules - annual or irregular, numbered or unnumbered,
                        monographic or non-monographic books in series.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">Serials Acquisitions Features:</para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">DocStore supports Bibliographic
                                record,Holdings and Items as well as E-Holdings for electronic
                                materials.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Serials single title order</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Serial bundles, includes print and
                                electronic versions of title</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">View and edit subscriptions</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Action Interval-based receiving
                                record</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Deposits and prepayments</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Claiming reports</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Unpaid subscriptions reports (scheduled for
                                a future release)</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                                linkend="_serialsReceivingTransaction">Serials Receiving</link>, see
                            the relevant section under the OLE <emphasis>Select and
                                Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Receiving</title>
                <para role="Normal">OLE Receiving supports the receiving and cataloging of ordered
                    library materials, as the first step to making library materials available for
                    circulation, following the completion of all required cataloging activities. OLE
                    allows receiving of a quantity and/or parts on line items, as well as offers the
                    ability to report unordered line items, damaged items, or return items. In
                    addition, OLE accepts record annotations such as receiving note(s), and special
                    handling directives. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Receiving Features: </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Receiving Queue - global actions promote
                            receiving across Purchase Orders from a single search interface</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Combined Receiving, Invoicing - interactions
                            prompt auto or manual processing of Invoice while concurrent Line-Item
                            Receiving</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Create additional Item records for each “copy”
                            received </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Initial Requisition, Purchase Orders auto-create
                            single items regardless of quantity during ordering </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Based on the action-interval established for a
                            title, OLE offers an alternative to line item receiving for
                            serials/journals and optional receiving for multi-part monographs
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Receiving staff can update full cataloging
                            records during processing of bibliographic, holdings and item
                            cataloging</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link linkend="_Receiving_-Line_Item"
                            >Monograph Receiving</link> and <link linkend="_Receiving_Queue"
                            >Receiving and Claiming Queue</link>, see the relevant sections under
                        the <emphasis>Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                </note>
                <section>
                    <title>Serials Action Interval-Based Receiving </title>
                    <para role="Normal">Serial subscriptions require repeated receiving of
                        individual issues over time--for purposes of “receiving”, serials are
                        distinct from “receiving” non-serials. The latter are typically “received”
                        by changing a PO line item status and that is all that is required for a
                        receiving process. By contrast, serials are typically “received” by
                        recording receipt of individual issues and--since in most libraries unbound
                        current issues are shelved separate from bound older issues--a distinct type
                        of record is required. The Serial Receiving Record allows for action
                        interval checkin.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about <link
                                linkend="_serialsReceivingTransaction">Serials Receiving</link> and
                            action interval checkin within OLE, see the relevant section under the
                                <emphasis>Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Receiving Business Rules</title>
                    <para role="Normal">OLE can set maximum receiving thresholds ($) to require
                        reception even if the initial order indicates “no Receiving required”.
                        Receiving Requirements for purchase orders can be set at “yes” or “no” on
                        the Requisition indicating whether receiving is required or not for an item.
                        Based on Receiving Required rules, OLE will run checks that display errors
                        if a user attempts to process Invoice/ Payment Request for quantities
                        greater than quantities actually received.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">For items not on the original Purchase Order, users may
                        create Purchase Order Amend (POA) documents. The POA must be processed
                        before an invoice can be approved.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about how <link linkend="_POA">Purchase
                                Order Amend</link> documents currently works in OLE, see the
                            relevant section under the <emphasis>Select and Acquire
                                Module</emphasis>. </para>
                    </note>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Payment/Invoicing</title>
                <para role="Normal">Although OLE technically processes vendor invoices as payment
                    requests, the OLE Invoice document was created to accommodate many-to-one
                    purchase orders to payment requests. This e-document populates payment requests
                    for staff. OLE also processes any negative amounts or credits as separate credit
                    memos. Payments (“paid”) display on purchase order line items. Prorating on
                    Invoices and Payment Requests allows users to take a $500 Shipping &amp;
                    Handling charge (or other types)  and optionally assign accounting lines to it
                    (KFS behavior), or prorate it across line items: manually, by quantity, or by
                    dollar amounts. OLE accommodates advance payments to vendors (deposit accounts),
                    and allow a variety of batch jobs, to ensure accurate information to university
                    financial office. Related document links display on purchase orders and payment
                    requests, linking them, plus Receiving and Requisitions. </para>
                <para role="Normal"/>
                <para role="Normal">Payment/Invoicing Features:</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Payment schedules are indicated on initiating
                            Purchase Order</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Library invoice types and sub-types allow for
                            specialized rules and processing of invoices</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Many-to-one purchase order to invoices</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Prepayments</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Deposit account</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Payments charged to credit card</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Pro-forma Invoicing</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">$0 invoices</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Prorated additional charges</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Payment requests process in US Dollar
                            equivalency</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Payment details from university financial
                            (TBD)</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph">Purchase order payment holds (remove
                            hold)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the <link linkend="_Invoice"
                            >Invoice</link> document within OLE, see the section under the <emphasis
                            role="italic">Select and Acquire Module</emphasis>. </para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Electronic Resource Management (ERM)</title>
                <para role="Normal">Electronic Resource Management covers all aspects of managing
                    titles that are delivered or provided in electronic form. These materials might
                    consist of e-books, e-journals, images, music, video, etc. Many of these
                    resources are continuing serials while others, such as e-books, are one-time
                    purchases. Managing electronic resources is highly complex because they are
                    purchased and billed in many different ways – an institution may be purchasing a
                    single journal title, an aggregated database with 5,000 titles that change
                    throughout the year, or a journal package that contains 500 individual titles as
                    well as several bundles with several titles each. In addition to purchasing
                    workflows comparable to print counterparts, acquiring electronic resources may
                    involve one (or more) trial periods for evaluation and generally requires
                    complex negotiation of license and business terms. The workflow for making
                    electronic resources accessible to patrons is difficult to manage because there
                    is no physical item being tracked through a cataloging process. Electronic
                    resources also require ongoing monitoring and management over their lifecycle to
                    ensure continuous access in addition to workflows for disabling access to a
                    resource no longer being licensed.</para>
                <section>
                    <title>E-Resource Records</title>
                    <para role="Normal">The E-Resource Record provides a place to store and view
                        information about an electronic resource acquisition, including the title(s)
                        involved and the content provider. Within the OLE user interface, the
                        E-Resource Record presents a single, unified view of all information related
                        to acquisition of an individual electronic resource or group of electronic
                        resources, including titles, payment, licensing, administrative, and contact
                        information. There are several general workflows that make up the electronic
                        acquisitions process after a selector or patron requests the purchase of an
                        electronic resource, these will be managed with the E-Resource Record. </para>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the current functionality of <link
                                linkend="_E-Resource">E-Resources</link> within OLE, see the section
                            under the <emphasis>Select and Acquire
                            Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title><anchor xml:id="_Licensing"/>Licensing</title>
                    <para role="Normal">OLE created extensive specifications for the licensing
                        process. Licensing is a variable step in the electronic acquisitions
                        process. Some resources do not require a license at all and can be used
                        within the guidelines of copyright law, while others require extensive
                        negotiation of business and licensing terms. In lieu of a negotiated
                        license, some vendors use standard Shared Electronic Resource Understanding
                        (SERU) agreements to bypass complicated licensing processes. The goal of the
                        licensing specifications is for a license editor that is flexible enough to
                        encode the rights for a variety of scenarios making them easy to query,
                        rather than recording the terms only for fully negotiated licenses. License
                        Request e-documents, used to manage negotiations, are available in
                        OLE.</para>
                    <para role="Normal"/>
                    <para role="Normal">Licensing Process in OLE:</para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Request a standard license from a publisher
                                for a resource</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Assign the license to a “shepherd” or
                                license owner</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Compare the license with standard
                                requirements established by the institution and/or library</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Back and forth negotiation with the
                                publisher and library administration to modify license language if
                                necessary</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">If approval, final signatures from both
                                parties recorded</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Storage of final license document (generally
                                a PDF) in OLE</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para role="List Paragraph">Coding machine-readable interpretation of
                                license terms in OLE via a license editor (will be stored as ONIX-PL
                                in the DocStore) will be available in a future release.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <note>
                        <para role="Normal"> To learn more about the current functionality of <link
                                linkend="_Standard_Licensing_E-Docs">Licensing</link> within OLE,
                            see the relevant section under the <emphasis>Select and
                                Acquire Module</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
