<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    version="5.0" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title>Kuali Open Library Environment, 1.5 Release Notes</title>
    <warning>
        <para>This is a draft.</para>
    </warning>
    <para dir="ltr" xml:id="docs-internal-guid-3cdd8b3b-216f-a785-100e-81b8f558a834">Kuali Open
        Library Environment (OLE) 1.5 is the first release that will be implemented by several OLE
        partners. OLE is delivered with demo and bootstrap data. A switch has been provided that
        allows an option to load bootstrap, bootstrap and demo, or neither dataset. Data migration
        plans and best practices continue to be documented, and an additional loader for Serials
        Receiving records has been created. </para>
    <para dir="ltr">A key change in OLE is searching and browsing for records. The previous Describe
        Workbench and DocStore Search have been replaced by a single Search Workbench interface
        which allows searching of Bibliographic, Holdings, Item, E-Holdings, and Licenses or
        browsing by call numbers and titles. This new search will allow library staff to utilize
        customizable facets along with standard Boolean searching.</para>
    <para dir="ltr">OLE includes four core modules: Select and Acquire, Describe and Manage,
        Deliver, and System Integration. </para>
    <para> </para>
    <para> Select and Acquire Modules includes: </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Claiming functionality has been added to the module. While in 1.0 users could
                receive items from the Receiving Queue, the interface has been adapted to become the
                Receiving and Claiming Queue. If a particular order should never be claimed, the
                titles are marked from the Requisition or Purchase Order. Claim notices can be
                accessed easily from the Select/Acquire tab.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Donor information may now be tracked and several reports on donor funds are
                system-generated in OLE.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Additional modifications have been made to the Disbursement Voucher to allow for
                deposit accounts. The initial payment is made from the Disbursement Voucher, and
                then Purchase Orders and Invoices can be created to track item purchases.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The Invoice document has been enhanced to perform duplication checks, $0 invoices,
                and as an added convenience to users, cloning is available.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Imported records with order data in the 9xx fields are now mapped to purchase
                orders. Import profiles have also been established to allow the ingestion of
                electronic holdings.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Describe and Manange Module includes:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Global changes to Holdings, Items, and E-Holdings is a new feature available in
                1.5 that allows users to apply changes to multiple records at one time.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Analytics are also new for 1.5. The purpose of the feature is to allow a user of a
                library's discovery layer to determine the status (loaned, missing, etc.) of an item
                in a monographic series regardless of whether the user finds the item in the catalog
                via the bibliographic record for the series or the bibliographic record for an
                individual title in the series. Bound-withs have been available since the 0.8
                release.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Clickable URLs have been added to OLE’s editors. Any URL on the bibliographic,
                holdings, or item record is now hyperlinked.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Several new MARC bibliographic record functionality improvements were added such
                as field-level validation and an improved user interface.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>Deliver Module includes:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>OLE has improved printing of routing and hold slips and included functionality to
                print call slips.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Claim returns can be viewed, created and updated not only from the loan screen but
                also the patron and item records. Missing pieces and damaged items functionality
                have been modified to continue to allow items to be circulated if libraries so
                choose. Missing pieces and damaged items notes can also be viewed from the patron
                and item records, not only the loan screen.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Item records now display the patron that has borrowed the item.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Additional operator warnings have been created for circulating materials still
                checked out, overdue, or lost. New blocks prevent staff from renewing an item that
                precedes the existing due date.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>System Integration includes:</para>
    <para>During the 1.5 development, OLE underwent significant structural changes. </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Due to performance and scalability concerns with Jackrabbit, OLE now incorporates
                a relational database management system. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The DocStore schema was refactored and the Instance wrapper has been removed from
                Holdings and Item records. (Labels remain in the interface but these will be removed
                in a future release).</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>OLE saw several software upgrades: Rice to 2.3.2, MySQL to 5.6.12, and Tomcat to
                7. Progress to make OLE a unified environment has been completed. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Significant user interface changes have impacted OLE. The portal has been
                reorganized to correspond with library needs.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>OLE now provides an API to interact with automated storage retrieval systems. In
                1.5, the ASR system interacting with OLE is Dematic. Additionally, an API was
                created to interact with NCIP for resource-sharing systems (ILL, self-service
                kiosks, consortial borrowing).</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section>
        <title>Known Bugs and Issues</title>
        <para> Known issues to be addressed in OLE 2.0 include: </para>
        <para>Initial import of records continues to need improvement and documentation. It has been
            noted that OLE needs a standard format separate from the underlying data structure to
            more easily load the records. Currently doing an initial load of records and documents
            into OLE requires library financial data to be structured in a very particular way and
            only with .csv files.</para>
        <para>While OLE strives to be compatible with standard browsers, “support” implies that best
            efforts will be made to ensure that data loss or unusably corrupted displays do not
            occur with a plugin and extension free instance of the browser software. There have been
            a few issues with plugins brought to our attention during 1.5 development.</para>
        <para>Updating Persons in KIM will cause an exception. This is a known issue for Rice 2.3.6,
            the Rice version that OLE 1.5 is packaged with. A fix was added in Rice 2.4, which will
            be available in OLE 2.0. For the work around suggestion, see OLE-5972.</para>
        <para> Additional issues can be found in Jira: <link
                xlink:href="https://jira.kuali.org/browse/OLE"
                >https://jira.kuali.org/browse/OLE</link>. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>OLE Technical Notes</title>
        <para>All technical installation notes for Kuali OLE Release 1.5 can be found on the public
            documentation site at <link
                xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/OLE+Technical+Documentation">OLE
                Technical Documentation</link>.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>OLE User Documentation and Links to Test Drive</title>
        <para>See the <link xlink:href="../html/Index.html">OLE Documentation Portal</link> to read
            throug the Overviews and Manuals, and learn more about the 1.0 release.</para>
        <para>Test drive OLE from Kuali.org: <link xlink:href="http://www.kuali.org/test-drives"
                >http://www.kuali.org/test-drives</link>.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Glossary</title>
            <para>The <link xlink:href="../webhelp/BASICS/content/go01.html">OLE glossary</link> is
                available through the wiki.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Future Releases</title>
        <para>The Kuali Open Library Environment project team is planning another release, OLE 2.0,
            for the final quarter of 2014. </para>
        <para>OLE 2.0 will be focused on new electronic resource management (ERM) development, which
            will include subscription and organization information management, GOKb imports, a new
            platform record, and linking E-Resources to Purchase Orders and other E-Resources. In
            addition to ERM, 2.0 will include fiscal year rollover basic functionality, upgrade to
            Solr 4, a major Rice upgrade that includes a conversion from the Kuali Nervous System
            (KNS) framework to the Kuali Rapid Application Development (KRAD) framework that
            modernizes the KFS-inherited screens, and additional initial bulk load procedures for
            data migration (see OLE-6672).</para>
        <para> See our timeline (<link xlink:href="http://www.kuali.org/ole/roadmap"
                >http://www.kuali.org/ole/roadmap</link>) for a big picture of the 2.0 release, as
            well as what has been developed in the current and past releases. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>OLE Acknowledgements</title>
        <para><link
                xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/Licenses+and+Acknowledgements+for+OLE+1.5"
                >https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/Licenses+and+Acknowledgements+for+OLE+1.5</link></para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Contact Us</title>
        <para>If you have technical questions, please contact our collaboration community at <link
                xlink:href="mailto:ole.technical.usergroup@kuali.org"
                >ole.technical.usergroup@kuali.org</link>.</para>
        <para>For functional questions, please contact our collaboration community at <link
                xlink:href="mailto:ole.functional.usergroup@kuali.org"
                >ole.functional.usergroup@kuali.org</link>.</para>
    </section>
</article>
