<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    version="5.0" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title><anchor xml:id="LicensingOverview"/>Licensing Overview<indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>Overview</primary>
        </indexterm></title>
    <para role="Body Text">The Licensing process in OLE includes a back and forth negotiating
        process between the licensing institution and the electronic resource vendor to set the
        final terms of the license contract. This is intended to be completed whenever appropriate
        during the electronic resource acquisition process. OLE will store notes, data and attached
        documents from this licensing period in an electronic document, or e-doc, called a License
        Request. </para>
    <para role="Body Text">Licensing workflows are a variable part of the electronic acquisitions
        process. Some resources do not require a license at all and can be used within the
        guidelines of copyright law, while others require extensive negotiation of business and
        licensing terms. In general, the licensing process consists of:</para>
    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">Requesting a standard license from a publisher for a
                resource</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">Assigning the license to a “shepherd” or license
                owner</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">Comparing the license with standard requirements established
                by the institution and/or library</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">Back and forth negotiation with the publisher / library
                administration to modify license language if necessary.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">If approval, final signatures from both parties.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">Storing final license document (generally a PDF) in
                OLE.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="List Paragraph">Coding machine-readable interpretation of license terms in
                OLE via a license editor (will be stored as ONIX-PL in the Doctor). Note that this
                final step is planned for a future release.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para role="Body Text">The documents and workflows in the Licensing sub-module will allow
        authorized users to gather information on available terms, store reference materials from
        providers, track and record external communications or “events,” and trace internal reviews,
        approvals, and signatures/signed agreements.</para>
    <note>
        <para> In order to work efficiently in the system’s Licensing screens, you need to
            understand the basics of the user interface. For information and instructions on logging
            on and off, navigating, understanding the components of screens, and performing basic
            operations in the screens, see the <link xlink:href="../../../webhelp/BASICS/content/pr01.html">OLE Basic
                Functionality and Key Concepts.</link></para>
    </note>
    <para role="Body Text"/>
    <section>
        <title>Licensing e-documents</title>
        <para role="Normal">OLE Licensing utilizes e-documents and XML documents to store
            information about the Licensing process and all internal and external negotiations and
            communications. Initial OLE licensing will utilize:</para>
        <para role="Normal"/>
        <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
            <listitem>
                <para role="List Paragraph">E-Resource Record to <link
                        linkend="_Initiate_License_Workflow">initiate licensing workflows</link> by
                    auto-creating the License Request when requested.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="List Paragraph"><link linkend="_License_Request">License Request</link>
                    e-doc captures critical information and communication that takes place during
                    vendor negotiations. It is used to create an institutional workflow for the
                    license negotiation process.</para>
                <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
                    <listitem>
                        <para role="List Paragraph"><link linkend="_Agreement_Documents_Tab"
                                >Agreement Documents</link> (title lists, sample contracts, signed
                            license, etc.) are external files that can be attached to License
                            Requests </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="List Paragraph">ONIX-PL <link linkend="_Agreement">Agreement</link> is
                    used to record the interpreted terms of the license in a machine-readable
                    format. Note that the Agreement is not available in the interface in 1.5, but
                    the underlying infrastructure to import and store these documents has been
                    created.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para role="List Paragraph">Maintenance Documents &amp; Code Lists</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para role="Normal">A License Request might be initiated for acquisitions of new titles,
            renewals of existing titles, or making changes to previous Agreements (amendments). OLE
            1.5 provides for a License Request generated from an E-Resource Record as part of the
            acquisitions process. Future releases may address licensing for Addendums, Renewals, and
            Trials in more detail.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
