<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0"
    xml:lang="en-US">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para role="Body Text">The Purchasing and Accounts Payable module allows users to request materials,
        generate and transmit purchase orders, and process invoices and credit memos received from vendors.
        The requisition, purchase order, payment request, purchase order amendment, and credit memo
        documents use the workflow Kuali Enterprise Workflow component for document approval followed by
        encumbrance, expense and liability entries in the General Ledger as required.</para>
    <note>
        <para> To learn more about the Select and Acquire Module, see the <emphasis>Select
            and Acquire Overview</emphasis>.</para>
    </note>
    <para role="Body Text">This guide provides information about using Purchasing and Accounts Payable
        functions. It is organized as follows.</para>
    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
        <listitem>
            <para role="C1H Bullet">The first section provides an overview of key Purchasing and Accounts
                Payable batch processes.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="C1H Bullet">The next section, Standard Transaction E-Docs, summarizes the options
                available to users and indicates how they are grouped on the OLE menus. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="C1H Bullet">Each of the remaining sections presents background information and
                instructions specific to a group of functions on the menu. </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para role="C1H Bullet">These sections are divided into subsections covering individual functions.
        For each function, the applicable subsection presents a breadcrumb trail showing how to access the
        function and information on the layout and fields on the related screen(s). As appropriate, some
        subsections include business rules and routing information for e-docs and/or special instructions
        for performing activities.</para>
    <note>
        <para role="Note"> In order to work efficiently in the system’s Purchasing and Accounts
            Payable screens, you need to understand the basics of the user interface. For
            information and instructions on logging on and off, navigating, understanding the
            components of screens, and performing basic operations in the screens, see the <link
                xlink:href="../../../webhelp/BASICS/content/pr01.html">OLE Basic Functionality and Key Concepts.</link></para>
        <para role="Note"> This guide as well as guides to other OLE modules are available for
            download from the <link xlink:href="../../../html/Index.html">OLE Documentation
            Portal</link>.</para>
        <para role="Note"/>
    </note>
</chapter>
