<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<glossary xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    version="5.0">
    <title>OLE Glossary of Terms</title>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Numerical Terms</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="thirdParty">
            <glossterm>3rd Party Component</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a reusable service, not developed or supplied by OLE that fulfils an OLE
                    library business process.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>A</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="AACRTWO">
            <glossterm>AACR2</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>AACR2 stands for Anglo-American Cataloguing Rules, Second Edition. Principles
                    of AACR include cataloging from the "item 'in hand" rather than inferring
                    information from external sources and using the "item in hand" as the preferred
                    source of information when conflicts exist. To be superseded by RDA.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="acceptanceCriteria">
            <glossterm>Acceptance Criteria</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>What are the conditions of satisfaction for this user story? Acceptance
                    criteria can be phrased in the form of a question and answer for the testers to
                    use as a test-script to see if the designed system satisfactorily completes the
                    actions specified in the User Story.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="acceptanceTesting">
            <glossterm>Acceptance Testing, UAT</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Acceptance Testing or User Acceptance Testing - Tests that can be applied to
                    determine successful outcome of a process, such as User Story or
                    Workflow.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="account">
            <glossterm>Account</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Identifies a pool of funds assigned to a specific university organizational
                    entity for a specific purpose. Global document functionality is available for
                    this document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="acquireEntity">
            <glossterm>Acquire Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE component whereby an entity is selected, obtained and the
                    license/registry terms associated with the entity are documented; the entity is
                    described and added to the collection.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="acquisitions">
            <glossterm>Acquisitions</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The functions, policies and processes by which a library purchases or licenses
                    materials for its collections; manages the the budget for this function; and
                    identifies purchases made with endowed funds.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="action">
            <glossterm>Action</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, an action is the event that is triggered within a rule when the terms
                    of the proposition are met..</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="rule">Rule</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="proposition">Proposition</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="actionList">
            <glossterm>Action List</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A list of the user's notification and workflow items. Also called the user's
                    Notification List. Clicking an item in the Action List displays details about
                    that notification, if the item is a notification, or displays that document, if
                    it is a workflow item. The user will usually load the document from their Action
                    List in order to take the requested action against it, such as approving or
                    acknowledging the document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="actionRequest">
            <glossterm>Action Request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A request to a user or Workgroup to take action on a document. It designates
                    the type of action that is requested, which includes:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approve: requests an approve or disapprove action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Complete: requests a completion of the contents of a document. This
                            action request is displayed in the Action List after the user saves an
                            incomplete document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Acknowledge: requests an acknowledgment by the user that the document
                            has been opened - the doc will not leave the Action List until
                            acknowledgment has occurred; however, the document routing will not be
                            held up and the document will be permitted to transaction into the
                            processed state if neccessary.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>FYI: a notification to the user regarding the document. Documents
                            requesting FYI can be cleared directly from the Action List. Even if a
                            document has FYI requests remaining, it will still be permitted to
                            transition into the FINAL state.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="activeDirectory">
            <glossterm>Active Directory</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authentication: Directory service created by Microsoft and relies on standards
                    of LDAP</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="activeIndicator">
            <glossterm>Active Indicator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An indicator specifying whether an object in the system is active or not. Used
                    as an alternative to complete removal of an object.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="address">
            <glossterm>Address</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An address is a way to contact a patron. Addresses have dates to indicate when
                    they can be used and types to indicate what they are used for. A subset of the
                    patron's addresses are primary. Primary addresses are used to contact the
                    patron.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="adHocRouting">
            <glossterm>Ad hoc Routing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of routing used to route a document to users or groups that are not in
                    the Routing path for that Document Type. When the Ad Hoc Routing is complete,
                    the routing returns to its normal path.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="administrativeSite">
            <glossterm>Admininstrative site</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A web interface for librarians to manage various elements of the look and feel
                    of a platform for their users. Data entered here include ip addresses, library
                    contact information, library logos, and links to the library's catalog and help
                    service, and sometimes the ability to customize site searching and results
                    sorting, among other administrativa. There may be a separate site for retrieving
                    usage statistics or usage statistics may be available from the administrative
                    site.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="affiliation">
            <glossterm>Affiliation (patron)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Patron groups defined by a library, e.g., "History Dept.","Research
                    Institute", etc. used primarily for statistical purposes.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="agenda">
            <glossterm>Agenda</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, the agenda is a plan for the execution of rules.  Agendas can be set
                    as a decision tree or as a sequential list.  Agendas are contained within a
                    Context.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="rule">Rule</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="context">Context</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="agent">
            <glossterm>Agent</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Any individual or organization entity that is represented in Kuali OLE. An
                    agent could be an institution, a staff member, a library consortia, a publisher,
                    a provider, or an individual working for a publisher / vendor.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="agreement">
            <glossterm>Agreement</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An agreement or understanding between the library / institution and a
                    publisher / provider / donor regarding access to content. May include
                    descriptive metadata, such as start date, end date, and contract number, as well
                    as information about rights, restrictions, and business terms. An agreement will
                    often represent either a negotiated license or a SERU agreement, although it
                    could conceivably also represent other types of agreements, such as restrictions
                    surrounding use of digital materials deposited in an institutional repository,
                    use of donations made to a special collections unit, or use of gifts to the
                    institution.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="agreementDocument">
            <glossterm>Agreement Document</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A file associated with an Agreement in OLE. Many types of files are utilized
                    in the negotiation process / provide further details about an Agreement,
                    including a variety of word processing files, spreadsheet files, and
                    pdfs.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="AJAX">
            <glossterm>AJAX</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>AJAX, short for Asynchronous JAvascript + XML, is a group of interrelated Web
                    development techniques used on the client-side to create asynchronous web
                    applications. With AJAX, web applications can send data to, and retrieve data
                    from, a server asynchronously (in the background) without interfering with the
                    display and behavior of the existing page.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="allocations">
            <glossterm>Allocations</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is the primary area in which the ILS accounting is more granular and
                    specific than at the parent organization level. A university will commonly
                    budget operating funds for library acquisitions in one lump sum. The library
                    then commonly subdivides that money into smaller chunks, according to the
                    perceived needs of its users. The most common ways to subdivide the collection
                    budget are: by school or administrative unit -- $x for the School of Medicine,
                    for instance, $X for the School of Arts and Sciences, $X for the Business
                    School, etc.; by subject -- with the library deciding how many subject funds to
                    subdivide the money into; by material type -- dividing the budget among
                    monographs, print serials, e-serials, other e-resources, rare material, etc.; or
                    by combinations of these categories.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ALA">
            <glossterm>American Library Association (ALA)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>“The object of the American Library Association shall be to promote library
                    service and librarianship.” The stated mission is, “To provide leadership for
                    the development, promotion, and improvement of library and information services
                    and the profession of librarianship in order to enhance learning and ensure
                    access to information for all.”</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="analytic">
            <glossterm>Analytic</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A bibliographic record for an individual work in a monographic series.
                    Alternatively, a bibliographic record for an article in a journal or newspaper,
                    or for a chapter in a book. Analytics for monographic series are common in
                    libraries. Analytics for journal articles or book chapters are much less common.
                    Sometimes called "analytic entry".</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="analyticHoldingRecord">
            <glossterm>Analytic Holding Record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A holdings record for an individual work in a monographic series
                    (distinguished from a holdings record for the entire series.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="seriesHoldingRecord">Series holdings record</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="analyzedSeries">
            <glossterm>Analyzed series</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A group of titles on related topics issued over time in which each individual
                    work can be identified by two titles: the series title and the title of the
                    individual work (as a volume of the seris title). The series title has its own
                    bib record and each individual title has its own bib record as well, with the
                    two sharing item-level data.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="apacheLucene">
            <glossterm>Apache Lucene</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Apache Lucene(TM) is a high-performance, full-featured text search engine
                    library written entirely in Java. It is a technology suitable for nearly any
                    application that requires full-text search, especially cross-platform.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="approvalOrder">
            <glossterm>Approval order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A library's tentative commitment to purchase a title.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="approvalPlan">Approval Plan</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="approvalPlan">
            <glossterm>Approval Plan</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An arrangement between a supplier (e.g., a "book jobber") and a library
                    whereby the supplier automatically ships materials of certain kinds, of certain
                    types, on certain subjects, etc. as profiled by the library; when received, the
                    library has the option of keeping (and paying) or rejecting (and returning) any
                    individual title. Approval plan shipments are often accompanied by a file of
                    records from the supplier that include the bib, item/holdings, order and/or
                    invoice data for the titles; this data is loaded into a library's system using a
                    locally-defined import profile.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="approve">
            <glossterm>Approve</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of workflow action button. Signifies that the document represents a
                    valid business transaction in accordance with institutional needs and policies
                    in the user's judgment. A single document may require approval from several
                    users, at multiple route levels, before it moves to final status.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="API">
            <glossterm>API</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An Application Programming Interface (API) specifies a software component in
                    terms of its operation, their inputs and outputs and underlying types. Its main
                    purpose is to define a set of functionalities that are independent of their
                    respective implementation, allowing both definition and implementation to vary
                    without compromising each other.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="aquaBrowser">
            <glossterm>AquaBrowser</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The AquaBrowser® discovery layer provides a fresh, modern interface for
                    patrons of varied backgrounds to use independently. By providing a simple
                    interface with a single search box, patrons are able to quickly find relevant
                    results when they need them. A fully hosted, subscription-based solution,
                    AquaBrowser 3 significantly enhances service quality with minimal impact on a
                    library's resources</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="archive">
            <glossterm>Archive</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>governed by specific archival management policies, the process by which an
                    entity or the copy of one can be stored or transferred to data storage.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="associationCollege">
            <glossterm>Association College Research Libraries (ACRL)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Association of College and Research Libraries (ACRL), a division of the
                    American Library Association, is a professional association of academic
                    librarians and other interested individuals. It is dedicated to enhancing the
                    ability of academic library and information professionals to serve the
                    information needs of the higher education community and to improve learning,
                    teaching, and research.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="authenticate">
            <glossterm>Authenticate</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process by which a system verifies the identity of a user. The user may be a
                    person using a computer, a computer itself, or a computer program.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="authority">
            <glossterm>Authority</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authority records provide the authoritative display, listing, and indexing for
                    Subject, Name, Title, Name/Title, so that all works by an author, for example,
                    can be found with one unified Author Authority. Authority values can be selected
                    and imported or manually copied from an external source in multiple standard
                    formats. The actual "input" in the Author or Subject Heading field of the
                    Bibliographic record, for example, could either hold the actual textual value
                    (copied) or a hyperlink or UUID to the appropriate Authority record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="authorize">
            <glossterm>Authorize</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process by which a system validates that a known individual or entity has the
                    authority to perform specific actions within the system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Automated Storage Retrieval (ASR)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A computer-controlled mechanical system designed to move items efficiently
                    into compact storage and out again automatically, without human intervention. In
                    libraries with large collections, ASRSs are used to maximize storage density and
                    reduce labor costs by storing books and other materials in bins mechanically
                    stacked in rows.</para>
                <para>Definition retrieved 6/6/2014 from <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.abc-clio.com/ODLIS/odlis_a.aspx#asrs"
                        >http://www.abc-clio.com/ODLIS/odlis_a.aspx#asrs</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>B</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="barcode">
            <glossterm>Barcode (number)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In libraries, barcode number labels are physically attached to items as unique
                    identifiers and are indexed to permit retrieval of an item's record(s) when the
                    barcode number is scanned or typed in as a search term. Barcode numbers are also
                    assigned to patrons and may be printed or encoded on magnetic stripes on an ID
                    card. Patron barcodes are unique identifiers, indexed to permit retrieval of a
                    patron's record when the barcode number is scanned or typed in as a search term.
                    Barcodes are most frequently used to identify and link patrons to items when
                    items are borrowed; library staff use barcode searches for record retrieval,
                    typically for items in hand when record edits are required.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="barcodeValidation">
            <glossterm>Barcode validation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A system feature that permits identification of a barcode as pertaining to an
                    item or to a borrower (either through an initial digit or number of characters,
                    set as a system configuration value); and/or calculation of a checksum using the
                    barcode number's check digit in order to determine the validity of the barcode
                    format.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="batchJob">
            <glossterm>Batch Job</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Batch jobs, or batch processing, are what update General Ledger balances,
                    other KFS/OLE tables, and files/jobs for exports. Batch jobs need to be run on
                    some schedule to keep OLE in sync with external systems, such as University
                    Financial.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="biblioCommons">
            <glossterm>BiblioCommons</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Vendor database. See <link xlink:href="http://www.bibliocommons.com/"
                        >http://www.bibliocommons.com/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="biblopgraphicDescription">
            <glossterm>Bibliographic description</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An OLE document that describes a bibliographic entity as published. Often
                    referred to by library staff as a "bibliographic record." OLE will initially
                    support two kinds of bibliographic records: (1) Those in the USMARC
                    bibliographic formats, and (2) Dublin Core records.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="bibliography">
            <glossterm>Bibliography, bibliographic data</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Metadata describing a title such as title, author(s), publisher, date of
                    publication, standard number(s), subject headings, format, physical
                    characteristics, etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="holdings">Holdings</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="item">Items</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="MARC">MARC</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="dublinCore">Dublin Core</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="blanketApprove">
            <glossterm>Blanket Approve</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authority that is given to designated Reviewers who can approve a document to
                    a chosen route point. A Blanket Approval bypasses approvals that would otherwise
                    be required in the Routing. For an authorized Reviewer, the E-document will
                    displays the Blanket Approval button along with the other options. When a
                    Blanket Approval is used, the Reviewers who are skipped are sent Acknowledge
                    requests to notify them that they were bypassed.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="blanketOrder">
            <glossterm>Blanket Order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Generally refers to a situation where a library automatically receives any and
                    all publications from a publisher or other entity.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="standingOrder">Standing Order</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="bookNumber">
            <glossterm>Book Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A decimal number consisting of a letter of the alphabet followed by one or
                    more digits that is appended to a class number in order to arrange material on
                    the same subject in a specified order, usually alphabetically by author.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Borrower</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="patron">Patron</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="borrowerSession">
            <glossterm>Borrower Session</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A single visit to the circulation desk by a borrower. Multiple items may be
                    loaned during a single borrower session.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="borrowerType">
            <glossterm>Borrower Type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A group of library users (e.g., "undergraduate", "graduate", "faculty,
                    "alumni", "affiliate", etc.) who share a primary characteristic(s) and have the
                    same service privileges (e.g., loan period, fine rate, access (or not) to
                    interlibrary loan, etc.). Borrower type is one component in determining whether
                    or not a user can borrow a library item and if so, under what policies.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="boundWith">
            <glossterm>"Bound with"</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A physical object where two or more titles are joined together under one
                    cover. The object is represented in a system as a single item which links to
                    more than one bibliographic record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Branding</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Typically uploading an image of, or linking a library's logo to the main page
                    of a platform.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="browse">
            <glossterm>Browse</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>To enter a sorted index at a particular point, and then to be able to page up
                    or down through the index (possibly all the way up to the beginning or all the
                    way down to the end). Distinguished from "search," which means to attempt to
                    retrieve a finite set of records based on a search term or terms. A search
                    ordinarily produces a finite subset of records (which might then be sorted); a
                    browse positions the user at a particular place within an i</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="businessAnalyst">
            <glossterm>Business Analyst</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a liaison among stakeholders in order to understand the structure, policies,
                    and operations of an organization, and to recommend solutions that enable the
                    organization to achieve its goals.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="businessProcessEngine">
            <glossterm>Business Process Engine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE infrastructural middleware tool, the business process engine manages
                    and executes library business processes defined by OLE</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="businessProcessModeling">
            <glossterm>Business Process Modeling</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a design approach used by OLE to document core library processes. The start
                    and end points, step by step descriptions of how functions are performed, and
                    contingencies are written down, and duplicate processes identified.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="businessRules">
            <glossterm>Business Rules</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>1. Describes the operations, definitions and constraints that apply to an
                    organization in achieving its goals.</para>
                <para>2. A restriction to a function for a business reason (such as making a
                    specific object code unavailable for a particular type of disbursement).
                    Customizable business rules are controlled by Parameters.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>C</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="callNumber">
            <glossterm>Call number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An identifier assigned to an object, usually printed on a label attached to
                    the object, and used to determine its physical position in a shelving sequence
                    in a library. Call numbers are derived from classification schemes; Dewey,
                    Library of Congress (LC) and Superintendent of Documents (SuDoc) are the three
                    major classification schemes used in North American libraries.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="classification">classification</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="cancel">
            <glossterm>Cancel</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action available to document initiators on documents that have not
                    yet been routed for approval. Denotes that the document is void and should be
                    disregarded. Canceled documents cannot be modified in any way and do not route
                    for approval.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="cancellation">
            <glossterm>Cancellation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which a library ends its subscription to a resource.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Cancelled Request Notice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Notice sent to a patron when a hold has been manually cancelled by the library
                    staff.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="notices">Notices</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="caption">
            <glossterm>Caption</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In serials, a caption is a character(s) used for to label a level of
                    enumeration or chronology, e.g., "v." (volume), "no." (issue number), "pt."
                    (issue part), etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="enumeration">Enumeration</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="chronology">Chronology</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="capture">
            <glossterm>Capture</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process by which exposed data/metadata from an agency/source is harvested or
                    deposited into the collection</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="CAS">
            <glossterm>CAS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authentication: Central Authentication Service (CAS)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="casaliniLibri">
            <glossterm>Casalini libri</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Vendor--based in Italy--for the academic and research library community,
                    specializing in the distribution of scholarly materials from countries outside
                    the U.S.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="cataloging">
            <glossterm>Cataloging</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Used to label Describe-Manage library activities, and can be performed by
                    acquisitions, cataloging, or even licensing and circulation staff.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="charge">
            <glossterm>Charge/Charge Out</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="loan">Loan</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="chart">
            <glossterm>Chart</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Chart document is used to define the valid charts that make up the
                    high-level structure of the KFS Chart of Accounts. It also indicates who has
                    management responsibilities for each chart and which object codes are used for
                    system-generated accounting lines for the chart.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkDigit">
            <glossterm>Check digit</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A check digit is a form of redundancy check used for error detection, the
                    decimal equivalent of a binary checksum. It consists of a single digit computed
                    from the other digits in the message.With a check digit, one can detect simple
                    errors in the input of a series of digits, such as a single mistyped digit or
                    some permutations of two successive digits. In libraries, e.g., check digit
                    routines can be used to validate ISBNs, ISSN, and item and borrower barcode
                    numbers.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkin">
            <glossterm>Checkin (circulation)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="return">Return</link>.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="return">return</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkinSerials">
            <glossterm>Checkin (serials)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which a library records receipt of individual serial
                    issues</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkinAction">
            <glossterm>Checkin action</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A check-in action is a single identifiable block of behavior that may take
                    place during check-in. A check-in action will do something, then return check-in
                    conditions back to the check-in session where it originates.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkinCondition">
            <glossterm>Checkin condition</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A check-in condition indicates what the operator should do with a checked-in
                    item. A single check-in can generate multiple check-in conditions. Each check-in
                    condition can generate several interactive notifications to the user.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkinMessage">
            <glossterm>Checkin message</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Check-in message tells the user what to do with a checked-in item. A single
                    check-in can generate multiple Check-in messages.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkinSession">
            <glossterm>Checkin session</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A single check-in session is one sequence of item check-ins. The check-in
                    session is a coherent block of work in the UI. Note that the materials in a
                    given check-in session do not necessarily have anything to do with each
                    other--often they are a mixture of materials from different places in the same
                    bin. For things like batched receipt printing, it does make sense to treat the
                    check-in session as a unit of work, though.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checklistTemplate">
            <glossterm>Checklist Template</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A specific file (or files) that represents a university, library, or other
                    institution's contractual requirements; licenses negotiated by the institution
                    usually must meet (or attempt to meet) these specific requirements. Form of
                    Agreement Document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="checkout">
            <glossterm>Checkout</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="loan">Loan</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="chronology">
            <glossterm>Chronology</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Descriptive information for the dating scheme of a serial, usually identified
                    by level, e.g., level 0 = year level 1 = month would mean that each issue of the
                    serial has a month and a year on each issue. Coupled with other information such
                    as enumeration, frequency, etc., a system can predict the dating that appears on
                    each issue. Chronology levels may also be assigned a descriptive caption.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="caption">caption</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="enumeration">enumeration</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="serial">Serial</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="circulation">
            <glossterm>Circulation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The functions, policies and processes by which a library loans materials to
                    its users, tracks such transactions and charges fines and fees for policy
                    violations, e.g., overdue fines for late returns, lost item replacement fees,
                    etc. Departments in charge of circulation may also issue borrower ID cards, rent
                    lockers, collect copying fees, manage the interlibrary loan function,
                    etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="circulationLocation">
            <glossterm>Circulation Location</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The place that is considered an item's "home" when it is presented for
                    circulation transactions, i.e., it can be checked out without override AND, when
                    checked-in, does not need to be routed as it is already "home".</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="location">Location</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="citationParser">
            <glossterm>Citation Parser</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>application that parses document citations into fielded data. You can use it
                    as a web application or a service (see also Code4Lib presentation 2009- <link
                        xlink:href="https://docs.google.com/present/view?skipauth=true&amp;ncl=true&amp;id=dc5dd3br_0df622z6t"
                        >https://docs.google.com/present/view?skipauth=true&amp;ncl=true&amp;id=dc5dd3br_0df622z6t</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="claim">
            <glossterm>Claim</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The action (or a record thereof) of notifying a vendor that an ordered item
                    has not been received for whatever reason. A claim can be made for a PO line
                    item OR for a single issue of a serial title. Claims can be prompted by:
                    non-receipt, receipt of the wrong version of an item, receipt of a damaged copy,
                    etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="classTogetherSeries">
            <glossterm>Class-together Series</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A monographic series which the library has chosen to give a single call
                    number, instead of giving different call numbers to the individual volumes. A
                    series to which the library has chosen to give different call numbers to the
                    individual volumes is said to be "classed separately" or "scattered."</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="classification">
            <glossterm>[Element] classification</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The set of data elements within the OLE Instance Schema that, taken together,
                    make up the "call number" and state what classification/call number system
                    (e.g., Library of Congress, Superintendent of Documents, Dewey Decimal) the call
                    number conforms to.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="classificationScheme">
            <glossterm>Classification (classification scheme, classification schedule)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A system of coding and grouping library materials (books, serials, audiovisual
                    materials, computer files, maps, manuscripts, realia) according to their subject
                    and assigning a call number to each item.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="callNumber">Call Number</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="LC">LC</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="dewey">Dewey</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="suDoc">SuDocs</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="clone">
            <glossterm>Clone</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Ability to use an existing record (bibliographic, OLE Instance, Item,
                    Holdings, Authority, etc.) to create a new record with some the same data values
                    as contained in the original record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="close">
            <glossterm>Close</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action available on documents in most statuses. Signifies that the
                    user wishes to exit the document. No changes to Action Requests, Route Logs or
                    document status occur as a result of a Close action. If you initiate a document
                    and close it without saving, it is the same as canceling that document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="cloudComputing">
            <glossterm>Cloud computing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivery of software as a service via a network, typically the Internet.
                    "Cloud computing provides computation, software, data access, and storage
                    resources without requiring cloud users to know the location and other details
                    of the computing infrastructure. End users access cloud based applications
                    through a web browser or a light weight desktop or mobile app while the business
                    software and data are stored on servers at a remote location. Cloud application
                    providers strive to give the same or better service and performance as if the
                    software programs were installed locally on end-user computers."</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="code">
            <glossterm>Code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An individual Code within a Code List. A Code within a table of Codes will
                    have the attribute, Display Value.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="displayValue">Display Value</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="codeList">
            <glossterm>Code List</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A list of valid values for a particular data element within OLE. For example,
                    there will be a Code List for Locations; a user cannot assign a Location value
                    within an Item unless it is part of the library's Location Code List (which
                    might be shown in an OLE editor in the form of a pull-down menu). Ideally, the
                    user could not assign the Code for a Location unless the user were authorized to
                    assign that particular Code (in which case the OLE editor should show the user a
                    pull-down menu of Locations that included only those Locations that the user is
                    allowed to use). Within OLE, a Code List is made up of code values from similar
                    maintenance documents.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="location">location</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="locationCode">Location Code</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="collectionGeneral">
            <glossterm>Collection (general)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>All materials owned by a library are often referred to as its "collection(s)".
                    Can also mean the materials kept together in one area of a library, e.g.,
                    General Reference Collection, Music Recordings Collection, etc. usually in one
                    sequence (e.g., by call number).</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="locationShelving">Location (shelving)</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="collectionShelving">Collection (shelving)</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="collectionShelving">
            <glossterm>Collection (shelving)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An area of a library where a set of similar materials is physically kept,
                    e.g., "General Reference Collection", "Circulating Collection", etc. where items
                    are typically organized in a single sequence (most often by call number), A
                    collection in this sense is often identified as a "shelving location".</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="locationShelving">Location (shelving)</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="collection">
            <glossterm>Collection</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An OLE entity, a collection is a group of managed relationships. Collections
                    are not necessarily formal library collections, and may be virtual collections,
                    hierarchical relationships, relationships across formats, or a collection of
                    people and services.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="collectionSpace">
            <glossterm>Collection Space</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>(http://wiki.collectionspace.org) Academic and research libraries share
                    similarities with museums and cultural heritage organizations in how they
                    operate and manage their collections. Both types of organizations acquire,
                    describe, manage, and preserve physical, and increasingly virtual, objects.
                    During the OLE Design Project, CollectionSpace was identified as a
                    community-source project that had some confluence of approach of service
                    orientation, modular design, and functionality with the Kuali OLE project.
                    Through conversations with CollectionSpace, the Kuali OLE Partners have
                    established a basis for sharing appropriate programming code and software design
                    parameters. These efforts could save Kuali OLE efforts while designing
                    acquisition and description services, and could result in greater integration
                    between these two projects. In discussions with CollectionSpace, the Kuali OLE
                    Partners have agreed to formal interactions of these projects by a reciprocal
                    advising between the boards of the two projects.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="commitFunds">
            <glossterm>Commit Funds (Acquire)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process allows purchase price for entity to be encumbered from the appropriate
                    fund; incorporates selector guidelines for assigning funds to order.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="commitments">
            <glossterm>Commitments</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is a running total of costs expected in the future, from purchase orders
                    that have been placed, but not yet paid for. Commitments are an inexact science,
                    and their importance varies according to the types of purchases the library
                    makes. Many libraries only use them for some types of orders (like firm orders,
                    or print monographs), but do not use them at all for other types (like serial
                    standing orders).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="completed">
            <glossterm>Completed</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The action taken by a user or group in response to a request in order to
                    finish populating a document with information, as evidenced in the Document
                    Route Log.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="component">
            <glossterm>Component</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A set of functional library business processes defined by OLE</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="configurateMetadata">
            <glossterm>Configure Metadata (Manage)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where metadata is normalized and processed according to established
                    rules.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Consortia Library</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Libraries that have an administrative or legal warrant, or a business
                    arrangement that privileges cooperative activities that effectively share the
                    collections, patrons, funding, and/or other library activities of participants
                    in the consortia. Relevant to OLE implementations that require OLE functions
                    that scale to multi-campus installations, and that need to leverage
                    multi-institutional cooperative functions such as resource sharing or collection
                    management. See definition document: <link
                        xlink:href="https://docs.google.com/a/kuali.org/document/d/1mcPgucq8CKDyJkBSPe-5GzwktBsaLlsYbHpYo8ZcfTM/edit?usp=sharing"
                        >https://docs.google.com/a/kuali.org/document/d/1mcPgucq8CKDyJkBSPe-5GzwktBsaLlsYbHpYo8ZcfTM/edit?usp=sharing</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="context">
            <glossterm>Context</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, a context is a container for related agendas.  Contexts are also used
                    to control what types of actions, terms, etc. are available.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="agenda">Agenda</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="continuationOrder">
            <glossterm>Continuation order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Continuation orders are commitments from a library to purchase titles
                    published over time, e.g., a series. A continution order is an order where it is
                    not known what all the titles in the series are going to be, making it a type of
                    standing order. In fact the only real difference between a continuation order
                    and a standing order is that there may be multiple series ordered on a PO and
                    that the distribution information is considered more than just a default. But
                    just like standing orders, the order does not control what title is actually
                    received. Instead, each title comes as it is published and it is then that the
                    library describes it, receives it, and pays for it. Unless discontinued, a
                    continuation order will be modified by year-end so that it continues against a
                    new fiscal year. Unlike subscriptions, continuation orders are continued as
                    opposed to being renewed. It is also possible that a multi-volume set, published
                    over time, would be ordered as a continuation; this would probably be dictated
                    by how payment was made--if the entire amount was paid in advance, it would
                    likely be created as a firm order; if paid as each volume arrived, it might be
                    created as a continuation order.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="standingOrder">Standing Order</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="firmOrder">Firm Order</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="copy">
            <glossterm>Copy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A single specimen of an intellectual entity, e.g., a library can have one (or
                    more) copies of a single-volume monograph; one (or more) copies of a
                    multi-volume set; etc. A single subscription to a journal may also be known as a
                    "copy". A multipart book (or a serial subscription) is a copy with as many items
                    as there are volumes.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="holdings">Holding</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="item">Item</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="title">Title</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="copyRequest">
            <glossterm>Copy Request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Request for an item to be retrieved from its shelving location and designated
                    pages from that item to be reproduced (scanned or photocopied) for the
                    requesting patron. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="coutts">
            <glossterm>Coutts</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Coutts Information Services for book supply, collection management and
                    shelf-ready services</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="createEntity">
            <glossterm>Create Entity Relationships</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that creates a link between two or more entities. Entities can include
                    resources, people, courses, facilities, organizations, finances, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="createMetadata">
            <glossterm>Create Metadata (Select, Describe)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Process where descriptive, structural, and/or administrative information about
                    an entity is generated.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="credit">
            <glossterm>Credit</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>On patron bills, used by an operator to issue a credit for an amount already
                    collected.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="fullcredit">Full credit issued / Partial credit
                    issued</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="customer">
            <glossterm>Customer</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="patron">Patron</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="cutterNumber">
            <glossterm>Cutter Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A method of representing words or names by using a decimal point followed
                    first by a letter of the alphabet, then by one or more Arabic numerals. A Cutter
                    number is read and sorted as a decimal number. The cutter number is a coded
                    representation of the author or organization's name or the title of the work
                    (Charles Ammi Cutter first developed cutter numbers using a two-number table. A
                    three-number table was developed in 1969.)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>D</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="dataArchitect">
            <glossterm>Data Architect</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A data architect is a person responsible for ensuring that the data assets of
                    an organization are supported by an architecture supporting the organization in
                    achieving its strategic goals. The architecture should cover databases, data
                    integration and the means to get to the data. Usually the data architect
                    achieves his/her goals via setting enterprise data standards. A Data Architect
                    can also be referred to as a Data Modeler, although the role involves much more
                    than just creating data models.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dataDiagram">
            <glossterm>Data / Dataflow diagrams</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A data flow diagram (DFD) is a graphical representation of the "flow" of data
                    through an information system, modeling its process aspects. Often they are a
                    preliminary step used to create an overview of the system which can later be
                    elaborated</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dataModels">
            <glossterm>Data Models</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE infrastructural middleware tools, data models define how data is
                    represented, accessed, and exchanged. Data models are independent of OLE
                    components and databases.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dateApproved">
            <glossterm>Date Approved</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which a document was most recently approved.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dateFinalized">
            <glossterm>Date Finalized</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which a document enters the FINAL state. At this point, all
                    approvals and acknowledgments are complete for the document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="DCMI">
            <glossterm>DCMI (Dublin Core Metadata Initiative)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Dublin Core Metadata Initiative (DCMI) is an open organization,
                    incorporated in Singapore as a public, not-for-profit Company, engaged in the
                    development of interoperable metadata standards that support a broad range of
                    purposes and business models.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>DDC</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="dewey">Dewey Decimal Classification (DDC)</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="defaults">
            <glossterm>Defaults</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>new functionality via OLE for system, org, role, or user level defaults. For
                    example, S Miller may have default fields or selection lists pre-defined on
                    certain documents based on his permissions or memberships. A future enhancement
                    may be added for "My OLE" to support user-configured preferences. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Deleted TIPP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A TIPP is deleted when it is recognized as an error that should not have
                    existed in the first place.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="TIPP">TIPP</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="delegate">
            <glossterm>Deletgate</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user who has been registered to act on behalf of another user. The Delegate
                    acts with the full authority of the Delegator. Delegation may be either Primary
                    Delegation or Secondary Delegation.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="primaryDelegation">Primary Delegation</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="secondaryDelegation">Secondary Delegation</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="delegateActionList">
            <glossterm>Delegate Action List</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A separate Action List for Delegate actions. When a Delegate selects a
                    Delegator for whom to act, an Action List of all documents sent to the Delegator
                    is displayed.</para>
                <para>For both Primary and Secondary Delegation the Delegate may act on any of the
                    entries with the full authority of the Delegator.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="deleteEntity">
            <glossterm>Delete Entity Relationship (MER)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that removes a link between two or more entities. Entities can include
                    resources, people, courses, facilities, organizations, finances, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="deleteMetadata">
            <glossterm>Delete Metadata (Select, Describe)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where descriptive, structural, and/or administrative information about
                    an entity is removed</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="delimiter">
            <glossterm>Delimiter</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is a character or symbol that is used in front of each subfield in the
                    MARC record. The delimiter indicates to the computer that a different piece of
                    information is coming. In OLE, it is the | (bar).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="deliver">
            <glossterm>Deliver Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE component that tracks the request and supply of a resource including the
                    resource availability, the terms of access, the preconditions of use, and
                    whether the user requesting the resource has been identified and their
                    credentials checked and verified.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Delivery</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Library will deliver item to patron's designated location, rather than asking
                    the patron to come to the libary for it.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="describe">
            <glossterm>Describe Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE component where metadata for an entity is obtained, created, modified and
                    deleted</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="describeCreate">
            <glossterm>Describe- Create</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="createMetadata">Create Metadata</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="describeExpose">
            <glossterm>Describe- Expose</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="exposeMetadata">Expose Data</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="describeObtain">
            <glossterm>Describe- Obtain</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="obtainMetadata">Obtain Metadata</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="descibeDelete">
            <glossterm>Describe-Delete</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="deleteMetadata">Delete Metadata</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="describeModify">
            <glossterm>Describe-Modify</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="modifyMetadata">Modify Metadata</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="developmentInfrastructure">
            <glossterm>Development Infrastructure, OLE</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is the development infrastructure being used by OLE- see wiki page to
                    understand development environment: Application Servers, Database
                    Servers/Schemas, Instances, Schemas, Continuous Integration, Amazon Web
                    Console</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dewey">
            <glossterm>Dewey Decimal Classification/Call Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A scheme that organizes knowledge into 10 classes, 100 divisions and 1000
                    sections, using decimals for these categories to create call numbers. Works are
                    classified principally by subject, with extensions for subject relationships,
                    place, time or type of material, producing classification numbers of at least
                    three digits but otherwise of indeterminate length with a decimal point before
                    the fourth digit, where present (for example, 330 for economics + .9 for
                    geographic treatment + .04 for Europe = 330.94 European economy; 973 for United
                    States + .05 form division for periodicals = 973.05 periodicals concerning the
                    United States generally).</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="callNumber">Call Number</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="disapprove">
            <glossterm>Disapprove</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action that allows a user to indicate that a document does not
                    represent a valid business transaction in that user's judgment. The initiator
                    and previous approvers will receive Acknowledgment requests indicating the
                    document was disapproved.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="discharge">
            <glossterm>Discharge</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="return">Return</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="discoveryTools">
            <glossterm>Discovery Tool(s)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Applications (both proprietary and open source) providing search and discovery
                    functionality for library end-users; may include features such as cross-database
                    searching, relevance ranking, spell checking, tagging, enhanced content, search
                    facets. Examples include AquaBrowser, Primo, eXtensible Catalog, Blacklight,
                    etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="displayValue">
            <glossterm>Display Value</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An attribute of a Code that specifies an alternate display value for the Code
                    within a particular interface. For example, the code "REGENSTEIN" might have
                    Display Value "Regenstein Library." The display value could appear in places
                    within the OLE user interface, but could also be used by an external Discovery
                    Tool.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="code">Code</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="discoveryTools">Discovery Tools</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Doc Nbr</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="documentNumber">Document Number</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="docstore">
            <glossterm>Docstore</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE architecture for structured and unstructured metadata (e.g., bib, item,
                    holding, authority, licenses) that works in conjunction with linked
                    transactional data in an OLE RDBMS/relational tables (e.g., purchasing,
                    circulation, users, financial, borrowers).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="documentDescription">
            <glossterm>Document Description</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The description given to the document when it was created. Depending on the
                    Document Type, this description may have been assigned by the Initiator or built
                    automatically based on the contents of the document. The Document Description is
                    displayed in both the Action List and Document Search.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Document ID</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="documentNumber">Document Number</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="documentNumber">
            <glossterm>Document Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A unique, sequential, system-assigned number for a document</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="documentSearch">
            <glossterm>Document Search</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A web interface in which users can search for documents. Users may search by a
                    combination of document properties such as Document Type or Document ID, or by
                    more specialized properties using the Detailed Search. Search results are
                    displayed in a list similar to an Action List.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="documentStore">
            <glossterm>Document Store</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="docstore">DocStore</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="DOI">
            <glossterm>DOI</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: The Digital Object Identifier (DOI®) System is for identifying
                    content objects in the digital environment. DOI® names are assigned to any
                    entity for use on digital networks. They are used to provide current
                    information, including where they (or information about them) can be found on
                    the Internet</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="donorNote">
            <glossterm>Donor Note</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Donor information in an item if not purchased from specific donor funds; may
                    be a code</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="donorPublicDisplay">
            <glossterm>Donor Public Display</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Text of a Donor Note to acknowledge a specific donor</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Drools</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Drools is a Business Rules Management System (BRMS) solution that OLE uses for
                    circulation policies.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="drupal">
            <glossterm>Drupal</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Drupal is a free software package that allows anyone to easily publish, manage
                    and organize a wide variety of content on a website.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dublinCore">
            <glossterm>Dublin Core</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Dublin Core set of metadata elements provides a small and fundamental
                    group of text elements through which most resources can be described and
                    cataloged. Using only 15 base text fields, a Dublin Core metadata record can
                    describe physical resources such as books, digital materials such as video,
                    sound, image, or text files, and composite media like web pages. Metadata
                    records based on Dublin Core are intended to be used for cross-domain
                    information resource description and have become standard in the fields of
                    library science and computer science. Implementations of Dublin Core typically
                    make use of XML and are Resource Description Framework (RDF) based. Dublin Core
                    is defined by ISO through ISO Standard 15836, and NISO Standard
                    Z39.85-2007.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="dueDate">
            <glossterm>Due Date/Time</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date and/or time by which a loaned library must be returned in order to
                    avoid a penalty.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>E</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="EAD">
            <glossterm>EAD (Encoded Archival Description)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The EAD Document Type Definition (DTD) is a standard for encoding archival
                    finding aids using XML and is maintained in the Network Development and MARC
                    Standards Office of the Library of Congress (LC) in partnership with the Society
                    of American Archivists.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EBSCO">
            <glossterm>EBSCO</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>"EBSCO provides libraries with traditional print subscription services and
                    electronic information discovery and management solutions." <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.ebscoind.com/EBSCOInformationServices.asp"
                        >http://www.ebscoind.com/EBSCOInformationServices.asp</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EDI">
            <glossterm>EDI</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Electronic Data Interchange; structured transmission of data between
                    organizations by electronic means. Usually a sequence of formatted messages
                    between two parties. EDI formatted data can be transmitted using any methodology
                    agreed to by the sender and recipient: FTP, HTTP, VAN, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EDIFACT">
            <glossterm>EDIFACT</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Electronic Data Interchange for Administration, Commerce and Transport, an EDI
                    standard adopted by the United Nations.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EDIFACTInvoiceMessage">
            <glossterm>EDIFACT Invoice Message</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A file containing EDIFACT data for one or more vendor invoices.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EDIFACTMessageSegment">
            <glossterm>EDIFACT Message Segment</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A specific portion of the EDIFACT message, identified by a 3-letter code and a
                    segment number</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EDItEUR">
            <glossterm>EDItEUR</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Trade standards body for the global book and serials supply chains, with over
                    80 members in 18 countries. Works with EDIFACT, ONIX and other standards.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="eDoc">
            <glossterm>eDoc</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>"electronic document", an online business transaction initiated in a Web-based
                    form and routed electronically through a prescribed sequence of approvers. When
                    the eDoc has been through its entire approval process, it is maintained in a
                    database for future reference. The OLE adaption of Kuali Financial System (KFS)
                    for Select and Acquire uses eDocs.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="eDocSearch">
            <glossterm>eDoc Search</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The online application that lists eDocs by search conditions that you choose.
                    You may select an eDoc in the search results and view its contents or its
                    routing sequence.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="eInstance">
            <glossterm>E-Instance</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>E-Instance documents identify and describe electronic titles locally owned or
                    licensed by libraries and as such contain unique information that cannot be
                    captured by the global data provided by GOKb. They are the electronic
                    counterpart to the OLE Instance record. Each e-instance belongs to a bib
                    record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="electronicDataInterchange">
            <glossterm>Electronic Data Interchange</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="EDI">EDI</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="encumbrance">
            <glossterm>Encumbrances</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is a running total of costs expected in the future, from purchase orders
                    that have been placed, but not yet paid for. Commitments are an inexact science,
                    and their importance varies according to the types of purchases the library
                    makes. Many libraries only use them for some types of orders (like firm orders,
                    or print monographs), but do not use them at all for other types (like serial
                    standing orders).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="endowments">
            <glossterm>Endowments</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Endowments are restricted funds, segregated by the parent institution from
                    other funds. Institutions normally do not spend the capital in an endowment,
                    only some or all of the interest the fund earns each year. Unspent interest may
                    be re-capitalized, increasing the size of the endowment over time. Endowments
                    may have restrictions imposed by the donor in terms of subject matter or
                    material type. Endowments often carry requirements for reporting to the donor,
                    or for plating (placing a physical bookplate in a book, or attaching a virtual
                    bookplate to an online resource).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="enhancedContent">
            <glossterm>Enhanced content</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In discovery tools, a feature that refers to augmentation of standard
                    bibliographic metadata with additional information such as cover images, tables
                    of contents, book reviews, author biographies, content summaries, etc. Typically
                    supplied by a vendor, e.g., Syndetic Solutions (owned by R.R. Bowker).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="enterpriseLevel">
            <glossterm>Enterprise Level Integration</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>using a defined relationship, process by which a system allows linking of
                    services and business entities across applications to promote unrestricted data
                    sharing</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="entity">
            <glossterm>Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An Entity record houses identity information for a given Person, Process,
                    System, etc. Each Entity is categorized by its association with an Entity
                    Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="enumeration">
            <glossterm>Enumeration</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Descriptive information for the numbering scheme of a serial, usually
                    identified by level and a descriptive caption, e.g., level 0 = v. and level 1 =
                    no. would mean that each issue of the serial has a volume and an issue number
                    that would appear, e.g., as "v. 1 no. 3".</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="caption">Caption</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="chronology">Chronology</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="serial">Serial</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="eocr">
            <glossterm>EOCR</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Electronic Order Confirmation Record. A typical case would be: a library
                    places orders with a vendor, and the vendor returns a file of order
                    confirmations. The file could contain bibliographic records, data to populate
                    holdings and item records, and data to populate order records.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="eResourceRecord">
            <glossterm>E-resource record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The E-Resource record provides a central place to store information about an
                    e-resource acquisition throughout its lifecycle. The E-resource may be linked to
                    one or many OLE E-Instances or print Instances.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="eventManager">
            <glossterm>Event Manager</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE middleware that analyzes and reports system event data, for example
                    actions performed by users, changes in status. (Rice)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="exLibris">
            <glossterm>Ex Libris</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Commercial vendor of ILS systems ALEPH and Voyager; link resolver SFX;
                    consolidated searching tool MetaLib; ERM application Verde; digital resource
                    management application DigiTool; discovery tool Primo; and Alma, next-generation
                    ILS in the cloud.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="exception">
            <glossterm>Exception</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow routing status indicating that the document routed to an exception
                    queue because workflow has encountered a system error when trying to process the
                    document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="exceptionRouting">
            <glossterm>Exception Routing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A type of routing used to handle error conditions that occur during the
                    routing of a document. A document goes into Exception Routing when the workflow
                    engine encounters an error or a situation where it cannot proceed, such as a
                    violation of a Document Type Policy or an error contacting external services.
                    When this occurs, the document is routed to the parties responsible for handling
                    these exception cases. This can be a group configured on the document or a
                    responsibility configured in KIM. Once one of these responsible parties has
                    reviewed the situation and approved the document, it will be resubmitted to the
                    workflow engine to attempt the processing again.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="expenditure">
            <glossterm>Expenditure</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The actual expenditure of money is done by other parts of the system (payment
                    request, disbursement vouchers). The fund accounting system's role is to track
                    the money involved, and to update the fund balances. Paying an expenditure
                    usually involves removing any commitment from the purchase order involved.
                    (Note: to be added to Payment requirements- There can be partial expenditures
                    with partial commitments needing to be held until final receipt and payments
                    made against to be shipped materials. I think we want the system to have this
                    capability.)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Expired Hold</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="onHoldCourtesyNotice">On Hold Courtesy
                    Notice</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Expired Request Notice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Notice sent to a patron when the request has expired unfilled.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="notices">Notices</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="exposeMetadata">
            <glossterm>Expose Metadata (Describe)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where metadata has been made available for capture</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="extensible">
            <glossterm>eXtensible Catalog</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="XC">XC</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="externalFundingSources">
            <glossterm>External funding sources</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>(still has university accounts, money still tracked and reported to university
                    account- just different funding sources, ie not general fund). Libraries
                    frequently receive special funding from outside sources. These may include:
                    grants from foundations, government agencies, other charities, etc. to the
                    library (title 6- depts get grants, but $ reported to library and portion that
                    is library's is tracked in LMS); grant money given to other parts of the
                    organization, but subvented to the library for purchases supporting the project
                    receiving the grant; internal grants, from other divisions of the library's
                    parent organization. For instance, it is not uncommon to share the cost of a
                    particular purchase with a specific school at a university, separate from
                    whatever other money the school may be contributing to the library budget;
                    income from endowments or trusts held outside the university</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="EZProxy">
            <glossterm>EZProxy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>EZproxy is a web proxy server program extensively used by libraries to give
                    access from outside the library's computer network to restricted-access websites
                    that authenticate users by IP address. This allows library patrons at home or
                    elsewhere to log in through their library's EZproxy server and gain access to
                    bibliographic databases. OCLC Is the owner of EZProxy.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>F</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="fact">
            <glossterm>Fact</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, actual data points within a proposition used when executing a
                    rule.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="proposition">Propositions</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="rule">Rule</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fastAdd">
            <glossterm>Fast Add</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A means of circulation staff quickly assembling a cataloging record for the
                    purpose of circulating a title to a Patron. Also brief bib or brief
                    record</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fee">
            <glossterm>Fee</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A monetary charge levied by a library as a penalty (e.g., overdue fine,
                    replacement cost for a lost item) or for a service (e.g., copying, locker
                    rental).</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="overdueFine">Overdue Fine</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="replacementFee">Replacement Fee</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fieldLookup">
            <glossterm>Field Lookup</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The round magnifying glass icon found next to fields throughout the GUI that
                    allow the user to look up reference table information and display (and select
                    from) a list of valid values for that field.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="final">
            <glossterm>Final</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow routing status indicating that the document has been routed and has
                    no pending approval or acknowledgement requests.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fine">
            <glossterm>Fine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="overdueFine">Overdue Fine</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="firmOrder">
            <glossterm>Firm Order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Firm orders are commitments from a library to purchase a quantity of a title
                    from a provider. Once all quantities are resolved on a firm order (received
                    &amp; paid for, or cancelled) the order is considered complete and that no
                    further relationship continues with a provider with regards to that firm
                    order.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fluidFoundation">
            <glossterm>Fluid Foundation Project</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A critical aspect of any software system is the user interface. While Kuali
                    OLE will not provide a public interface, it will need to provide interfaces for
                    staff interactions. Efficiencies and ergonomics of the staff interface will help
                    determine the overall utility and efficacy of Kuali OLE. The Fluid Project, an
                    international group of designers, developers, advisors and volunteers that focus
                    on improving the user experience of community and open source web applications,
                    has agreed to provide consultation and development of the Kuali OLE user
                    experience framework. This work will provide an ergonomic framework for
                    constructing and extending user interfaces for staff interaction with Kuali OLE
                    functions. The commitment of the Fluid Project extends to consultation and
                    support, mentoring and design participation, and contracting for services. We
                    anticipate a successful collaboration with the Fluid Project that will enrich
                    both the Kuali OLE and the Fluid communities. (<link
                        xlink:href="http://wiki.fluidproject.org"
                        >http://wiki.fluidproject.org</link>)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="format">
            <glossterm>Format</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The physical form of a title, e.g., a printed book, e-book, DVD, map, serial,
                    CD, kit, etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="title">Title</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="FRBR">
            <glossterm>FRBR</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Content and Metadata; Functional Requirements for Bibliographic Records, a
                    conceptual entity relationship model developed by IFLA for retrieval and access
                    ( Work, Expression, Manifestation, Item) <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.ifla.org/publications/functional-requirements-for-bibliographic-records"
                        >http://www.ifla.org/publications/functional-requirements-for-bibliographic-records</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="frequency">
            <glossterm>Frequency</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The interval at which a serial appears, e.g., daily, weekly, monthly,
                    quarterly, etc. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="serial">Serial</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fullcredit">
            <glossterm>Full credit issued / Partial credit issued</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Payment statuses that documents a fee has been fully or partially credited via
                    the credit payment mode.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="credit">Credit</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fspec">
            <glossterm>Functional specification (fspec)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a set of functional library requirements for a specific library process or set
                    of related activities. In OLE, we are isolating our Fspecs per User Story in
                    order to define a small, easily specified set of requirements.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="fund">
            <glossterm>Fund</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a portion of available money in any FY budget used to purchase materials. A
                    fund can be used to purchase any kind or type of material or be dedicated to
                    purchasing materials of a particular kind. Traditional Fund Codes could be long
                    strings, that may include accounting information, fiscal year, and object codes
                    (depicting departments, subjects, collections, donors etc). When libraries or
                    specifications say "library fund", "fund" or "fund-code", it is meant as the
                    financial structure to which a budget is attributed. This term is commonly used
                    to refer to the OLE accounting string (chart, account, object code, plus
                    optional elements if desired)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>G</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="giftExchange">
            <glossterm>Gift exchange</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A voluntary agreement between a library and another organization whereby the
                    parties agree to trade specified types of materials without charge.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="giftFund">
            <glossterm>Gift fund</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Gift funds are similar to endowments in their segregation and potential
                    restrictions. The difference is that the money in a gift fund is not
                    capitalized, so its full balance is available to be spent when the institution
                    desires. Some gift funds are one-time gifts, and are gone once they are fully
                    spent. Others exist for many years, if the donor continues donating more money
                    to them.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="GILSISO">
            <glossterm>GILS ISO</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: Global Information Locator Service. <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.gils.net/about.html"
                        >http://www.gils.net/about.html</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>GLCP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>General Ledger Correction Document. A document type OLE inherited from KFS.
                    Used to load files of ledger entries, usually generated by batch jobs. Used by
                    several steps in the fiscal-year-rollover process.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="globalEdit">
            <glossterm>Global edit</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ability to make identical changes to multiple records (OLE Instance,
                    Bibliographic Description, or Authority)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="GOBI">
            <glossterm>GOBI</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An online selection and ordering tool provided by Yankee Book Peddler that
                    allows library selectors to place orders using library-profiled data such as
                    funds, etc. and define approval plans for automatic shipment of materials. GOBI
                    provides bib, item, order and invoice metadata to a library for batch
                    import.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="gracePeriod">
            <glossterm>Grace Period</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The number of days/hours by which the system automatically extends a loan
                    period (often unbeknownst to a borrower) so that items checked in before the end
                    of the grace period are treated as being returned on time, i.e., no fines or
                    penalties are assessed.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="group">
            <glossterm>Group</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Group has members that can be either Principals or other Groups (nested).
                    Groups essentially become a way to organize Entities (via Principal
                    relationships) and other Groups within logical categories.</para>
                <para>Groups can be given authorization to perform actions within applications by
                    assigning them as members of Roles.</para>
                <para>Groups can also have arbitrary identity information (i.e., Group Attributes
                    hanging from them. Group Attributes might be values for "Office Address," "Group
                    Leader," etc.</para>
                <para>Groups can be maintained at runtime through a user interface that is capable
                    of workflow.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="GUI">
            <glossterm>GUI</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Graphical User Interface (also UI).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>H</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="happeningLocation">
            <glossterm>"Happening" Location</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A work unit in a library where certain functions are performed for items
                    housed (or to be housed) at all or some of a library's shelving locations. An
                    essential component of staff operator login and setting up permissions. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="location">Location</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="harrassowitz">
            <glossterm>Harrassowitz</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Vendor--based in Germany--for the academic and research library community,
                    specializing in the distribution of scholarly materials from countries outside
                    the U.S.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="hathiTrust">
            <glossterm>Hathi Trust</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>HathiTrust is a partnership of major research institutions and libraries
                    working to ensure that the cultural record is preserved and accessible long into
                    the future.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="heading">
            <glossterm>Heading</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The descriptive metadata for a name (personal or corporate), topic/subject,
                    series title or uniform title. When placed in an authority record, a heading can
                    be coded as "established" (suitable for use when creating bibliographic
                    metadata) or as a "see" cross-reference (used to guide users to the
                    "established" form).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="hideRecord">
            <glossterm>Hide Record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>To mark a record (bibliographic, holdings, item) so that is does not display
                    in a public-facing service.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="staffOnly">Staff-only</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Hold Courtesy / Expired Hold Notice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Notice sent to a patron when the length of time an item is on the hold shelf
                    has passed.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="notices">Notices</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Hold Expiration Date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="requestExpirationDate">Request Expiration
                    Date</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="holdRequest">
            <glossterm>Hold Request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ability for a patron/borrower to ask that an item currently on loan to
                    another patron/borrower be made available when it is returned. Hold requests do
                    not alter the existing loan period for the current borrower. If an item with a
                    hold request also has a recall request, the latter will always be filled
                    first.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="recallRequest">Recall Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Hold Slip</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>PDF printed at a circulation desk to place in a book to identify the patron
                    for which the book is being held.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="holdingDescription">
            <glossterm>Holding Description</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The part of an individual OLE Instance containing the Holdings data. An OLE
                    Instance must have one and only one Holdings Description.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="OLEInstance">OLE Instance</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="holdings">
            <glossterm>Holdings</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE Definition: Describes the extent of a resource available to the user. In
                    the case of continuing resources holdings data may record the pattern of
                    issuance of a resource and/or a summary statement of volumes held. 12/16/2011.
                    See also Item. </para>
                <para> Traditional Library Definition: Metadata describing a library resource in
                    terms of its physical or virtual location and a statement of the
                    quantity/sequence available (e.g., 3 copies; volumes 1-12, etc.). In the case of
                    a multipart resource, holdings data may record the pattern of issuance (i.e.,
                    enumeration and frequency patterns of a journal) as well as a summary statement
                    of the parts available to users. A separate MARC holdings record may be linked
                    to the related MARC bibliographic record by field 004 (Control Number for
                    Related Bibliographic Record). Holdings of serial titles may be recorded in two
                    ways: (1) through serials check-in features as issues arrive; these may or may
                    not have item records; (2) through item records for individual bound volumes of
                    back issues.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="item">Item</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="OLEInstance">OLE Instance</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="OLEHolding">OLE Holding</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="sourceHolding">sourceHolding</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>I</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="identifier">
            <glossterm>Identifier</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An identifier is an alternate identifier for the patron, for instance their
                    student number. Generally identifiers are unique to a patron although duplicates
                    are permitted. This is in contrast to affiliations, where many patrons share the
                    same affiliation. Identifiers also can be used for authentication - it is
                    possible to store a username and password as an identifier. Identifiers are
                    repeatable.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="identifySupplier">
            <glossterm>Identify Supplier (Acquire)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that retrieves policy for contact with supplier and allows query of
                    potential supplier list</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="identifyTermOfUse">
            <glossterm>Identify Terms of Use (Deliver)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where a resource that has been requested has been checked for terms of
                    access and preconditions of use. (ie, licensing)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="identifyUser">
            <glossterm>Identify User (Deliver, KIM)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where user requesting resource has been identified and their
                    credentials checked and verified</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="identityManagement">
            <glossterm>Identity Management</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where user is identified and their credentials checked and verified.
                    The users could be a person using a computer, the computer itself, or a computer
                    program and could use protocols such as LDAP, Shibboleth, Secure Shell Keys, and
                    Certificates. Identity management may be performed by an OLE or 3rd party
                    component. (KIM, KEM)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ILL">
            <glossterm>ILL, Interlibrary Loan</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>service whereby a user of one library can borrow books or access other
                    resources that are owned by another library</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ILSDI">
            <glossterm>ILS-DI API</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: "From the standpoint of libraries it would be ideal to be able to
                    mix_and_match ILS and discovery plaJorms to suit local needs. To create such a
                    rich environment the library and vendor community will need agreement on the
                    specific technical details of how discovery and ILS systems are to
                    integrate"</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="import">
            <glossterm>Import</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The act of importing, or ingesting, and processing information from an
                    external vendor; performing match-n-merge overlay; and creating appropriate
                    documents inside OLE.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="importProcess">
            <glossterm>Import Process</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Manual process for a staff user to transfer a Bibliographic Description or an
                    authority record from a utility or a file of Bibliographic Descriptions or
                    authority records into the local database. The import process can be used to
                    create a new Bibliographic Description/authority record or to replace an
                    existing Bibliographic Description/authority record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ingest">
            <glossterm>Ingest</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="import">Import</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Initial subscription start date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The first day of the initial subscription term for which an order was
                    placed.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="initiated">
            <glossterm>Initiated</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow routing status indicating a document has been created but has not
                    yet been saved or routed. A Document Number is automatically assigned by the
                    system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="initiator">
            <glossterm>Initiator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user role for a person who creates (initiates or authors) a new document for
                    routing. Depending on the permissions associated with the Document Type, only
                    certain users may be able to initiate documents of that type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="III">
            <glossterm>Innovative Interfaces, Inc. (III)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Commercial vendor of ILS system Millennium and discovery tool Encore.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="inquiry">
            <glossterm>Inquiry</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A screen that allows a user to view information about a business
                    object.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="instance">
            <glossterm>Instance</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="OLEInstance">OLE Instance</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="intellectualEntity">
            <glossterm>Intellectual entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>in a library context, any work in any format considered for purchase or
                    licensing, e.g., a book, serial, DVD, sound recording, archive, manuscript
                    collection, map, database, online resource, indexing service, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="inventory">
            <glossterm>Inventory</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process by which an entity is evaluated and tracked for retention and version
                    preference, and access and descriptive metadata updated. May be used to manage
                    weeding, reformatting, or relocation.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="invoice">
            <glossterm>Invoice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>New type of document to enter invoice payment requests in order to avoid
                    having to create individual PREQs and to distribute the cost of additional
                    charges.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ISBN">
            <glossterm>ISBN</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An International Standard Book Number "identifies the title or other book-like
                    product (such as an audiobook) to which it is assigned, but also the publisher
                    to be contacted for ordering purposes." ISBNs are 13-digit numbers (formerly
                    10-digits); the various elements of the number are separated by a hyphen ( -
                    ).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ISSN">
            <glossterm>ISSN</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ISSN is the standardized international code which allows the
                    identification of any serial publication, including electronic serials,
                    independently of its country of publication, of its language or alphabet, of its
                    frequency, medium, etc. The ISSN number,therefore, preceded by these letters,
                    and appears as two groups of four digits, separated by a hyphen , has no
                    signification in itself and does not contain in itself any information referring
                    to the origin or contents of the publication.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="issue">
            <glossterm>Issue</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An individual piece of a serial title. An issue often (but not always) has a
                    unique enumeration (e.g., volume 5, number 6) and chronology (e.g., June 2010)
                    that distinguishes it from other issues of the serial title.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="serial">Serial</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="item">
            <glossterm>Item</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE Definition: Describes the smallest unit of a resource that is managed
                    and/or circulated individually. It provides specific information regarding the
                    physical location when pertinent.</para>
                <para>Traditional Library Definition: An individual physical piece (e.g., a single
                    print volume; a DVD; an archival box; a CD jewel case) to which a library
                    typically assigns a unique barcode number and affixes the barcode number
                    label.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="copy">Copy</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="holdings">Holdings</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="OLEInstance">OLE Instance</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="OLEHolding">OLE Holding</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="sourceHolding">sourceHolding</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="title">Title</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="piece">Piece</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="itemAvailability">
            <glossterm>Item availability status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The item availability status is a single field that indicates whether the
                    library can loan an item. Items become temporarily unloanable when they are part
                    of some process, such as being on order, being on loan to another patron, and so
                    on.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="itemDescription">
            <glossterm>Item description</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The part of an individual OLE Instance containing the data about an individual
                    Item. An OLE Instance must have at least one Item Description and may have many
                    Item Descriptions.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Item-level</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>To request an individual, specific copy of a work, or make a request on
                    something where only one copy exists.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="itemStatus">
            <glossterm>Item status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A descriptor describing an item's state for circulation purposes, e.g., "not
                    checked out", "on hold", "checked out", "on shelf", etc. If an item is still in
                    the order process, item status typically is the same as the order status, e.g.,
                    "on order", "received", "in processing", etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="itemType">
            <glossterm>Item type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An identifier assigned to each item in a library that, in circulation, is one
                    component that can determine whether or not such an item can be borrowed and, if
                    so, the conditions of the loan. Item types are generally defined by each library
                    and can be either a specific format (e.g., "DVD", "CD", "Map", etc.) or an
                    indicator of borrowing eligibility (e.g., "Circulating", "Non-Circulating"). In
                    practice, item type itself does not determine loan conditions but is used in
                    combination with location and borrower type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>J</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="JISC">
            <glossterm>JISC</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>licensing company. See <link xlink:href="http://www.jisc.ac.uk"
                        >http://www.jisc.ac.uk</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="journal">
            <glossterm>Journal</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="serial">Serial</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="JSON">
            <glossterm>JSON</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivery: JavaScript Object Notation. See <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.json.org/">http://www.json.org/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="JSTOR">
            <glossterm>JSTOR</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>"JSTOR is a not-for-profit service that helps scholars, researchers, and
                    students discover, use, and build upon a wide range of content in a trusted
                    digital archive of over one thousand academic journals and other scholarly
                    content." <link xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/"
                    >http://www.jstor.org/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>K</title>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KCA</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Kuali Commercial Affiliate. A designation provided to commercial affiliates
                    who become part of the Kuali Partners Program to provide for-fee guidance,
                    support, implementation, and integration services related to the Kuali software.
                    Affiliates hold no ownership of Kuali intellectual property, but are full KPP
                    participants. Affiliates may provide packaged versions of Kuali that provide
                    value for installation or integration beyond the basic Kuali software.
                    Affiliates may also offer other types of training, documentation, or hosting
                    services.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KFS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="KFS">Kuali Financial System</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KFSAdministrativeTransactions">
            <glossterm>KFS Administrative Transactions</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> Allows the financial representation of a business activity performed by an
                    administrative or central office. Administrative transactions are like all
                    transactions in that they are recorded in journals or e-docs that are then
                    posted to the General Ledger and affect the financial statements of the
                    organization. Examples of administrative transactions are effort certification
                    recreate, cash management, and journal voucher. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KFSCustomDocSearches">
            <glossterm>KFS Custom Document Searches</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> Allows searches for specific types of documents based on attributes of the
                    transactions, primary key data elements, or both. Additional fields, specific to
                    different modules, are available on custom document searches. Examples are
                    customer invoices and requisitions. Special access may be required to retrieve
                    custom document searches. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KFSTransaction">
            <glossterm>KFS Transaction</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> Allows the financial representation of a basic business activity.
                    Transactions are recorded in e-docs or journals that are then posted to the
                    General Ledger and affect the financial statements of the organization. Examples
                    of transactions are customer invoices, cash receipts and requisitions. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KIM</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="KIM">Kuali Identity Management</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KEW</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="KEW">Kuali Enterprise Workflow</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="knowledgebase">
            <glossterm>Knowledgebase</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A data source for global-level descriptive data elements about
                    e-resources</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KNS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="KNS">Kuali Nervous System</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KRMS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="KRMS">Kuali Rules Management System</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>KSB</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="KSB">Kuali Service Bus</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="coeus">
            <glossterm>Kuali Coeus</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Kuali Coeus (KC) project is building a comprehensive system to manage the
                    complexities of research administration that fully addresses the needs from the
                    faculty researcher through grants administration to federal funding agencies. KC
                    is using MIT's proven COEUS system as its baseline design, filling in missing
                    functionality from COEUS, and updating its technical architecture for vendor
                    independence and easier integration with other administration systems</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KEW">
            <glossterm>Kuali Enterprise Workflow (KEW)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>workflow / Workflow Services / Kuali Enterprise Workflow (KEW) - the Kuali
                    infrastructure service that electronically routes an eDoc to its approvers in a
                    prescribed sequence, according to established business rules based on the eDoc
                    content.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KEM">
            <glossterm>Kuali Entity Management (KEM)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Future enhancement to KFS and KIM as partner to KIM, but for entities- to
                    provide another layer to differentiate customers, vendors, other groups and
                    organizations</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KFS">
            <glossterm>Kuali Financial System (KFS)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Kuali Financial System (KFS) project is a comprehensive suite of financial
                    software that meets the needs of all Carnegie Class institutions. Its partner
                    institutions are colleges, universities, and interested organizations that share
                    a common vision of open, modular, and distributed systems for their software
                    requirements. The goal of KFS is to bring the proven functionality of legacy
                    applications to the ease and universality of online services. Based on modular
                    architecture. Incorporated/adapted/extended by OLE for its Select and Acquire
                    modules.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="foundation">
            <glossterm>Kuali Foundation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Kuali - (ku-wah-lee) 1) kitchen wok - humble utensil which plays an important
                    role in a successful kitchen, 2) Kuali Financial Systems - insanely fine,
                    collaboratively developed, modular financial information system for higher
                    education, 3) Community sourced development effort for distributed services in
                    higher-education</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KIM">
            <glossterm>Kuali Identity Management (KIM)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Solutions for authentication and authorization have been provided as part of
                    the Kuali Identity Management (KIM) module in Rice. Kuali Identity Management
                    (KIM) provides central identity and access management services. It also provides
                    management features for Identity, Groups, Roles, Permissions, and their
                    relationships with each other. All integration with KIM is through a simple and
                    consistent service API (Java or Web Services). The services are implemented as a
                    general-purpose solution that could be leveraged by both Kuali and non-Kuali
                    applications alike.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KMM">
            <glossterm>Kuali Materials Management (KMM)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>incubator project within Kuali: Kuali Materials Management</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KNS">
            <glossterm>Kuali Nervous System (KNS)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> underlying infrastructure code that any Kuali module may employ to perform
                    its functions. The KNS is a set of functionality common to many modules.
                    Examples include creating custom attributes, attaching electronic images,
                    uploading data from desktop applications, lookup/search routines, and database
                    interaction. the the Kuali Nervous System (KNS) provides services for encryption
                    and decryption of data. KNS will eventually be replaced by KRAD beginning with
                    Kuali Rice 2.0.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="OLE">
            <glossterm>Kuali OLE</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The goal of the Kuali Open Library Environment Project is to define a
                    next-generation technology environment based on a thoroughly re-examined model
                    of library business operations. The model will then be used to develop
                    specifications for a next generation community-sourced library management
                    system, Kuali OLE (pronounced oh-LAY). This software system will be a part of
                    the academic enterprise technology framework and will scale up to connect with
                    other enterprise technology systems within the academic and administrative
                    computing environment. The software system will also be capable of scaling down
                    for stand-alone library use</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KPME">
            <glossterm>Kuali People Management for the Enterprise (KPME)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Over the past year, many schools have expressed interest in the idea of
                    forming a Kuali HR/Payroll project. Many of us have aging HR/Payroll systems and
                    are looking for a comprehensive, fully functional system, that is built BY
                    higher education FOR higher education. The interested schools have prepared a
                    white paper to describe the objectives of the project, and an initial phase for
                    delivery</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KRAD">
            <glossterm>Kuali Rapid Application Development (KRAD)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>"Kuali Rapid Application Development (KRAD) is a framework that eases the
                    development of enterprise web applications by providing reusable solutions and
                    tooling that enables developers to build in a rapid and agile fashion. KRAD is a
                    complete framework for web developers that provides infrastructure in all the
                    major areas of an application (client, business, and data), and integrates with
                    other modules of the Rice middleware project. In future releases, KNS will be
                    absorbed into and replaced by KRAD."</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="Ready">
            <glossterm>Kuali Ready</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Kuali Ready is a business continuity planning tool that is specific to
                    institutions of higher education. Its aim is to increase the institution's
                    ability to keep operating in the face of disruptive events. Kuali Ready produces
                    departmental continuity plans, and can be used by any type of department:
                    instructional, research, support, administrative, collections, and
                    clinical</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="Rice">
            <glossterm>Kuali Rice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Kuali Rice software provides an enterprise class middleware suite of
                    integrated products that allows for applications to be built in an agile
                    fashion. This enables developers to react to end-user business requirements in
                    an efficient and productive manner, so that they can produce high quality
                    business applications.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KRMS">
            <glossterm>Kuali Rules Management System</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>"Kuali Rule Management System (KRMS) is a common rules engine for defining
                    decision logic, commonly referred to as business rules. KRMS facilitates the
                    creation and maintenance of rules outside of an application for rapid update and
                    flexible implementation that can be shared across applications."</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="KSB">
            <glossterm>Kuali Service Bus</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Kuali Service Bus (KSB) is a simple service bus geared towards easy service
                    integration in an SOA architecture. In a world of difficult to use service bus
                    products KSB focuses on ease of use and integration. Message Driven Service
                    Execution; Transactional Asynchronous Messaging; Synchronous Messaging; Queue
                    Style Messaging.; Topic Style Messaging; Quality of Service; Service Discovery;
                    Reliability; Persisted Callback; Primitive Business Activity Monitoring; Spring
                    Based Integration; Programmatic Based Integration</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="student">
            <glossterm>Kuali Student</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Kuali Student will be a modular, open source, standards-based next generation
                    student system that will offer a flexible, scalable, cost-effective system that
                    can be configured to meet the business requirements of any higher education
                    institution</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>L</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="lastModifiedDate">
            <glossterm>Last Modified Date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date on which the document was last modified (e.g., the date of the last
                    action taken, the last action request generated, the last status changed,
                    etc.).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="LC">
            <glossterm>LC (Library of Congress)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Congressional agency to support the research needs of the U.S. Congress, LC
                    has evolved into a de facto national library of the U.S., creating and
                    distributing bibliographic metadata at minimal cost; developing and maintaining
                    MARC; and providing a myriad of other services to the U.S. library
                    community.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="LCClassification">
            <glossterm>LC (Library of Congress) Classification/Call Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A system originally developed at LC to organize subjects into broad
                    categories; it is essentially enumerative in nature. It provides a guide to the
                    books actually in a library, not a classification of the world (as Dewey
                    attempts to do). Call numbers derived from the system consist of one or two
                    letters followed by numbers/punctuation, e.g., PS1742._F6 1897 where PS is
                    American Literature, 1742.F6 further refines the topic of the work, and 1897 is
                    the date of publication and is part of what is called a Cutter number.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="callNumber">Call Number</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="LDAP">
            <glossterm>LDAP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authentication: LDAP, Lightweight Directory Access Protocol, is an Internet
                    protocol that email and other programs use to look up information from a server
                    OR is an application protocol for reading and editing directories over an IP
                    network</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="libLime">
            <glossterm>LibLime</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>consulting, implementation, data migrations, for Koha in over 800
                    libraries</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="libraryCatalog">
            <glossterm>Library Catalog</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A library catalog is a register of all bibliographic items found in a library
                    or group of libraries, such as a network of libraries at several locations, such
                    as <link xlink:href="http://www.iucat.iu.edu"
                    >http://www.iucat.iu.edu</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Library of Congress Classification/Call Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="LCClassification">LC Classification/Call
                    Number</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Library privileges</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="privileges">Privileges</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="libraryTechnicalServices">
            <glossterm>Library Technical Services</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Common name of primary work unit in libraries that is charged with overall
                    preparation of materials for circulation. After items/titles are
                    ordered/received, found, gifted, this unit (sometimes referred to as Cataloging)
                    prepares materials to make them available to library staff, patrons, online
                    catalogs, library catalog/discover layer. Common tasks can include: import or
                    completion of the Bib Record; edit or creation of the Instance or Holdings
                    record; bindery; shelf-prep; barcode; in-transit activities; bookplating
                    (gifts); etc. This varies by library and workflows are different for physical
                    items (books, DVDs, maps, etc) than Serial/Subsctiptions (magazines,
                    bound-withs, multi-volume sets), and Electronic resources (URL links, licenses).
                    Special handling/workflows may also be in place for offsite storage activities,
                    Archives, Special Collections.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Library user</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="patron">Patron</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="libraryUserInterface">
            <glossterm>Library user interface</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An application, typically Web/browser based, providing users with the ability
                    to search library and other information databases as selected by the library. In
                    most such products, the basic search type is general keyword (AND as a default
                    operator) with search results from all sources presented by relevancy ranking.
                    These applications typically offer a variety of local configuration options
                    (e.g., indexing choices for each database; display configuration for various
                    record types; etc.); social features such as public reviews, ratings, tagging,
                    and "my list" features; etc. Also included are "my account"-type functions,
                    i.e., the ability for a library user to renew items, check on the status of
                    requests, pay bills, update address information, etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="onlineCatalog">Online Catalog</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="license">
            <glossterm>License</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a right that gives a person or entity permission to do something that would be
                    illegal if the person or entity did not have such permission. Usually the scope
                    of the permission excludes ownership rights or privileges.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="lineItem">
            <glossterm>Line item</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an entity to be ordered, usually identified by title on a purchase order; any
                    purchase order can have more than one line item, e.g., 10 books on a purchase
                    order = 10 line items, one for each. Intended for ease of purchasing multiple
                    items from one vendor.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="linkResolver">
            <glossterm>Link Resolver</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A service that mediates OpenURL linking to library targets (licensed
                    electronic resources)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="loan">
            <glossterm>Loan</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which the system: (1) validates whether or not a library user
                    can borrow a library item based on defined attributes (e.g., the circulation
                    desk location, the shelving location of the item, item type, borrower type,
                    etc.); and (2) if a loan is permitted, links the item with the patron and
                    applies certain conditions (e.g., length of loan period) based on policies
                    defined in configuration files. Synonyms: Check-out, charge, charge out</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="loanPeriod">
            <glossterm>Loan Period</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The period of time for which a user has been allowed to borrow a library item.
                    The loan period is usually dependent on the item type, the item's location and
                    the borrower type. A loan period can be expressed in days, hours, as a fixed
                    date, or as "indefinite".</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="location">
            <glossterm>Location</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An element in a library's system configuration that describes a conceptual
                    entity or institution (e.g., "The University of X Library") or a building ("John
                    Doe Memorial Library") or an area ("Doe Library, Bookstacks"; "Doe Library,
                    Circulation Desk") where items are shelved or work is performed. All library
                    items are assigned to a shelving area location and this becomes an attribute for
                    circulation policy. Locations may also refer to library staff work areas at
                    which certain functions (e.g., acquisitions (or ordering and receiving),
                    cataloging, serials receiving, course reserve or circulation are the standard
                    ones) are performed on or with items housed at shelving locations; work areas
                    (e.g., a circulation location) are identified as part of an operator's login. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="locationShelving">Location (shelving)</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="locationCode">
            <glossterm>Location code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Code value from a Code List that describes, with a greater or lesser degree
                    of specificity, the Location where an Item is located. Within OLE there may be
                    up to five different levels of Location, so the Item may contain as many as five
                    different Location Codes. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="code">Code</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="codeList">Code List</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="locationHappening">
            <glossterm>Location ("happening")</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="workUnit">Work Unit</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="locationShelving">
            <glossterm>Location (shelving)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A physical area where library items are housed, generally in single sequence
                    (usually but not always by call number), either permanently or temporarily, and
                    identified in holdings and/or item-level records by codes and/or literals.
                    Shelving location is an attribute in determining circulation policy and can also
                    be used as a search limit.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="collectionGeneral">Collection (general)</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="collectionShelving">Collection (shelving)</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="location">Location</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="lookups">
            <glossterm>Lookups</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The round magnifying glass or 'lookup' icon on any edoc or screen allows you
                    to look up reference table information so you avoid data entry errors. Multiple
                    lookup and selection is also available. Lookups from an existing document allow
                    a "search select" option to return the selected value to the working edoc.
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Lost Book Processing Fee</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A fee type that is created at the same time a replacement fee is created (when
                    an item ages to lost or manually billed as lost) if desired by a library.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="lostItemReplacement">
            <glossterm>Lost Item Replacement Fee</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="replacementFee">Replacement fee</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>M</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="MADS">
            <glossterm>MADS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Content and Metadata; Metadata Authority Description Schema (MADS) is an XML
                    schema developed by the United States Library of Congress' Network Development
                    and Standards Office that provides an authority element set to complement the
                    Metadata Object Description Schema (MODS</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Magazine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="serial">Serial</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="magnolia">
            <glossterm>Magnolia</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>open source content management systems. See <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.magnolia-cms.com/magnolia-cms.html"
                        >http://www.magnolia-cms.com/magnolia-cms.html</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="maintenanceDocs">
            <glossterm>Maintenance document</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An e-doc used to establish and maintain a table record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="MER">
            <glossterm>Manage (Create) Entity Relationship (MER)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE component that allows for the creation, modification and deletion of
                    relationships between any two or more entities. Entities can include resources,
                    people, courses, facilities, organizations, finances, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="manageEntity">
            <glossterm>Manage Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE component that describes the processes that track the lifecycle of an
                    entity including preservation, curation, evaluation, retention, relocation,
                    duplication, version preference, rights management, and updated in this process
                    according to established rules.binding, repair, reformat, replacement, and
                    withdraw. Access and descriptive metadata may be normalized</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="manageFunds">
            <glossterm>Manage Funds (Acquire)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process supported by the system to make payment for a service or product.
                    Included in this process is a log trigger and log response; the system records
                    the usage of services or product for audit, reporting or billing
                    purposes.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="manageInventory">
            <glossterm>Manage Inventory (Manage)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where entity is evaluated and tracked for retention and version
                    preference, and access and descriptive metadata updated.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="manageRights">
            <glossterm>Manage Rights (Manage)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where information is maintained (collected, stored, updated) regarding
                    rights of entities. Information is consulted and disseminated as
                    necessary.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="manageTerms">
            <glossterm>Manage Terms of Acquisitions Use (Acquire)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>documents and manages acquisitions entities and associated information license
                    terms (e-resources, gift, deposit, exchange, approval, etc.) selected for the
                    collection; record is created with pending status; tracking begins as
                    negotiations and/or evaluation of trial take place; final selection decision is
                    recorded and pending status removed.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="manageUserRelationship">
            <glossterm>Manage User Relationship</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE or 3rd party component that describes processes to handle CRM (customer
                    relationship management) including a user's initiation for request of service to
                    the fulfilling of that request.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="MARC">
            <glossterm>MARC</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>MARC (acronym for machine readable cataloging) is a standard for the
                    representation and communication of bibliographic, authority and holdings
                    information in machine-readable form. The structure of MARC records is an
                    implementation of national and international standards, e.g., Information
                    Interchange Format (ANSI Z39.2) and Format for Information Exchange (ISO
                    2709).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="MARCXML">
            <glossterm>MARC XML</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A framework for working with MARC data in a XML environment.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="matchPoint">
            <glossterm>Match point</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A data element used to determine a Bibliographic Description/authority record
                    to be replaced by a new Bibliographic Description/authority record in the import
                    process.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="membershipOrder">
            <glossterm>Membership order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Membership orders are commitments from a library to purchase a subscription to
                    a membership from a provider. Having a membership may give a library permission
                    to order materials from the provider or might cause the provider to periodically
                    send materials to the library. Generally, memberships are renewed to continue
                    the relationship with a provider.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="metadata">
            <glossterm>Metadata</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>'data about data', metadata defines, describes and manages information and may
                    include descriptive, holdings, authority, financial, or other types of
                    data.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="metricDoc">
            <glossterm>MetricDoc</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A reporting tool created by the University of Pennsylvania. Metridoc is a data
                    integration / job framework to assist libraries with data ingestion and
                    normalization, with the end result being a repository to help deal with usage
                    reporting.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="METS">
            <glossterm>METS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Content and Metadata; Metadata Encoding and Transmission Standard (METS) is a
                    metadata standard for encoding descriptive, administrative, and structural
                    metadata regarding objects within a digital library, expressed using the XML
                    schema language of the World Wide Web Consortium. The standard is maintained in
                    the Network Development and MARC Standards Office of the Library of Congress,
                    and is being developed as an initiative of the Digital Library Federation</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="middleware">
            <glossterm>Middleware</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>software that manages and connects OLE components and provides
                    interoperability with 3rd party applications and components; consists of a
                    number of functions that can be called upon by multiple components</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ModifyEntity">
            <glossterm>Modify Entity Relationships (MER)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that modifies a link between two or more entities. Entities can
                    include resources, people, courses, facilities, organizations, finances,
                    etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="modifyMetadata">
            <glossterm>Modify Metadata (Select, Describe)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where descriptive, structural, and/or administrative information about
                    an entity is altered</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="monographicSeries">
            <glossterm>Monographic series</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Scholarly and scientific books released in successive volumes, each of which
                    is structured like a separate book or scholarly monograph. See also:
                    series.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="series">Series</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="MODS">
            <glossterm>MODS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Metadata Object Description Schema is an XML-based bibliographic description
                    schema developed by the United States Library of Congress' Network Development
                    and Standards Office. MODS was designed as a compromise between the complexity
                    of the MARC format used by libraries and the extreme simplicity of Dublin Core
                    metadata.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Multi-tenant</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A software deployment model and business practice for hosting multiple tenants
                    on a single software instance that are logically separate and secure. Relevant
                    to OLE implementations that operate OLE for multiple clients, such as the GBV or
                    hbz, or for single instance implementations that want a commercial or
                    centralized hosted solution for OLE. See definition document: <link
                        xlink:href="https://docs.google.com/a/kuali.org/document/d/1WezORtYjQgm4bOw1ZjHRqGO2JnpDOliOREMuqjrsfVM/edit?usp=sharing"
                        >https://docs.google.com/a/kuali.org/document/d/1WezORtYjQgm4bOw1ZjHRqGO2JnpDOliOREMuqjrsfVM/edit?usp=sharing</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>N</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="NCIP">
            <glossterm>NCIP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>NISO (National Information Standards Organization) Circulation Interchange
                    Protocol. This Standard is intended to address the growing need for
                    interoperability among disparate circulation, interlibrary loan, and related
                    applications. Interoperability between self-service applications and circulation
                    applications; between and among various circulation applications; between
                    circulation and interlibrary loan applications; and between other related
                    applications, has been the principal focus of this Standard.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="negotiatedLicense">
            <glossterm>Negotiated License</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>One specific type of Agreement, which usually covers negotiated access to a
                    purchased resource or collection of resources. The ONIX-PL standard was
                    developed specifically to describe / transport both the text and interpretation
                    of a negotiated license.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Newspaper</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="serial">Serial</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="NISO">
            <glossterm>NISO (National Information Standards Organization)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A non-profit association accredited by the American National Standards
                    Institute (ANSI); identifies, develops, maintains, and publishes technical
                    standards to manage information in our changing and ever-more digital
                    environment. NISO standards apply both traditional and new technologies to the
                    full range of information-related needs, including retrieval, re-purposing,
                    storage, metadata, and preservation. NISO has a variety of working groups of
                    interest to OLE including those investigating ERM, KBART, CORE, et al.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="NLM">
            <glossterm>NLM classification/call numbers</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>National Library of Medicine - These call numbers cover the field of medicine
                    and related sciences, utilizing schedules QS-QZ and W-WZ, permanently excluded
                    from the Library of Congress (LC) Classification schedules. The NLM
                    Classification is a system of mixed notation patterned after the Library of
                    Congress (LC) Classification where alphabetical letters which denote broad
                    subject categories are further subdivided by numbers.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="notices">
            <glossterm>Notices</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Messages sent to borrowers as a result of requests made for library items or
                    the status of current loans of library items, e.g., recall notices, overdue
                    notices, on hold notices, etc. Notices can be printed, emailed or texted.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>O</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="OAIPMH">
            <glossterm>OAI-PMH</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: Open Archives Initiative- Protocol for Metadata Harvesting. <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.openarchives.org/pmh/tools/"
                        >http://www.openarchives.org/pmh/tools/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="objectCode">
            <glossterm>Object Code</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Object codes represent all income, expense, asset, liability and fund balance
                    classifications that are assigned to transactions and help identify the nature
                    of the transaction Object Level. The Object Level document is used to maintain
                    an attribute of the object code that is used to group similar object codes into
                    categories for reporting Object Consolidation The Object Consolidation document
                    defines a general category of object codes for reporting. One object
                    consolidation includes the object codes belonging to one or more object
                    levels.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="obtainMetadata">
            <glossterm>Obtain Metadata (Select, Describe)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where descriptive, structural, and/or administrative information about
                    an entity is acquired.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="OCLC">
            <glossterm>OCLC</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Worlds largest library cooperative, source of WorldCat online catalog
                    (originally the Ohio College Library Center)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ODLIS">
            <glossterm>ODLIS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Online Dictionary for Library and Information Science, <link
                        xlink:href="http://lu.com/odlis/">http://lu.com/odlis/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="OLEHolding">
            <glossterm>OLE Holding</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This section of the OLE Instance records "general" holdings information in a
                    format specific to OLE.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="OLEInstance">
            <glossterm>OLE Instance</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE XML document type that describes individual Holdings and associated Items.
                    The OLE Instance document is a container for recording holdings and item
                    information for a bibliographic record. See also Holdings, OLE Holding,
                    sourceholding and Items.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="OLESourceHolding">
            <glossterm>OLE sourceHolding</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This section of the OLE Instance represents "specific" holdings information
                    entered according to some standard external to OLE. Examples are MARC holdings,
                    MODS holdings or any other format specific holdings.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="onHoldCourtesyNotice">
            <glossterm>On Hold Courtesy Notice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Notice sent to a patron when a hold has expired and will be removed from the
                    hold shelf.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="notices">Notices</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>On Hold Notice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Notice sent to a patron when a hold is available for pick-up.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="notices">Notices</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ONIX">
            <glossterm>ONIX</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An XML-based family of international standards intended to support
                    computer-to-computer communication between parties involved in creating,
                    distributing, licensing or otherwise making available intellectual property in
                    published form, whether physical or digital</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ONIXForBooks">
            <glossterm>ONIX for Books</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ONIX for Books Product Information Message is the international standard
                    for representing and communicating book industry product information in
                    electronic form.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ONIXForLicensing">
            <glossterm>ONIX for Licensing (LT)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>ONIX for Licensing Terms (LT) is the generic name for the most recent addition
                    to the ONIX family. Built on a consistent underlying model of rights and usages,
                    OLT formats are specialized to the needs of different user groups and
                    applications.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ONIXForPublications">
            <glossterm>ONIX for Publications Licensing (PL)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>ONIX for Publications Licenses (ONIX-PL) is intended to support the licensing
                    of electronic resources - such as online journals and ebooks - to academic and
                    corporate libraries. ONIX-PL enables libraries to: (1) express licenses in a
                    machine-readable format; (2) load them into electronic resource management
                    systems; (3) link them to digital resources; and (4) communicate key usage terms
                    to users. Publishers can also benefit from the ability to maintain their
                    licenses in a standard machine-readable form.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ONIXForSerials">
            <glossterm>ONIX for Serials</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>ONIX for Serials is a family of XML formats for communicating information
                    about serial products and subscription information, using the design principles
                    and many of the elements defined in ONIX for Books.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="onlineCatalog">
            <glossterm>Online Catalog</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The public user interface module of an integrated library system (ILS) that
                    provides the ability to search for and display library resources by various
                    search types and limits. Current online catalogs, while browser based, are
                    typically proprietary applications that have limited capabilities for extending
                    discovery and access to databases external to the library. Online catalogs also
                    typically provide "my account"-type functions, e.g., the ability for a library
                    user to renew items, check the status of requests, update an address,
                    etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="libraryUserInterface">Library User Interface</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>OPAC</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An Online Public Access Catalog (OPAC). </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="onlineCatalog">Online Catalog</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="openID">
            <glossterm>OpenID</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Authentication: OpenID is an open standard that describes how users can be
                    authenticated in a decentralized manner</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="openURL">
            <glossterm>Open URL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: OpenURL is a standardized format of Uniform Resource Locator (URL)
                    intended to enable Internet users to more easily find a copy of a resource that
                    they are allowed to access. Although OpenURL can be used with any kind of
                    resource on the Internet, it is most heavily used by libraries to help connect
                    patrons to subscription content</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="operatingFunds">
            <glossterm>Operating funds</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This is unrestricted money from the parent organization. In universities, this
                    money typically comes from sources like tuition. Often, the library receives a
                    lump sum of operating money from its parent body, and then decides internally
                    how much of that to allocate for collection development.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="operator">
            <glossterm>Operator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a person who creates/updates/deletes a document online and typically recorded
                    as such in a document's audit trail.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="operatorCirculation">
            <glossterm>Operator (Circulation)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Operators log into OLE to do work. They perform work on behalf of patrons in
                    the system.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="OPLE">
            <glossterm>OPLE</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Open source software package developed by EDItEUR for creating, editing and
                    managing license expressions using ONIX-PL. OPLE can be installed on a wide
                    range of computer platforms from large network servers to individual laptop PCs
                    and is compatible with all major operating system environments (Microsoft
                    Windows, Apple Macintosh, Linux).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="orderResource">
            <glossterm>Order Resource (Acquire)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>obtain collection resources, with associated functions to manage providers. In
                    the case of acquiring digital material it is a process whereby a system manages
                    content in order to bring it into a collection.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="orderStatus">
            <glossterm>Order status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a label describing the purchase order's stage in the overall acquisition
                    process from, e.g., "new" to "received/paid". Overlaps with item status.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="orderType">
            <glossterm>Order type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a label describing characteristics of the order that indicate what future
                    actions will apply. Required for any purchase order.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="organization">
            <glossterm>Organization</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE entity, an organization is an administrative structure, for example a
                    college or university, library, institution, society, consortium, or
                    association.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="overdueFine">
            <glossterm>Overdue Fine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The amount charged to a borrower when a loaned library item is returned late.
                    Overdue fines are calculated at checkin, based on an amount per day/hour, and
                    may vary depending upon the borrower type, the item's location and the item
                    type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="overdueRecall">
            <glossterm>Overdue Recall Fine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The amount charged to a borrower when a loaned library item that has been
                    recalled is returned late. Recall overdue fines are calculated at checkin, based
                    on an amount per day/hour, and may vary depending upon the borrower type, the
                    item's location and the item type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ownership">
            <glossterm>Ownership</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The idea that permissions or policies based on a piece of data in a document
                    (bib control numbers, item location, ownership field data) could be used to
                    infer ownership, in conjunction with policies. Work Units or Roles would be
                    connected or allowed to complete certain actions based on additional qualifier
                    for ownership.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>P</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="package">
            <glossterm>Package</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A grouping of TIPPs offered by a supplier under particular terms.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="page">
            <glossterm>Page</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ability for a patron/borrower to ask that an item not on loan be retrieved
                    and either placed on hold (for the user to pick-up at a specified location for
                    checkout) or be delivered (the item is retrieved, checked out, and then
                    routed/physically delivered to the user).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="patron">
            <glossterm>Patron</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An individual who has some level of library privileges. A person with access
                    to a library (virtual or physical) and identified as belonging to a specific
                    group, e.g., faculty, undergraduate, unaffiliated, etc. Each group may have
                    different levels of service privileges, e.g., faculty have indefinite loan
                    periods when borrowing items, undergraduates can borrow for 90 days, etc. Terms
                    such as "patron", "library user", "user", or "borrower" are often used
                    interchangeably.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="patronBody">
            <glossterm>Patron body</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Main part of an OLE patron record containing data NOT in a patron
                    component.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="patronComponent">Patron Component</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="patronComponent">
            <glossterm>Patron component</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Repeatable segments of an OLE patron record: (1) address; (2) affiliation; (3)
                    barcode; (4) identifier; (5) borrower type; and (6) note. Other information is
                    in the patron body.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="patronBody">Patron Body</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="affiliation">Affiliation (patron)</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="patronInfrastructure">
            <glossterm>Patron Infrastructure type</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a generic way to refer to borrower type, address type, affiliation type,
                    identifier type, and note type. This is again not a term that should be exposed
                    to end users but is useful to talk about all the types together. Right now they
                    all have quite a bit in common although as OLE becomes more sophisticated they
                    will vary from each other more.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="paymentRequest">
            <glossterm>Payment Request/ Invoice</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Vendor Invoices are processed thru an OLE Payment Request, and represent money
                    owed/due to a Vendor for products or services.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="pCard">
            <glossterm>P-Card</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Synonym for credit card, also called procard</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="permissions">
            <glossterm>Permissions</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Permissions represent fine grained actions that can be mapped to functionality
                    within a given system. Permissions are scoped to Namespace which roughly
                    correlate to modules or sections of functionality within a given system. (A
                    permission says something a role's users can do)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Periodical</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="serial">Serial</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="person">
            <glossterm>Person</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE entity, a person is an individual represented in the environment. A few
                    examples of persons include a user of a resource (such as a library user), a
                    creator of a resource (such as an author), or a creator of metadata (such as a
                    library staff member).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Phase 1</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A series of code releases that satisfy the requirements of all partners for a
                    minimum deployment and migration to production of OLE by the end of December
                    2017. See definition document: <link
                        xlink:href="https://docs.google.com/a/kuali.org/document/d/156f3ubrKXxe3GweKConaZVioXgQOMe5EQJ-3l1MOnDA/edit?usp=sharing"
                        >https://docs.google.com/a/kuali.org/document/d/156f3ubrKXxe3GweKConaZVioXgQOMe5EQJ-3l1MOnDA/edit?usp=sharing</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Pickup</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Indicates that patron will come to the library to retrieve items set aside on
                    his behalf.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="piece">
            <glossterm>Piece</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A component of an item, e.g., a CD jewel case of 3 CDs would typically be
                    treated as 1 item with 3 pieces.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="item">Item</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="platform">
            <glossterm>Platform</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An interface that administers or delivers electronic resources content, or
                    provides a route to the content, to the user. A single publisher may have
                    multiple platforms, eg: Elsevier has Science Direct, Scopus, and
                    Compendex/Engineering Village. The platforms of one publisher may or may not be
                    integrated in one administrative site.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Platform Administrative Site</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Many platforms provide librarians with an interface for managing and
                    customizing the display and other attributes of their platform. This interface
                    (accessed via a URL) allows librarians to enter their institution’s IP ranges,
                    input their link resolver URL, manage the look and feel of the platform for
                    their users, gather usage stats, etc. The interface is password
                    protected.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="platformProviderName">
            <glossterm>Platform Provider Name</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Name of company that hosts the platform, eg: EbscoHost, Proquest, Gale
                    Cengage</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Platform Software</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The underlying architecture that runs a platform. A platform may belong to
                    Oxford University Press, but run on the Highwire platform software. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="pluggableFramework">
            <glossterm>Pluggable Framework</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE infrastructural middleware that allows separately installable software
                    modules to interact seamlessly in the environment. This provides for increasing
                    functionality of the system with components that are not built-in.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="POJO">
            <glossterm>POJO</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>POJO is an acronym for Plain Old Java Object. The name is used to emphasize
                    that a given object is an ordinary Java object and not a special object.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="polaris">
            <glossterm>Polaris Library Systems</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Library automation solutions. See <link xlink:href="www.gisinfosystems.com/"
                        >www.gisinfosystems.com/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="policyBusinessRules">
            <glossterm>Policy/Business Rules</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE infrastructural middleware, Policy/Business Rules modifies workflows based
                    on locally defined policies</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="predictionPattern">
            <glossterm>Prediction pattern</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A set of descriptive data (enumeration, chronology, frequency) enabling a
                    system to generate a listing of future issues.of a serial. This data enables a
                    system to show an operator the next expected issue which in turn allows for a
                    quick and easy method of recording receipt of each issue.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="preDisbursementProcessor">
            <glossterm>Pre-Disbursement Processor</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A KFS module and core component that receives data from systems that need to
                    make disbursements and outputs a data file that can be sent to a check writer or
                    formatted and sent to a bank for Automated Clearing House (ACH) direct deposits.
                    Generates ledger entries when appropriate. (for example, to relieve liabilities
                    when making a disbursement against a KFS Payment Request document)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="preOrderRequest">
            <glossterm>Pre-order request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A collection of metadata describing a title (in any format) requested by
                    library staff or outside users for addition to the library's collection.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="preOrderRequestDocument">
            <glossterm>Pre-Order Request Document</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A Kuali OLE document containing a pre-order request's metadata along with data
                    concerning the request type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="preserveConserve">
            <glossterm>Preserve/Conserve (Entity) Resource (Manage)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that tracks the preservation and curation of an entity that needs
                    attention in regard to preservation/conservation activities including
                    evaluation, binding, repair, reformat, replacement, and withdraw. Access and
                    descriptive metadata may be updated in this process. Determine whether the item
                    should be relocated to archives/special collections.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="primaryDelegation">
            <glossterm>Primary Delegation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Delegator turns over full authority to the Delegate. The Action Requests
                    for the Delegator only appear in the Action List of the Primary Delegate. The
                    Delegation must be registered in KEW or KIM to be in effect.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="principal">
            <glossterm>Principal</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KIM, a principal reflects a method that an entity uses to log in to the
                    system, for instance a username/password pair. One entity can have multiple
                    principals when a single individual has more than one way to authenticate
                    themselves. We will not use principals for patrons at all.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="printing">
            <glossterm>Printing</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Printing slips as part of transfers, sending items to bindery, shelf
                    preparation.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="privileges">
            <glossterm>Privileges</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Library services (many related to circulation) available to users, e.g., the
                    ability to borrow items for periods of time; recall checked out items; order
                    copies of library materials; gain access to a library building; etc. Certain
                    services may be restricted to certain categories or types of users.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="process">
            <glossterm>Process</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a loosely coupled series of operations or activities that achieve a library
                    business goal.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="processed">
            <glossterm>Processed</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing status indicating that the document has no pending approval requests
                    but still has one or more pending acknowledgement requests.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="projectManager">
            <glossterm>Project Manager</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A project manager is the person responsible for accomplishing the stated
                    project objectives. Key project management responsibilities include creating
                    clear and attainable project objectives, building the project requirements, and
                    managing the constraints of the project management triangle, which are cost,
                    time, scope, and quality.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="proposition">
            <glossterm>Proposition</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, rules consist of propositions and actions.  A proposition is made up
                    of terms and facts.  KRMS supports three main types of propositions:</para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Simple Propositions - a proposition of the form "lhs op rhs" where
                            lhs=left-hand side, rhs=right-hand side, and op=operator</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Compound Propositions - a proposition consisting of more than one
                            simple proposition and a boolean algebra operator (AND, OR) between each
                            of the simple propositions</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Custom Propositions - a proposition which can optionally be
                            parameterized by some set of values. Evaluation logic is implemented "by
                            hand" and returns true or false.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <glossseealso otherterm="rule">Rule</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="term">Term</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="fact">Fact</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="proxy">
            <glossterm>Proxy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A system that acts as an intermediary for authenticating authorized users
                    accessing licensed electronic resources from an IP address outside of the
                    registered institutional IP ranges.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="publicFacingService">
            <glossterm>Public-facing Service</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Any service/system that allows public users to query a library's database.
                    Examples include discovery layers (such as VuFind) and Z39.50.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="publicReceipt">
            <glossterm>Public receipt</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In the Receipt History section of the Serials Receiving record, these are
                    issues that have the "Public Display" checkbox checked</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="PO">
            <glossterm>Purchase order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A document describing an entity to be bought or licensed along with vendor,
                    fund, order type and other related data; OLE uses an adaptation of the Kuali
                    Financial System's purchase order.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Q</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="QAManager">
            <glossterm>Quality Assurance Manager</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Quality assurance (QA) refers to the planned and systematic activities
                    implemented in a quality system so that quality requirements for a product or
                    service will be fulfilled.[1] It is the systematic measurement, comparison with
                    a standard, monitoring of processes and an associated feedback loop that confers
                    error prevention.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>R</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="RDA">
            <glossterm>RDA (Resource Description and Access)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Designed for the digital world and an expanding universe of metadata users,
                    RDA is the new, unified cataloging standard - an evolution of the cataloging
                    principles from AACR2, Second Edition with rules carried over or adapted to the
                    RDA model.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="RDBMS">
            <glossterm>RDBMS (Relational Database Management System)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Relational Database Management System (RDBMS) is a database model that
                    stores information about both the data and how it is related. Relationships
                    exist both among the columns within a table and among the tables. Each database
                    is a collection of related tables.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="RDF">
            <glossterm>RDF (Resource Description Framework)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A standard model for data interchange on the Web.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="recallRequest">
            <glossterm>Recall Request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ability for a patron/borrower to ask that an item currently on loan to
                    another patron/borrower be returned. In most libraries, a recall request
                    abbreviates the loan period for the current borrower who typically receives a
                    notice with the new due date/time. In addition, fine rates applied for late
                    return of recalled items are often higher than fine rates for late returns of an
                    item without a recall request.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="holdRequest">Hold Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="receiveResource">
            <glossterm>Receive Resource (Acquire)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where a resource or service is received in response to request, for
                    example an order request, a request for a service or resource, a gift.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Recurring Order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A purchase order with the “Type of Recurring Payment” field populated.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="referenceModel">
            <glossterm>Reference Model</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>provides an abstract view of how the environment functions and the
                    relationships between the various components, entities, and middleware. The
                    reference model provides a foundation upon which the architecture of the system,
                    and the concrete details, will be built.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="reformatResource">
            <glossterm>Reformat Resource (Manage)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where resource is selected, retrieved and converted; content is
                    duplicated; access and descriptive metadata are updated.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="reformating">
            <glossterm>Reformating</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Converting a document from one format to another without changing its
                    content</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="relais">
            <glossterm>Relais</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Relais International provides highly sophisticated systems and software to
                    automate and streamline operations in traditional ILL, Document Delivery and
                    consortial resource sharing services as well as for services supporting on
                    campus delivery and distance education programs</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="renew">
            <glossterm>Renew(al)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>For circulation, the process/policy for extending the loan period of a
                    borrowed library item. For acquisition, the process/policy for paying for a
                    resource that is obtained on a periodic basis (e.g., continuing a subscription
                    to a journal; obtaining access to an electronic database for a specified length
                    of time; etc.).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="renewalEresource">
            <glossterm>Renewal (for E-Resources)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which by a library extends its subscription to a resource to
                    cover the next subscription period. Typically done in yearly increments.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="replacementFee">
            <glossterm>Replacement fee</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>When a borrowed library item is not returned after a series of overdue
                    notices, the system automatically creates and sends a replacement fee borrower
                    bill to the borrower. The fee is either a default value defined in the
                    circulation policy sets OR is the price entered in the item-level record.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="reportManagement">
            <glossterm>Report Management</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a 3rd party component to OLE that aids in the creating, viewing, and printing
                    of reports. The software may provide an interface that will assist with the
                    selection and extraction of data. This component may communicate with OLE
                    through the report manager in the OLE middleware.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="reportManager">
            <glossterm>Report Manager</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE infrastructural middleware reporting application that provides a
                    connection between OLE, its data, and 3rd party report management software. The
                    report manager may assist with the selection and extraction of data according to
                    a particular type of report, as specified through the 3rd party report
                    management software or through the policy/business rules middleware in
                    OLE.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="repository">
            <glossterm>Repository</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>the OLE middleware that provides a registry of services. The repository
                    manages the services to support their development, discovery, and use.
                    Information about the services can be found here which could assist potential
                    users with determining whether a service will meet their particular need, who
                    maintains that service, etc.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="repositoryManagement">
            <glossterm>Repository Management</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE 3rd party component that performs import, storage and basic integrity
                    checks and preservation of entities stored in a repository.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="request">
            <glossterm>Request</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The ability of a library user/borrower to ask for services relating to the
                    retrieval, loan or copying of an item in the library's collections. Such
                    requests are now typically submitted online through a public interface that must
                    interact with the library's "back office" system. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="recallRequest">Recall Request</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="holdRequest">Hold Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="requestExpirationDate">
            <glossterm>Request Expiration Date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The date at which the hold will expire for a patron.  The date is equal to X
                    days after the hold notice was sent (as defined in the Circulation Desk
                    maintenance document) and calculated when hold notice batch processes are run.
                    The date is editable from the request screen by staff.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="requestService">
            <glossterm>Request Service (Deliver, MUR)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where resource is requested from a resource provider or data source,
                    or where a user initiates a request for service. The process will take into
                    account whether the resource or service is available and can be requested by the
                    user based on access and use policies.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="requestor">
            <glossterm>Requestor</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A library user who submits a request for the library to purchase a title,
                    recall a checked out item, page an item on the shelf, etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="patron">Patron</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="REQ">
            <glossterm>Requisition</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A pre-order document for a title being considered for acquisition as submitted
                    by a library user or library staff using various input methods (e.g., submitting
                    a Web form, manual keying, etc.) Default workflow is for a requisition to be
                    approved by a selector and, upon supply of information such as vendor, fund,
                    etc., be transformed into a purchase order. Selectors may also decide against
                    acquisition and cancel the requisition with notice to the original
                    requestor.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="resource">
            <glossterm>Resource</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an OLE entity, a resource is an item that may be collected and/or made
                    available by an organization. Common examples of resources include books,
                    journals, maps, and websites</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Retired TIPP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A TIPP is retired when it no longer has any content remaining in a Package.
                    The retired status allows users to see that the TIPP used to be part of a
                    certain package, but is no longer available.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="TIPP">TIPP</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="return">
            <glossterm>Return</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The process by which the system: removes the temporary linkage between an item
                    loaned by the library to a patron; calculates any overdue fines or penalties to
                    be charged to the patron; and resets the item status to indicate its next state
                    (e.g., "not checked out", "in transit", "on hold", etc.). Synonyms: Check-in,
                    discharge</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="rightsManagement">
            <glossterm>Rights Management</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where information regarding rights of entities is collected, stored,
                    and updated. For example, the license terms of an entity that is acquired are
                    reviewed, approved, and retained. Rights information is consulted and
                    disseminated as necessary, for example, a resource that has been requested is
                    checked for terms of access and preconditions of use. Rights management may be
                    performed by an OLE component or 3rd party component.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="roleQualifier">
            <glossterm>Role Qualifier/Parameter</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>OLE Roles or Groups will be extended to include optional qualifiers or
                    parameters on applied permissions. A Role or Group can continue with no
                    qualifiers, or multiple.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="rolesPerms">
            <glossterm>Roles- Permissions</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>We can apply access, use, permissions at system, organization, group, role, or
                    user level, so that users can belong to different groups with different access,
                    permissions, or actually responsibilities/assignments in workflow. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="routeLog">
            <glossterm>Route Log</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Displays information about the routing of a document. The Route Log is usually
                    accessed from either the Action List or a Document Search. It displays general
                    document information about the document and a detailed list of Actions Taken and
                    pending Action Requests for the document. The Route Log can be considered an
                    audit trail for a document.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="routeStatus">
            <glossterm>Route Status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The status of a document in the course of its routing:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approved: These documents have been approved by all required reviewers
                            and are waiting additional postprocessing.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Cancelled: These documents have been stopped. The document's initiator
                            can 'Cancel' it before routing begins or a reviewer of the document can
                            cancel it after routing begins. When a document is cancelled, routing
                            stops; it is not sent to another Action List. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Disapproved: These documents have been disapproved by at least one
                            reviewer. Routing has stopped for these documents.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Enroute: Routing is in progress on these documents and an action
                            request is waiting for someone to take action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Exception: A routing exception has occurred on this document. Someone
                            from the Exception Workgroup for this Document Type must take action on
                            this document, and it has been sent to the Action List of this
                            workgroup.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Final: All required approvals and all acknowledgements have been
                            received on these documents. No changes are allowed to a document that
                            is in Final status.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Initiated: A user or a process has created this document, but it has
                            not yet been routed to anyone's Action List.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Processed: These documents have been approved by all required users,
                            and is completed on them. They may be waiting for Acknowledgements. No
                            further action is needed on these documents.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Saved: These documents have been saved for later work. An author
                            (initiator) can save a document before routing begins or a reviewer can
                            save a document before he or she takes action on it. When someone saves
                            a document, the document goes on that person's Action List.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="routing">
            <glossterm>Routing an Item</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Libraries route items from one circulation desk to another when an item is
                    received at one circulation desk but should be shelved by another.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="RSS">
            <glossterm>RSS/Atom</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivery: RSS ( Really Simple Syndication) is a family of web feed formats
                    used to publish frequently updated works- XML. The Atom Syndication Format is an
                    XML language used for web feeds, while the Atom Publishing Protocol (AtomPub or
                    APP) is a simple HTTP-based protocol for creating and updating web
                    resources</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="rule">
            <glossterm>Rule</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, a rule contains a proposition and an action.  Rules are the policy
                    set within the system.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="policyBusinessRules">Policy/Business Rules</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="proposition">Proposition</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="action">Action</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="rulesEngine">
            <glossterm>Rules Engine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="policyBusinessRules">Policy/Business Rules</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>S</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="sakai">
            <glossterm>Sakai</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Open source application to support technology-enabled teaching, learning,
                    research and collaboration in academic institutions. See <link
                        xlink:href="http://sakaiproject.org/">http://sakaiproject.org/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="saved">
            <glossterm>Saved</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A routing status indicating the document has been started but not yet
                    completed or routed. The Save action allows the initiator of a document to save
                    their work and close the document. The document may be retrieved from the
                    initiator's action list for completion and routing at a later time.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="scheduleEvent">
            <glossterm>Schedule Event (Acquire, MUR, Rice)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that manages the scheduling of events based on policy implemented by
                    the workflow engine. Provides check interval and deadline for certain actions
                    such as claim, audit, renew, review, deliver.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SCONUL">
            <glossterm>SCONUL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The SCONUL effort is currently focused on gathering use cases with an eye
                    towards requirements for Electronic Resource Management in July 2011. David Kay
                    is involved in OLE due to the alignment of our projects, the potential benefits
                    to both projects if we work towards a common framework (built on Kuali Rice, KFS
                    and OLE), and the sharing of process, resources, and requirements across our
                    projects. This is a JISC-funded (Higher education funding agency in the UK)
                    SCONUL-managed (HE Academic Library Council in the UK) project to develop a
                    national academic library system that addresses many of the efforts of Kuali
                    OLE</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="secondaryDelegation">
            <glossterm>Secondary Delegation</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The Secondary Delegate acts as a temporary backup Delegator who acts with the
                    same authority as the primary Approver/the Delegator when the Delegator is not
                    available. Documents appear in the Action Lists of both the Delegator and the
                    Delegate. When either acts on the document, it disappears from both Action
                    Lists.</para>
                <para>Secondary Delegation is often configured for a range of dates and it must be
                    registered in KEW or KIM to be in effect.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="selectEntity">
            <glossterm>Select Entity</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>describes the processes where metadata for an entity that has been selected
                    for acquisition or trial, either permanently or temporarily, are created or
                    obtained.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Select- Delete</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="deleteMetadata">Delete Metadata</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Select-Approve/Reject</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>New-</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Select-Create</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="createMetadata">Create Metadata</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Select-Modify/update/use</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="modifyMetadata">Modify Metadata</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Select-Obtain</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="obtainMetadata">Obtain Metadata</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="selector">
            <glossterm>Selector</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a library staff member with authority to purchase titles for a library's
                    collection.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="separateCopyReport">
            <glossterm>Separate Copy Report</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An OLE Instance which includes information about a single Copy only.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="copy">Copy</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="OLEInstance">OLE Instance</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="serial">
            <glossterm>Serial</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A serial is a publication (in any format, most often print, microform or
                    electronic) that is issued in successive parts (issues); serials include
                    publications commonly referred to as magazines, newspapers, periodicals,
                    journals, etc. A serial is usually published at intervals (i.e., a frequency,
                    e.g,. quarterly, weekly, daily, etc.) with each issue often (but not always)
                    identified by a number (i.e., enumeration, e.g., v. 7, no 1) and/or date (i.e.,
                    chronology, e.g., July 2009). Some serials have an irregular or unknown
                    frequency and may also lack enumeration or chronology but are, nevertheless,
                    considered serials. Enumeration and chronology can have multiple levels, each
                    with a descriptive caption used for display purposes.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="subscription">Subscription</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="caption">Caption</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="enumeration">Enumeration</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="chronology">Chronlogy</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="serialClaim">
            <glossterm>Serial claim</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="claim">claim</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="series">
            <glossterm>Series</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A group of titles, usually on the same or related topics, issued under the
                    same name (i.e., a series title) over a period of time. Each individual title
                    may (or may not) have a series volume number and often has its own distinct
                    title in addition to the series name. E.g., Lecture Notes in Mathematics volume
                    345 is the title "Proceedings of a Conference on Operator Theory, Dalhousie
                    University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, April 13 and 14th, 1973". In many cases,
                    libraries create records to allow users to find series volumes by either the
                    series title/number AND by the individual title of a single volume in the
                    series. These are called "analyzed series" or "analytics".</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="seriesHoldingRecord">
            <glossterm>Series Holding Record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A holdings record for a monographic series (distinguished from a holdings
                    record for an individual work in the series.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="analyticHoldingRecord">Analytics Holdings
                    Record</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SERU">
            <glossterm>SERU</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Shared Electronic Resource Understanding (SERU) - licensing agreements service
                    between libraries and publishers</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="service">
            <glossterm>Service</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a well-defined, reusable set of operations, services are independent software
                    pieces that are the building blocks used to assemble library business processes
                    in OLE.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="serviceMediator">
            <glossterm>Service Mediator</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>as part of the OLE middleware, the service mediator aids communication between
                    system-level service consumers and service providers. As consumers request
                    services, the mediator negotiates between the consumer and the provider to
                    manage the service request and its delivery.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SOA">
            <glossterm>Service Oriented Architecture (SOA)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>the design approach that will be used to develop OLE, Service Oriented
                    Architecture provides for loosely coupled, reusable services, and methods for
                    allowing different functionality and communicate with other systems.applications
                    to exchange data. By using SOA design architecture, OLE will describe a system
                    that is can add new</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="serviceTaxonomy">
            <glossterm>Service Taxonomy</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an index and classification of the services used in OLE. The taxonomy provides
                    definitions of the services, helping to build a common and accepted language
                    among OLE users.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="shelflist">
            <glossterm>Shelflist</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A file of bibliographic records arranged in the same order as the
                    corresponding materials on a library's shelves.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="shelflisting">
            <glossterm>Shelflisting</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Arranging library materials within an existing collection, normally by author;
                    and determining the book number and other additions to the classification number
                    necessary to create a unique number for each item. Shelflisting is also the
                    activity of documenting the holdings of a collection as to location, volumes,
                    and copies, providing an inventory of the collections (from: LC Classification
                    and Shelflisting Manual, 2008).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="shelfPrep">
            <glossterm>Shelf Prep</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Physical preparations of tangible library materials, that may include standard
                    cataloging (barcode, call number, etc), plus physical preparation external to
                    OLE. May be managed via notifications or cataloging checklist in OLE.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="shibboleth">
            <glossterm>Shibboleth</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Proxy or Authentication: A standards based, open source software package for
                    web single sign-on across or within organizational boundaries. It allows sites
                    to make informed authorization decisions for individual access of protected
                    online resources in a privacy-preserving manner. <link
                        xlink:href="http://shibboleth.internet2.edu/"
                        >http://shibboleth.internet2.edu/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="singleSignOn">
            <glossterm>Single Sign On</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A mechanism for authenticating authorized users accessing licensed electronic
                    resources using a single log-in for accessing all applications (i.e.
                    Shibboleth)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SIP">
            <glossterm>SIP2</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Document and Resource Delivery: Standard Interchange Protocol 2 for library
                    automation. <link xlink:href="http://www.niso.org/workrooms/sip/"
                        >http://www.niso.org/workrooms/sip/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="sirsiDynix">
            <glossterm>SirsiDynix</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Commercial vendor of ILS systems Symphony,Unicorn and Horizon; discovery tool
                    Enterprise.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SKOS">
            <glossterm>SKOS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Content and Metadata</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SOAP">
            <glossterm>SOAP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>SOAP, originally defined as Simple Object Access Protocol, is a protocol
                    specification for exchanging structured information in the implementation of web
                    services in computer networks. It relies on XML information set for its message
                    format, and usually relies on other application layer protocols, most notably
                    Hypertext Transfer Protocol or Simple Mail Transfer Protocol, for message
                    negotiation and transmission. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SOLR">
            <glossterm>SOLR</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Solr is an open source enterprise search platform from the Apache Lucene
                    project. [Penn and other libraries are using Solr to develop library discovery
                    tools--AKA catalogs] <link xlink:href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr/"
                        >http://lucene.apache.org/solr/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="sourceHolding">
            <glossterm>sourceHolding</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>This section of the OLE Instance represents "specific" holdings information
                    entered according to some standard external to OLE. Examples are MARC holdings,
                    MODS holdings or any other format specific holdings.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="sourceRecord">
            <glossterm>Source record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Record from which another record receives data from.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SPARQL">
            <glossterm>SPARQL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: an RDF query language; its name is a recursive acronym that stands
                    for SPARQL Protocol and RDF Query Language</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SQL">
            <glossterm>SQL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Reporting: is a database computer language designed for managing data in
                    relational database management systems</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="SRU">
            <glossterm>SRU/SRW</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Discovery: SRU is a standard XML-focused search protocol for Internet search
                    queries, utilizing CQL (Contextual Query Language), a standard syntax for
                    representing queries. SRW is a variation of SRU. Messages are conveyed from
                    client to server, not by a URL, but instead using XML over HTTP via the W3C
                    recommendation SOAP, which specifies how to wrap an XML message within an XML
                    envelope.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="staff">
            <glossterm>Staff</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>For the purpose of OLE specs, Users or Staff may be used interchangeably to
                    denote authorized library staff or system users. Library SME's prefer the term
                    Staff or Operator, as in the library world, "users" is often construed as
                    synonymous with "patrons" or "users of the library". Synonyms: User, Staff,
                    Operator, (KIM) Person</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="standardNumber">
            <glossterm>Standard number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a numeric or alpha-numeric string with or without punctuation used as a unique
                    identifier for an item; some standard number types have established validation
                    rules, e.g., ISBN and ISSN.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="standingOrder">
            <glossterm>Standing order</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Standing orders are commitments from a library to purchase (sometimes after
                    approval) all titles from a provider that fit within a predestinated profile
                    (Author, subject, publisher, etc.) The titles to be sent from the provider are
                    often not known until they are received at the library. The library processes
                    each title as it is sent from the provider by describing it, receiving it, and
                    invoicing it. Unless discontinued, a standing order will be modified by year-end
                    so that it continues into each new fiscal year. Unlike subscription orders,
                    standing orders are "continued" as opposed to "renewed". A standing order may
                    also be called a blanket order.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="staffOnly">
            <glossterm>Staff Only</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A flag on record (bibliographic, holdings, item) that, when checked, marks the
                    record so it does not display in a public-facing service.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="status">
            <glossterm>Status</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>On an Action List; also known as Route Status. The current location of the
                    document in its routing path.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="routeStatus">Route Staus</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="subfield">
            <glossterm>Subfield</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The code used to separate pieces of information in the bibliographic record,
                    such as separating the title from the author: 245 04 |a The life and times of a
                    cataloger / |c Frieda B. Cataloger, where the "a" and "c" that proceed the
                    delimiter | are the subfield codes.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="submit">
            <glossterm>Submit</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow action button used by the initiator of a document to begin workflow
                    routing for that transaction. It moves the document (through workflow) to the
                    next level of approval. Once a document is submitted, it remains in 'ENROUTE'
                    status until all approvals have taken place.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="subscription">
            <glossterm>Subscription</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A subscription is an order for a title that is published in parts over time,
                    often (but not always) on a set schedule, where each part often (but not always)
                    has a specific numeric and/or chronological identifiers. One can subscribe to a
                    journal for a specific period of time (e.g., a year's subscription to the New
                    Yorker) or to a package of e-journals licensed for a specific period of time
                    (e.g., EBSCOHost Business Source Complete). Subscriptions are renewed (typically
                    annually) to ensure continuous receipt/access.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Subscription start date; subscription end date</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Beginning and end dates of the term of covered by the most recently paid
                    order.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="suDoc">
            <glossterm>SuDoc (Superintendent of Documents) Classification/Call Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A system to organize publications of the U.S. government based on the issuing
                    agency. Call numbers derived from this system describe the agency, a subunit,
                    type of publication, title, etc., e.g., HE 3.3:15/2 where HE is the agency; 3 is
                    a bulletin, .3 is the title and 15/2 is the volume and issue number.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="callNumber">Call Number</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Superintendent of Documents Classification/Call Number</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="suDoc">SuDoc (Superintendent of Documents)
                        Classification/Call Number</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="superuser">
            <glossterm>Superuser</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user who has been given special permission to perform Superuser Approvals
                    and other Superuser actions on documents of a certain Document Type.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="supervisorOverride">
            <glossterm>Supervisor Override</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A supervisor override allows an operator to approve a loan when another
                    operator does not have sufficient permission to approve it.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="supplyEntity">
            <glossterm>Supply Entity (Deliver)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process where an appropriate entity is supplied subject to conditions or
                    constraints on use.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>T</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="talis">
            <glossterm>Talis</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Commercial vendor of ILS system Talis Alto and discovery tool Talis
                    Prism.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="targetRecord">
            <glossterm>Target record</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Record (Bibliographic Description or OLE Instance) to which a record (OLE
                    Instance or Item Description) is being transferred.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="term">
            <glossterm>Term</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>In KRMS, a named variable used to build propositions.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="proposition">Proposition</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="TIPP">
            <glossterm>TIPP</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>(from GOKb) An electronic resource distinguished by a unique combination of
                    Title Instance, Package, and Platform. It represents, at the most granular
                    level, the resource a library has purchased.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="title">
            <glossterm>Title</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An identifying name assigned to an intellectual entity, e.g., a book, DVD,
                    map, serial, music recording, etc.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="format">Format</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="copy">Copy</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="item">Item</glossseealso>
                <glossseealso otherterm="uniformTitle">Uniform Title</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="titleInstance">
            <glossterm>Title instance</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>(from GOKb) A publication distinguished by a unique combination of title,
                    publisher, and ISSN.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Title-level</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>To request any one of multiple copies of a work where there are mulitple item
                    records attached to a bibliographic record.</para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="request">Request</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="trackEvent">
            <glossterm>Track Event (Acquire, MUR, Rice)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>process that enables tracking the status of an event, a resource, a request,
                    or a task at any given point in the workflow.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="transfer">
            <glossterm>Transfer</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A change in the physical custody of archival materials from one location or
                    agency to another, usually without a corresponding change of legal ownership and
                    responsibility. In OLE, Users may move Instances to other Bibs; Items to other
                    Instances. Global edits can provide functionality for relocating or moving
                    (physically) the actual Items, updating Location information. Transfers are
                    subject to document ownership and status rules.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="trial">
            <glossterm>Trial</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Access to a particular e-resource on a particular platform for a limited time
                    period, usually 30 days, to evaluate an e-resource.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="triggers">
            <glossterm>Triggers</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>When writing specifications, triggers describe the event(s) that cause the
                    user story to be initiated</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>U</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="UI">
            <glossterm>UI</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>User Interface, also GUI (graphical user interface).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="UIF">
            <glossterm>UIF</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Built upon a rich JQuery library of Standards as part of KRAD, UIF (User
                    Interface Framework), includes, Light boxes, Messages and Notifications,
                    Progressive Disclosure, Client Side Validation, Table Tools, Themes and AJAX
                    Enabled Fields and are no longer limited to the vertical tab layout of
                    KNS.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="uniformTitle">
            <glossterm>Uniform Title</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>The standardized form of a title that has been issued in different versions
                    using many variations of the original title. For example, "Huck Finn", "Mark
                    Twain's Huckleberry Finn" and "Huckleberry Finn" all share the same content,
                    i.e., the work written by Mark Twain. When creating metadata for any one of
                    these titles, a librarian would include the standard form of the title (in this
                    case, it's "Adventures of Huckleberry Finn") thus allowing users to find a
                    listing of all versions in a library's collection. Uniform titles are most often
                    established for literary classics; musical compositions; and religious texts
                    (the Bible and the Koran being the most famous examples of the latter). Uniform
                    titles are established in the U.S. by the Library of Congress (and its various
                    cataloging partners) and are available to libraries via services such as
                    OCLC.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="URL">
            <glossterm>URL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Uniform resource locator: a web address; a character string that refers to an
                    internet resource</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="useCase">
            <glossterm>Use Case</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an example that illustrates the potential application of OLE, its components,
                    and its processes. Use cases might be abstract or concrete. They help provide
                    meaning to the functionalities of OLE. </para>
                <glossseealso otherterm="userStory">User Story</glossseealso>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="user">
            <glossterm>User</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="staff">Staff</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>User Interface</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="GUI">GUI</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="userStory">
            <glossterm>User Story</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A user story is a software system requirement formulated as one or more
                    sentences in the everyday or business language of the user. User stories are
                    used with Agile software development methodologies for the specification of
                    requirements (together with acceptance tests).</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>V</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="variableField">
            <glossterm>Variable Field</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>MARC fields for which the length of the field varies, as the length is
                    dependent upon the data that is entered into the field. All fields except 00X
                    are variable data fields. (see <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.loc.gov/marc/96principl.html#eight"
                        >http://www.loc.gov/marc/96principl.html#eight</link>)</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="vendor">
            <glossterm>Vendor</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>an organization or individual supplying materials for purchase, exchange or at
                    no cost; KFS term is "supplier".  </para>
            </glossdef>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Companies or non-profits businesses with which a library has a business
                    relationship.  They may play one or many roles in the e-resource management
                    world.  Eg: Ebsco Publishing licenses its databases and hosts (on their own
                    platform) those same databases. However, they do not bill direct to
                    libraries.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="VRA">
            <glossterm>VRA</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Content and Metadata; Visual Resources Association, a library association for
                    image media professionals, or, Video Recordings Act 1984</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="VTLS">
            <glossterm>VTLS</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Commercial vendor of ILS system Virtua</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>W</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="webServices">
            <glossterm>Web Services</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a software component that supports machine-to-machine transactions over a
                    network, in particular, over the Internet.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="wildCard">
            <glossterm>Wild Card</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A character that may be substituted for any of a defined subset of all
                    possible characters.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Work Location</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="workUnit">Work Unit</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="workMark">
            <glossterm>Work Mark</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A letter (or combination of letters) placed after the Cutter number to help
                    maintain alphabetical order on a library's shelves and to create a unique call
                    number for each work. The work mark is usually the first letter of the first
                    important word in the title.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="workUnit">
            <glossterm>Work Unit</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A location or departmental, or organizational field, used to as an attribute
                    or match point between documents and Roles/Permissions. The Work Unit will be
                    compared between a Document and as a qualifier on a Role, in order for
                    Permissions/Policy to designate what staff can perform which actions on a
                    document. Work units can be designated with parent-child relationships, to allow
                    easier creation of roles/permissions across work units (one parent work unit can
                    include or cover multiple child work units). Note: while locations hierarchy
                    could be replicated for Work units, it is more granular than work units or
                    document ownership designations may need to be. Work units and document
                    ownership will frequently be at the Library level.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="workflow">
            <glossterm>Workflow</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>a series of activities that involve people, business processes, and software
                    that achieve a library business goal</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>Workflow Engine</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>See <link linkend="businessProcessEngine">Business Process
                    Engine</link>.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="worldCat">
            <glossterm>WorldCat</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Online catalog representing holdings of more than 72,000 libraries
                    worldwide.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="worldCatSelection">
            <glossterm>WorldCat Selection</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Allows selectors of new materials at a library to view notification records
                    from multiple materials vendors in one central system and access participating
                    vendors' systems directly from WorldCat Selection.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="WSDL">
            <glossterm>WSDL</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>WSDL is an acronym for Web Services Description Language. It is an XML-based
                    interface definition language that is used for describing the functionality
                    offered by a web service. The acronym is also used for any specific WSDL
                    description of a web service which provides a machine-readable description of
                    how the service can be called, what parameters it expects and what data
                    structures it returns. </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>X</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="XTwelve">
            <glossterm>X12</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>"The Accredited Standards Committee (ASC) X12, chartered by the American
                    National Standards Institute in 1979, develops electronic data interchange (EDI)
                    standards and related documents for national and global markets." <link
                        xlink:href="http://www.x12.org/">http://www.x12.org/</link></para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="XC">
            <glossterm>XC (eXtensible Catalog)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>An open source, user-centered, next generation software for libraries. It
                    comprises four software components that can be used independently to address a
                    particular need or combined to provide an end-to-end discovery system to connect
                    library users with resources.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="XHTML">
            <glossterm>XHTML</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivery: the next generation of HTML, compliant with XML standards</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="ISBNWebService">
            <glossterm>xISBN (Web service)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Use this Web service to retrieve a list of International Standard Book Numbers
                    (ISBNs) associated with a submitted ISBN, based on WorldCat information. Free
                    and subscription versions are available. The xISBN Web service supplies ISBNs
                    and other information associated with an individual intellectual work that is
                    represented in WorldCat. Submit an ISBN to this service, and it returns a list
                    of related ISBNs and selected metadata. Ideal for Web-enabled search
                    applications - such as library catalogs and online booksellers - and based on
                    associations made in the WorldCat database, xISBN enables an end user to link to
                    information about other versions of a source work</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="XML">
            <glossterm>XML</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Delivery: Extensible Markup Language (XML) is a set of rules for encoding
                    documents in machine-readable form</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry>
            <glossterm>XML ingester</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>A workflow function that allows you to browse for and upload XML data.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Y</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="YBP">
            <glossterm>YBP (Yankee Book Peddler)</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>YBP provides books and supporting collection management and technical services
                    to academic, research and special libraries around the world. Owned by Baker
                    &amp; Taylor.</para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
    <glossdiv>
        <title>Z</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="zotero">
            <glossterm>Zotero</glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para>Zotero [zoh-TAIR-oh] is a free, easy-to-use tool to help you collect,
                    organize, cite, and share your research sources. It lives right where you do
                    your work - in the web browser itself. <link xlink:href="http://www.zotero.org/"
                        >http://www.zotero.org/</link>
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
</glossary>
