<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    version="5.0" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_workflowOverviewAndKeyConcepts"/>OLE Workflow Overview and Key
        Concepts</title>
    <para role="Body Text"> The Kuali Enterprise Workflow (KEW) is a general-purpose, content-based
        electronic routing infrastructure or workflow engine. Its main purpose is to automate the
        routing of electronic documents (e-docs) to individuals and groups for approval, yet the KEW
        can also be used to orchestrate complex processes between business components and
        applications. Approval routing is based on institutional or departmental business rules and
        policies. A new routing option called PeopleFlow is also available from the KEW to provide a
        streamlined way to view and update routing actions.  This section provides an overview of
        KEW as it relates to the OLE. </para>
    <section>
        <title>KEW Overview</title>
        <para role="Normal"> Kuali OLE uses the KEW to handle the routing of electronic documents
            for actions such as approvals, acknowledgments and FYI notifications. Although much KEW
            functionality works behind the scenes, the <emphasis role="bold">action list</emphasis>
            and <emphasis role="bold">doc search</emphasis> buttons and the <emphasis role="bold"
                >Workflow Admin</emphasis> submenu options on the OLE <emphasis role="bold"
                >Admin</emphasis> tabs are part of the KEW. These workflow options allow you to
            access, act on, and search for many types of e-docs from various functional areas from a
            single location. Additionally, the <emphasis role="bold">Route Log</emphasis> tab on OLE
            e-docs is a workflow feature that allows you to follow the progress of given documents
            through the approval process. </para>
        <note>
            <para> Many facets of Workflow (such as the route nodes that define how a given document
                type routes) are stored in workflow process definition files for the various
                document types. These files can be easily modified to alter the default routing of
                documents in your OLE implementation, but doing so requires a technical resource and
                as such is beyond the scope of this documentation. </para>
        </note>
        <para> OLE Workflow relies on Kuali Identity Management (KIM) to specify when workflow
            action requests are to be generated and who should take action to fulfill them.
            Functional users employ the KIM interfaces to make changes that affect the routing of
            documents. </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                <link
                    xlink:href="https://wiki.kuali.org/display/OLE/OLE+Demonstration+Library#OLEDemonstrationLibrary-KIMfunctions%28roles,permissions,responsibilities%29"
                    >KFS Knowledge Transfer - KIM functions (roles permissions,
                    responsibilities)</link> was a video conference about roles and workflows. It
                also contains a visual demonstration on responsibilities. </para>
        </note>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>PeopleFlow Overview</title>
        <para>PeopleFlow is a new Kuali Rice feature that Kuali OLE is now using for License
            Requests and Electronic Resources. PeopleFlows are a prioritized list of people to send
            requests to. Essentially, it's like a mini people-based workflow that doesn't require
            you to specify a KEW node in the document type for each individual who might need to
            approve or be notified. You can define "Stops" in a PeopleFlow, where everything in the
            same stop proceeds in parallel, but all must be done within the stop before proceeding
            to the next stop.</para>
        <para>You can call/execute a PeopleFlow from within a KEW workflow node directly, or you can
            invoke the Kuali Rules Management System (KRMS - a common rules engine for defining
            decision logic, commonly refereed to as business rules) engine from an application and
            any PeopleFlows that get selected during rule execution, defined in a KRMS agenda, will
            be called. In this way, you can integrate business rules across applications and
            workflows.</para>
        <para>The same PeopleFlow that defines a routing order among a set of persons, groups or
            roles can be called by KRMS rules, with the KRMS rules defining which type of request to
            pass to the PeopleFlow (for example, an "approval" routing action or a
            "notification").</para>
        <note>
            <para> For information about creating and managing PeopleFlows in OLE, see <link
                xlink:href="../../../webhelp/ADMIN/content/ch05s02.html">PeopleFlow</link> in the <link
                    xlink:href="../../../webhelp/ADMIN/index.html"><emphasis role="italic">Guide to OLE System
                        Administration Functions.</emphasis></link>
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title><anchor xml:id="_routeLevelAndWorkflowRouting"/>Route Levels and Workflow
            Routing</title>
        <para> Documents route by progressing through a series of route levels (also called 'route
            nodes'). Many of the financial e-docs on the Select/Acquire menu, and other e-docs
            throughout OLE, support both pre-established workflow routing and ad hoc routing. Here
            is an example of the approval route nodes that a typical financial processing document
            passes through: </para>
        <para/>
        <para><inlinemediaobject>
                <alt>Routing of Financial Documents: Initiate > Fiscal Officer > Organization >
                    Special Condition > Record in the GL</alt>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-61.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </inlinemediaobject></para>
        <para/>
        <para> In workflow routing, a document's type (General Error Correction, Transfer of Funds,
            etc.) determines the route levels it passes through. Route nodes are defined by document
            type within the workflow process definition file. To view workflow process definitions
            in XML, use the <emphasis role="bold">export</emphasis> button on the Document Type
            Inquiry. </para>
        <para/>
        <para>
            <screenshot>
                <mediaobject>
                    <alt>Document Inquiry: Export button at the bottom of many OLE screens</alt>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-62.png" width="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para> You may need technical assistance to understand or modify a workflow process
            definition file. Given that assistance, the file can easily be modified to change a
            document's routing behavior. </para>
        <para> An easier view for functional users is located in the <emphasis role="bold">Routing
                &amp; IDM Doc Type</emphasis> (Routing and Identity Management Document Type
            Hierarchy) option in the <emphasis role="bold">Workflow Admin</emphasis> submenu on the
                <emphasis role="bold">Admin</emphasis> menu. </para>
        <para/>
        <para>
            <screenshot>
                <mediaobject>
                    <alt>Workflow Admin Submenu</alt>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-configuration.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para> The KEW arranges OLE document types in a hierarchical fashion, with some document
            types being 'parent' to the document types below them in the hierarchy. 'Child' document
            types inherit attributes from their parents. The Routing &amp; IDM Doc Type Hierarchy
            screen displays documents in their respective positions in this hierarchy and also
            displays the route nodes associated with each document type. Nodes are listed in the
            order in which the document progresses through them. </para>
        <para> The following example shows route nodes associated with the Transfer of Funds
            document type viewed through the  Routing &amp; IDM Doc Type Hierarchy. </para>
        <para/>
        <para>
            <screenshot>
                <mediaobject>
                    <alt>Route nodes on the Transfer of Funds Document Displayed in the Routing
                        &amp; IDM Doc Type Hierarchy</alt>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-63.png" width="100%"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
        </para>
        <para/>
        <section>
            <title>Typical Route Levels of the OLE financial documents</title>
            <note>
                <para> Routing and roles inherited from KFS continue to exist within OLE.  Many of
                    the route nodes remain listed but are passed over in OLE.  These options remain
                    available for institutions that wish to implement them. </para>
            </note>
            <para> Most, but not all, Kuali financial documents are able to progress through three
                route levels: account level, organization hierarchy, and special conditions. </para>
            <section>
                <title>Account Level Routing (Fiscal Officer)</title>
                <para> Each account in OLE is assigned a designated approver called a fiscal
                    officer. This individual is responsible for maintaining the fiscal integrity of
                    an account and is often one of the first approvers to review a document that
                    impacts the account. Most financial processing documents are routed to the
                    fiscal officer for each of the accounts identified in the document. For example,
                    Sue is the fiscal officer for account 1012300. All financial transactions
                    involving this account are routed to Sue for approval. </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Organization Review (Review Hierarchy) Routing </title>
                <para>Every account belongs to an organization. The organization develops customized
                    routing to appropriate roles based on criteria such as document type, dollar
                    amount and override code. This routing may take advantage of the Chart of
                    Accounts organization hierarchy, meaning that approvals are set up at different
                    levels in the organization hierarchy. A document proceeding through this
                    hierarchy routing might route to someone at the department level, then route to
                    someone else at this department's school or college.</para>
                <para>Organization hierarchy routing (corresponding to the
                    AccountingOrganizationHierarchy route node) is very flexible and may be
                    customized to be as simple or complex as needed. For example, it can be set up
                    to accommodate appropriate routing when the head of acquisitions wants to
                    approve every Transfer of Funds document over $1,000 that involves an account
                    reporting to his organization.</para>
                <para>Some documents without dollar amounts (such as account maintenance documents)
                    also use organization hierarchy routing. While technically distinct, this type
                    of routing functions exactly as described above without regard to dollar amount
                    or override code.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Special Conditions Routing</title>
                <para> Special condition routing is a blanket term for additional route levels that
                    might be triggered by various attributes of a transaction. Special conditions
                    often represent special administrative approvals that may be required. This
                    routing may be based on the type of document, attributes of the accounts being
                    used, or other attributes of the transaction. </para>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Examples of special conditions routing</emphasis></para>
                <informaltable border="1" class="MsoNormalTable"
                    style="border-collapse:collapse;mso-table-layout-alt:fixed;border:none;  mso-border-alt:solid black .5pt;mso-yfti-tbllook:160;mso-padding-alt:0in 5.4pt 0in 5.4pt;  mso-border-insideh:.5pt solid black;mso-border-insidev:.5pt solid black"
                    width="478">
                    <thead>
                        <tr>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                                <para>Routing Type</para>
                            </td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                                <para>E-Docs</para>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Content Routing</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">If the document's content is incomplete,
                                routes the document to an appropriate individual for
                                completion.</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Requisition</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Separation of Duties</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">If the amount of the document exceeds an
                                institutionally-defined threshold and there have been no approvers
                                other than the document initiator, routes the document to a defined
                                central approver.</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Requisition</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sub-Account Routing</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">If the document uses a sub-account and the
                                sub-account has a routing rule established, routes the document to
                                the person, group or role for which the rule has been
                                established.</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Purchasing related e-docs</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sub-Fund Routing</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">If a sub-fund derived from an account
                                appearing on the document has a routing rule established, the
                                document routes to the person, group or role for which the rule has
                                been established.</td>
                            <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Financial transactions e-docs</td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </informaltable>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_adHocRouting"/>Ad Hoc Routing</title>
                <para> Ad hoc routing allows a document initiator or approver to add additional
                    individuals or groups to the routing of a specific document. In most cases, ad
                    hoc approvers inserted into the routing interrupt the regular routing process.
                    For example, when a user initiates a financial document and ad hoc routes it to
                    another user for approval, the document routes to the ad hoc approver before it
                    routes to the fiscal officer. </para>
                <tip>
                    <para> Ad hoc acknowledge and FYI routing do not interrupt the regular routing
                        process. </para>
                </tip>
                <para> Financial processing documents with these types of ad hoc requests still
                    pending post to the General Ledger as soon as all other approvals are obtained.
                    The system does not put them on hold while waiting for the acknowledgment to
                    take place or for the FYI to be cleared. </para>
                <para> The following steps describe how to add an ad hoc recipient in the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Ad Hoc Recipients</emphasis> tab. <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para> Select an action requested from the <emphasis role="bold">Action
                                    Requested</emphasis> list. To route the document to an
                                individual, select this option in the <emphasis role="bold">Person
                                    Requests</emphasis> section. To send the request to a group,
                                select this option in the <emphasis role="bold">Ad Hoc Group
                                    Requests</emphasis> section. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>Ad Hoc Recipients Tab of an OLE Document: User selects
                                            Acknowledge, Approve, or FYI from the drop down</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-64.png"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                            <para/>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para> To ad hoc route the document to another person, type the
                                principal name in the <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis> box in
                                the <emphasis role="bold">Ad Hoc Recipients</emphasis> section or
                                use the lookup icon <mediaobject>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/Lookup.png" depth="15"
                                            width="15"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject> to search for the appropriate user name. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Documents: Ad Hoc Recipients Tab with sample
                                            data</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-65.png" width="100%"
                                            />
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                            <para/>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para> To ad hoc route the document to a group, in the <emphasis
                                    role="bold">Namespace Code</emphasis> field in the <emphasis
                                    role="bold">Ad Hoc Group Requests</emphasis> section, enter the
                                group name or use the <emphasis role="bold">Lookup</emphasis> icon <mediaobject>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/Lookup.png" depth="15"
                                            width="15"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject> to search for the appropriate group name. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Documents: Ad Hoc Group Requests on the Ad Hoc
                                            Recipients Tab</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-66.png" width="100%"
                                            />
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                            <para/>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>Add</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/VendorNoTitlePage-88.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject> . The system verifies that the person ID or
                                group namespace code and name that you have entered for routing is
                                valid. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>Submit</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata
                                            fileref="../images/PurchasingAndAccountsPayableNoTitlePagept2-82.png"
                                        />
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject> on the document.</para>
                            <para> After you complete the <emphasis role="bold">Ad Hoc
                                    Recipient</emphasis> section and submit the document, the system
                                changes the <emphasis role="bold">Node(s)</emphasis> value to
                                'Adhoc' and changes the <emphasis role="bold">Status</emphasis>
                                value to 'ENROUTE'. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Document: Route Log Tab with Sample Data</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-67.png"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para> The <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests</emphasis> tab
                                shows the requested action and the user ID. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Document: Pending Action Requests on the Route Log
                                            Tab</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-68.png"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
                <para> When a document is en route, you may send ad hoc requests without taking a
                    workflow action on the document. To do this follow the steps listed above but
                    use the <inlinemediaobject>
                        <alt>Send Ad Hoc Request</alt>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-69.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </inlinemediaobject> button instead of <emphasis role="bold">Submit</emphasis>. </para>
                <note>
                    <para> When you review the Route Log immediately after submitting a document,
                        you may not see the <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests</emphasis>
                        tab. This is because OLE has not yet received the routing information from
                        Workflow. In this case, wait for a few seconds and click the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Refresh</emphasis> button at the top of the Route Log to
                        refresh the screen. You may need to repeat this process a few times until
                        the information appears in the <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action
                            Requests</emphasis> tab. </para>
                </note>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <alt>OLE Document: Refresh button on the Route Log</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-70.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </para>
                <para/>
                <para> The <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests</emphasis> tab shows the
                    requested action and the user ID. </para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing Route Nodes</title>
            <para> To see the route nodes associated with a particular document type: </para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para> Click the <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Admin</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/Admin.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject> menu tab. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> Select <emphasis role="bold">Routing &amp; IDM Doc Type</emphasis>
                        (Routing and Identity Management Document Type Hierarchy) from the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Workflow Admin</emphasis> submenu. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Workflow Admin Submenu</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-configuration.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> The system displays document types in the hierarchy.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> Locate the desired document type route levels. </para>
                    <para> For example, you might scroll down to Transfer of Funds to view the rules
                        of the Transfer of Funds document route levels. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Route nodes on the Transfer of Funds Document Displayed in the
                                    Routing &amp; IDM Doc Type Hierarchy</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-63.png" width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> Beneath the document type, you see the nodes that the document routes
                        through. The system lists these nodes in order from first to last. To view
                        more detail about the KIM responsibilities associated with these route
                        nodes, click the <emphasis role="bold">View Document
                            Configuration</emphasis> link. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Routing and IDM Doc Type: View Document Configuration</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-71.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> Scroll down to the <emphasis role="bold">Workflow /
                            Responsibilities</emphasis> tab. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Document Configuration: Workflow / Responsibilities Tab</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routingWorkflowTab.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> In the <emphasis role="bold">Workflow / Responsibilities</emphasis> tab,
                        the system displays the name of each route node along with the associated
                        role(s) and other information. The first entry in the list defines the
                        exception routing for this document type. This entry identifies the role
                        that receives the document if Workflow encounters an error that prevents it
                        from completing the document's normal routing. </para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            <note>
                <para> In some cases a document may have route nodes that the document passes
                    through based on certain conditions. These split or branching route nodes are
                    indented to distinguish them from the route nodes through which all documents of
                    this type pass. </para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Workflow Responsibilities</title>
            <para>When a document routes through a particular route level, the KEW evaluates it
                against the responsibilities that reference this document type and route level. A
                responsibility acts like a trigger: If the document meets its criteria, the system
                sends an action request to a particular user or group of users.</para>
            <para>Responsibilities are associated with roles in KIM. Roles have members or assignees
                who are represented in the system as persons, groups, or other roles. Users assigned
                to a role inherit the role's responsibilities, meaning that they receive action
                requests from Workflow when specified conditions are met.</para>
            <para> To view responsibilities, select the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Responsibility</emphasis> option from the <emphasis role="bold">Identity
                    Admin</emphasis> submenu on the <inlinemediaobject>
                    <alt>Admin</alt>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/Admin.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject> tab.</para>
            <para/>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <alt>Identity Admin Submenu</alt>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-responsibility.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </para>
            <para/>
            <para> Each responsibility includes several attributes (that is, values and details)
                that determine when it is triggered. </para>
            <para/>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <alt>Responsibilities Loo up sample results</alt>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-responsibilityList.png" width="100%"
                            />
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </screenshot>
            </para>
            <para/>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"> Responsibilities lookup results
                Definitions</emphasis></para>
            <informaltable border="1" class="MsoNormalTable"
                style="border-collapse:collapse;mso-table-layout-alt:fixed;border:none;  mso-border-alt:solid black .5pt;mso-yfti-tbllook:160;mso-padding-alt:0in 5.4pt 0in 5.4pt;  mso-border-insideh:.5pt solid black;mso-border-insidev:.5pt solid black">
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                            <para>Title</para>
                        </td>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                            <para>Description</para>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Responsibility Detail Values</td>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                            <para>Display-only. Additional detail that identifies the document this
                                responsibility generates action requests for, when the requests are
                                generated and how Workflow handles them. </para>
                            <para> Route Node Name: The point in a document's workflow routing at
                                which this responsibility generates requests. </para>
                            <para> Document Type Name: The name of the document type this
                                responsibility will generate action requests for. </para>
                            <para> Action Details At Role Member Level: A 'True' or 'False'
                                indicator that indicates where the details of this workflow action
                                request are defined. If the value is 'True,' action details are
                                collected when members are assigned to the role. If the value is
                                'False,' the action details are collected when this responsibility
                                is assigned to a role. </para>
                            <para> Required: A 'True' or 'False' value that indicates whether this
                                responsibility is required to generate an action request or send the
                                document into exception status ('True') or is an optional
                                responsibility and can be bypassed if no action requests are
                                generated ('False').</para>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Responsibility Name</td>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
                            <para>Display-only. The name of this responsibility. In most cases, the
                                responsibility name will be the same as the associated template name
                                (Review). </para>
                            <para> Like permission names, responsibility names are not unique. Thus
                                most OLE responsibilities have a <emphasis role="bold"
                                    >Responsibility Name</emphasis> of 'Review'.</para>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Responsibility Namespace</td>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Display-only. The namespace with which the
                            responsibility is associated. This namespace usually corresponds to the
                            namespace of the document type for which the responsibility generates
                            action requests.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Template Name</td>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Display-only. The name of the template on which
                            the responsibility is based. The template defines, in a broad sense,
                            what the responsibilities based on it do. Since responsibilities usually
                            generate action requests for user review, most responsibilities have a
                                <emphasis role="bold">Template Name</emphasis> of 'Review'.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Template Namespace Code</td>
                        <td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Display-only. The namespace for the
                            responsibility template. Usually, the namespace identifies the
                            application and module the applicable responsibility template pertains
                            to. Because responsibilities pertain to workflow, most responsibility
                            templates are associated with the <emphasis role="bold"
                                >KR-WKFLW</emphasis> (Kuali Rice-Workflow) namespace.</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </informaltable>
            <para>While responsibilities are created and maintained in two central locations, users
                may supply qualifying values when assigning users to a role associated with these
                responsibilities. These qualifying values generally identify specific circumstances
                under which the responsibility is invoked. For example, if a departmental user adds
                a user to a role with a responsibility that refers to an organization hierarchy
                route node, the departmental user supplies the appropriate chart and organization
                code. Subsequently, only documents that contain this chart and organization code
                route to the specified user.</para>
            <note>
                <para> For more information about roles and responsibilities, see <link
                    xlink:href="../../../webhelp/ADMIN/content/ch07s02.html">KIM Permissions, Responsibilities, and
                    Roles</link> in the <link xlink:href="../../../webhelp/ADMIN/index.html"><emphasis
                            role="italic">Guide to OLE System Administration
                        Functions.</emphasis></link>
                </para>
            </note>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_routeLog"/>Route Log</title>
                <para> The <emphasis role="bold">Route Log</emphasis> tab displayed on all OLE
                    e-docs shows workflow status details. The <emphasis role="bold">Route
                        Log</emphasis> can have up to these four subtabs---<emphasis role="bold"
                        >Document ID</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">Actions Taken</emphasis>,
                        <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests</emphasis>, and <emphasis
                        role="bold">Future Action Requests</emphasis>. </para>
                <para/>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <alt>OLE Document: Route Log with Sample Data</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routeLog.png" width="100%"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </para>
                <para/>
                <para role="TableHeading"><emphasis role="bold">Document ID Tab
                        Definitions</emphasis></para>
                <informaltable frame="top">
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Title</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Description </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Title </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> A combination of the document type,
                                        description, and the organization document number (if any).
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Type</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The document type. The full name of
                                        the transaction used to identify this document type in
                                        Workflow. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Initiator</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The name of the person who created the
                                        document. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Status</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The route status for the document. </para>
                                    <note>
                                        <para> For more information, see <link
                                                linkend="_routeStatus">Route Status</link>. </para>
                                    </note>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Node(s)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The current route node of the document
                                        -- that is, the current step that the document is on, on its
                                        route path. Route nodes are also referred to as 'route
                                        levels'. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Created</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The time and date that the document
                                        was created. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Last Modified</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The time and date that the document
                                        was modified last. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Last Approved</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The time and date that the last action
                                        was taken on this document. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Finalized</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> The time and date that the document
                                        reached' Final,' 'Canceled,' or 'Disapproved' status.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable>
                <section>
                    <title>Action Taken Tab</title>
                    <para> The <emphasis role="bold">Actions Taken</emphasis> tab displays the
                        history of workflow actions on the e-doc. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Actions Taken Tab in the Route Log</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routeLogActionTaken.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> This tab lists each action taken, the name of the person who took this
                        action, and the time and date the action was taken. The <emphasis
                            role="bold">For Delegator</emphasis> field shows the name of a delegate
                        that took action on someone else's behalf. For example, for account routing
                        the fiscal officer's name would be shown here if this person's delegate took
                        action on the document. </para>
                    <para> To drill down into the details of each action, click <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Show</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-show.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Show Button on the Actions Taken Tab</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routeLogActionTakenShow.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> The system displays the detail. </para>
                    <note>
                        <para> Several layers of information may be available for an action request.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Pending Action Requests Tab</title>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests</emphasis> tab displays
                        the next action to be taken and shows more detailed routing information
                        about this request. Only action requests at the current route node are
                        displayed.</para>
                    <para>The following example shows a document that is awaiting approval by one
                        fiscal officers.</para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Pending Actions Requests Tab in the Route
                                    Log</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routeLogPendingActions.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Action</emphasis> field indicates whether the
                        document is in a user or group's action list or is pending their approval.
                        An action of <emphasis role="bold">Pending Approve</emphasis> means Workflow
                        has identified other approval actions needed at this route node, but it has
                        not actually sent these requests yet. Pending approval actions may be
                        determined by the <emphasis role="bold">Priority</emphasis> attribute on the
                        appropriate workflow responsibilities.</para>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Requested Of</emphasis> field displays the name
                        of the user or group responsible for the pending action. The value in this
                        field is based on the responsibility at this current route level. In cases
                        where a document routes to a role with more than five members the name of
                        the role will be displayed along with any qualifying values pertaining to
                        the role assignees who received the request.</para>
                    <para>Note that the <emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests</emphasis> tab
                        shows pending requests only for the document at its current route node. The
                        system may add new requests when the document transitions to a new route
                        level.</para>
                    <tip>
                        <para> To identify members of a group whose ID is displayed in the <emphasis
                                role="bold">Requested Of</emphasis> field, click the link for the
                            group ID. The system displays information about the group members.
                        </para>
                    </tip>
                    <para> If multiple users are identified as the recipients of a single action
                        request, the number of actions required is controlled by the action policy
                        code associated with the responsibility that generated the request. </para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>If this code is set to 'ALL,' all users specified must take the
                                required action on the document before the request will be
                                cleared.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>If the action policy code is 'FIRST,' the first of the specified
                                users to take the action will cause the system to clear the action
                                request for all other users with the same request.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Future Action Requests Tab</title>
                    <para> When a document's status is 'saved' or 'enroute,' the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Future Action Requests</emphasis> tab on the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Route Log</emphasis> shows the action requests that Workflow
                        will generate in the future based on the information currently on the
                        document. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Future Actions Requests Tab in the Route
                                    Log</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routeLogFutureActions.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>To open this section and view the future action requests, click the <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Show</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-show.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject> button. Future action requests are listed in the order
                        in which they are to occur.</para>
                    <para>As a document routes and users take action on it, the system updates the
                        contents of the <emphasis role="bold">Future Action Requests</emphasis> tab
                        to show only those requests that have not yet been made by Workflow. When a
                        document reaches 'Final' or 'Processed' status in Workflow, this tab becomes
                        empty because there are no future requests to display.</para>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Annotation</emphasis> entry is a message that is
                        generated based on the KIM responsibilities being referenced by
                        Workflow.</para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Sample Annotations on the Future Action Requests
                                    in the Route Log</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-74.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>View Routing Details</title>
                    <para> To display more detailed routing information about the request, click <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Show</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-show.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Show Button on the Pending Action Requests
                                    Tab</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata
                                        fileref="../images/basic-routeLogPendingActionsShow.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> The resulting display contains additional information about the request. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Additional Sample Information Displayed on the
                                    Pending Action Requests Tab</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata
                                        fileref="../images/basic-routeLogPendingActionsDetail.png"
                                        width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para role="TableHeading"><emphasis role="bold">Pending Action Requests Tab
                            Definitions</emphasis></para>
                    <informaltable frame="top">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
                            <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Title</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Description </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Node </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The route node at which this
                                            request was generated. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> Priority</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The priority assigned to this
                                            workflow request. If multiple requests are generated at
                                            the same workflow node, the system generates requests
                                            with low priority numbers before requests with higher
                                            priority numbers. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Approval Policy</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> A value indicating whether members
                                            of a role receiving this request must each take action
                                            to fulfill the request or if only a single role member
                                            must take action. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Forced Action</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> A true/false indicator specifying
                                            whether a user must take action on this document even if
                                            he or she has acted on it previously. If 'True,' then
                                            the user must take another action. If 'False,' then the
                                            previous action will automatically fulfill this request.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </informaltable>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title><anchor xml:id="_routeStatus"/>Route Status</title>
                    <para> Route status indicates where a document is in its routing process. For
                        any given document, the system displays route status in both the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Route Log</emphasis> tab and the document header. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>OLE Document: Route Status on the Route Log</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-routeLogStatus.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> The following table summarizes the meaning of various route statuses in
                        the KEW. </para>
                    <para role="TableHeading"><emphasis role="bold">Route Status
                            Definitions</emphasis></para>
                    <informaltable frame="top">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
                            <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Status</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Description </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Approved</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been approved.
                                            The document is now a valid business transaction in
                                            accordance with institutional needs and policies. See
                                            note below. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Canceled</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document is denoted as void
                                            and should be disregarded. This status is applied to a
                                            document when an initiator creates a document and
                                            cancels it before submitting it for approval. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Committed</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been committed to
                                            the database. See note below. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Disapproved</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been disapproved
                                            by an approver. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Enroute</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has pending approval
                                            requests. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Exception</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been routed to an
                                            exception queue because workflow has encountered an
                                            error when trying to process its routing. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Final</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been routed and
                                            has no pending approval or acknowledgment requests.
                                            Documents in 'Final' status are considered approved in
                                            that documents in this status affect the General Ledger
                                            or update Chart of Accounts values. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> Initialized</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been created but
                                            has not yet been saved or submitted. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Processed</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has no pending
                                            approval requests but still has one or more pending
                                            acknowledgment requests. Processed documents are
                                            considered approved, so they impact the General Ledger
                                            or update Chart of Accounts values. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells">Saved</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                        <para role="Table Cells"> The document has been started but
                                            not completed or routed yet. The save action allows the
                                            initiator of a document to save his or her work and
                                            close the document. The document may be retrieved from
                                            the initiator's action list for completion and routing
                                            at a later time. </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </informaltable>
                    <note>
                        <para> A user does not ordinarily see a Status value of 'Approved' or
                            'Committed'. The system displays these statuses to users only as a
                            result of a system error or performance issue. </para>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_actionList"/>Action List</title>
                <para> In OLE, you receive action requests for e-docs through your action list. This
                    list provides summary information about each document that requires your
                    attention, such as document type, title, route status, the type of action
                    requested of you, who initiated the document, when it was created, and whether
                    or not you've received this request because you are a delegate or a member of a
                    group. </para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                <alt>Action List</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-72.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                        <para> The Workflow system retrieves all documents that you have initiated
                            and saved and any documents that are routed to you to approve,
                            acknowledge, or FYI. </para>
                        <para/>
                        <para>
                            <screenshot>
                                <mediaobject>
                                    <alt>Sample Action List</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-73.png" width="100%"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject>
                            </screenshot>
                        </para>
                        <para/>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para> Click the document <emphasis role="bold">Id</emphasis> link to open
                            the document. </para>
                        <para> The system displays a set of buttons at the bottom of the screen. The
                            buttons you see depend on your role and the requested action.  For
                            example, you may see:</para>
                        <para/>
                        <para>
                            <screenshot>
                                <mediaobject>
                                    <alt>Workflow Action Buttons on the bottom of a action list
                                        document</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-75.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject>
                            </screenshot>
                        </para>
                        <para/>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para> Click one of the workflow action buttons. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_workflowActionButtons"/>Workflow Action Buttons</title>
                <para> When you open a document, you see various workflow action buttons at the
                    bottom of the page. The buttons vary depending on the document you are opening,
                    the kind of action request you have received for the document and the KIM
                    role(s) to which you belong.</para>
                <note>
                    <para> Some additional buttons are available, depending on the e-doc you are
                        viewing.  These buttons are described within their particular guide. </para>
                </note>
                <para role="TableHeading"><emphasis role="bold">Workflow Action Button
                        Definitions</emphasis></para>
                <informaltable frame="top">
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Action</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Description </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Acknowledge</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-76.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Signifies that you have responded to
                                        the acknowledgment action request. This button is available
                                        only to users to whom a document has been routed for
                                        acknowledgment. See FYI below. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Approve</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/ManagingAndEncumberingFundsNoTitlePagePt2-222.png"
                                                />
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Signifies that in your judgment the
                                        document represents a valid business transaction in
                                        accordance with institutional needs and policies. A single
                                        document may require approval from several users, at
                                        multiple route levels, before it moves to 'Processed'
                                        status. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Blanket Approve</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/ManagingAndEncumberingFundsNoTitlePagePt2-59.png"
                                                />
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Bypasses all subsequent levels of
                                        approval and immediately moves a document to 'Processed' or
                                        'Final' status. Anyone who would otherwise have received the
                                        document for approval receives an acknowledge request
                                        instead. This action may be taken only by roles associated
                                        with blanket approve document permission, such as the
                                        OLE-SYS Manager role. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Cancel</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/ManagingAndEncumberingFundsNoTitlePagePt2-275.png"
                                                />
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Denotes that the document is void and
                                        should be disregarded. Canceled documents cannot be modified
                                        in any way and do not route for approval. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Close</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-30.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Allows you to exit the document. The
                                        system displays a message asking whether you want to save
                                        the document before closing. No changes to action requests,
                                        route logs or document status occur as a result of a close
                                        action. If you initiate a document and close it without
                                        saving, it is the same as canceling that document. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Copy</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-24.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Allows you to create a new document
                                        based on the existing document. Not all document types can
                                        be copied. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Disapprove</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-77.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Signifies that in your judgment the
                                        document does not represent a valid business transaction. A
                                        disapprove action from any single approver prevents a
                                        document from posting to the GL or updating a maintenance
                                        table. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">
                                        <inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Error Correction</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-78.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Allows you to correct documents by
                                        creating a new document that reverses the original
                                        transaction. This feature can be used only on documents that
                                        have completed the routing process and have been fully
                                        approved. Not all document types are eligible for error
                                        correction. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>FYI</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-79.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Signifies that you have responded to
                                        the FYI action request. This action is available only to
                                        users to whom a document has been routed for FYI. The
                                        difference between acknowledgment and FYI is that FYI
                                        requests can be cleared directly from the action list
                                        without opening the document. FYI requests also have a
                                        different effect on the document status than
                                        acknowledgments. A document with no pending approval
                                        requests but with pending acknowledge requests is in
                                        'Processed' status. A document with no pending approval
                                        requests but with pending FYI requests is in 'Final' status.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Reload</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-80.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Refreshes the screen and displays the
                                        most recently saved information. Changes that are made but
                                        not saved prior to reloading a page are not maintained.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Save</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-27.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> If you are the initiator of this
                                        document, allows you to save your work and close the
                                        document. The document may be retrieved from your action
                                        list for completion and routing at a later time. If your
                                        permissions allow you to edit en route documents, you can
                                        also save changes to an en route document in your action
                                        list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"><inlinemediaobject>
                                            <alt>Submit</alt>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/PurchasingAndAccountsPayableNoTitlePagept2-82.png"
                                                />
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject></para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Moves the document (through workflow)
                                        to the next level of approval. After a document is
                                        submitted, it remains in 'Enroute' status until all
                                        approvals have taken place. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable>
                <para> Special attention should be paid when you select any of the workflow action
                    buttons noted below. </para>
                <section>
                    <title>Blanket Approving a Document</title>
                    <para>If you are a member of a role with a blanket approve document permission
                        (such as the OLE-SYS Manager role), you have the option to blanket approve a
                        document routed to you for your approval.</para>
                    <para>Note that you can only blanket approve a document you are initiating or a
                        document for which you already have an approval request.</para>
                    <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Blanket Approve</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata
                                    fileref="../images/ManagingAndEncumberingFundsNoTitlePagePt2-59.png"
                                />
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject> to approve the document bypassing all other approvals. </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Disapproving a Document</title>
                    <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Disapprove</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-77.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                    <para> Enter a reason for disapproval, and then click <emphasis role="bold"
                            >yes</emphasis> to confirm. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Document Disapprove Confirmation Screen</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-81.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> After you complete the disapprove action, the system displays the reason
                        in the <emphasis role="bold">Notes and Attachment</emphasis> tab. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Disapproval note added to the Notes and Attachments Tab of the
                                    Document</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-82.png" width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Acknowledging a Document</title>
                    <note>
                        <para> Acknowledgments do not interrupt the normal workflow routing of a
                            document. They do not stop a document from routing on to other
                            individuals, groups, or roles who need to take approval actions. </para>
                    </note>
                    <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Acknowledge</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-76.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>. </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>FYI a Document</title>
                    <note>
                        <para> FYIs do not interrupt the normal workflow routing of a document.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                    <para> To signify that you have responded to the FYI action, you may take either
                        of two actions: </para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>FYI</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-79.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject> when you open the document. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para> or, in the action list, select <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>FYI</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-79.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject> in the <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis>
                                column and click <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>Take Actions</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-83.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject></para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>Sample Action List with an FYI Action Request</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-84.png" width="100%"
                                            />
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <tip>
                        <para>
                            <emphasis role="bold">Setting the default action for FYI:</emphasis> To
                            clear all FYI actions in the action list simultaneously, first set the
                            default action from 'NONE' to 'FYI'. </para>
                        <para/>
                        <para><inlinemediaobject>
                                <alt>None, FYI Drop Down</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-85.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </inlinemediaobject></para>
                    </tip>
                    <para> Next, click <emphasis role="bold">apply default</emphasis> (in the upper
                        right corner) and then click <emphasis role="bold">take actions</emphasis>.
                    </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title><anchor xml:id="_correctingErrorsAfterApproval"/>Correcting Errors After
                        Approval</title>
                    <para> In financial e-docs, the error correction action allows you to correct
                        documents by creating a new document that reverses the original transaction
                        that has been fully approved. A document created with the error correction
                        action must route and be approved in the same manner as the e-doc it
                        corrects. </para>
                    <note>
                        <para> The error correction action should not be confused with the financial
                            transaction document type General Error Correction (GEC), which is
                            described in <link xlink:href="../../../webhelp/AG/content/ch14s05.html"
                                >General Error Correction</link> in the <link
                                    xlink:href="../../../../webhelp/AG/index.html"><emphasis role="italic">Guide to the
                                    OLE Select and Acquire Module</emphasis></link>. </para>
                    </note>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>Error Correction</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-78.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject></para>
                            <para> The system creates a new document with a new document ID. The
                                system also displays <emphasis role="bold">Corrects Document
                                    ID</emphasis> in both the document header and the <emphasis
                                    role="bold">Notes and Attachment</emphasis> tab of the document. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para><inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>OLE Document Header with Corrects Document ID</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-86.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject></para>
                            <para/>
                            <para> Amounts are in negative to reverse the original transaction. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Document with Account Amounts Being Reversed</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-87.png" width="100%"
                                            />
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para> The new document has an annotation that is an error correction. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Document: Error-correction note on the Notes and
                                            Attachments Tab</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-88.png"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                    <alt>Submit</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata
                                            fileref="../images/PurchasingAndAccountsPayableNoTitlePagept2-82.png"
                                        />
                                    </imageobject>
                                </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                            <para> The header of the corrected document shows the corrected by
                                document ID. </para>
                            <para/>
                            <para>
                                <screenshot>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <alt>OLE Document Header with Corrected By Document ID</alt>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-89.png" width="100%"
                                            />
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </screenshot>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Workflow Preferences</title>
                <para> The system allows you to change the automatic refresh rate, action list page
                    size, email notification, and row colors that indicate the status of the
                    document. You may also limit the list of documents in the action list by setting
                    filters for delegators or workflow status. To make any of these changes, click
                    the <emphasis role="bold">preferences</emphasis> button in the action list. </para>
                <para/>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <alt>Action Lists Preferences Button in the top right corner</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-90.png" width="100%"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </para>
                <para/>
                <para> The system displays the Workflow Preferences screen. </para>
                <para/>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <alt>Workflow Preferences Screen</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-91.png" width="100%"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </para>
                <para/>
                <para role="TableHeading"><emphasis role="bold">Workflow Preferences Field
                        Definitions</emphasis></para>
                <informaltable frame="top">
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Title</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Description </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Automatic Refresh Rate</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Enter a number in whole minutes.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Action List
                                    Page Size</entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Enter a number of rows to display per
                                        page in the action list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Email Notification</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Select one of the desired email
                                        frequencies from the list: 'None,' 'Daily,' 'Weekly' or
                                        'Immediate'. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Receive Primary Delegates Emails</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Check this box to receive an email
                                        when a document arrives in your action list for which you
                                        are the primary delegate. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Receive Secondary Delegates
                                        Emails</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Check this box to receive an email
                                        when a document arrives in your secondary delegate action
                                        list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Delegator Filter</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> In the list, select 'Secondary
                                        Delegators on Action List' or 'Secondary Delegators only on
                                        Filter Page' to specify when to show the secondary
                                        delegation entries in your action list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Fields Displayed in Action List</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Check each box to include these items
                                        on the action list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Document Route Status Colors for
                                        Action List Entries </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Click one of the color options for
                                        each document route status. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable>
                <para> To save your preferences, click <inlinemediaobject>
                        <alt>Save</alt>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-27.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                <para/>
                <para> To return to the default preferences, click <inlinemediaobject>
                        <alt>Reset</alt>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-92.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                <note>
                    <para> Color changes do not take place until the next time you log onto the
                        system. </para>
                </note>
                <para/>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <alt>Action List Sample with Color Changes Applied</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-93.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </screenshot>
                </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Action List Filter</title>
                <para> Setting a filter allows you to display a subset of the action list. </para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para> To go to the Action List Filter dialog box, click the <emphasis
                                role="bold">Filter</emphasis> button. </para>
                        <para/>
                        <para>
                            <screenshot>
                                <mediaobject>
                                    <alt>Action List Filter Button: Available on the top right of
                                        the screen</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-94.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject>
                            </screenshot>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para> Specify filtering criteria in the Action List Filter dialog box. </para>
                        <para/>
                        <para>
                            <screenshot>
                                <mediaobject>
                                    <alt>Action List Filter Screen</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-95.png" width="100%"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject>
                            </screenshot>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Click <inlinemediaobject>
                                <alt>Filter</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-96.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                        <para> The system displays a message in the upper left corner. </para>
                        <para/>
                        <para>
                            <screenshot>
                                <mediaobject>
                                    <alt>Action List Sample with Filtering Displayed</alt>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-97.png"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject>
                            </screenshot>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <para role="TableHeading"><emphasis role="bold">Action List Filter
                        Definitions</emphasis></para>
                <informaltable frame="top">
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Title</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Description </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Document Title</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Enter a partial or full character
                                        string that you are looking for in the document description.
                                        For example, enter 'Test' to see all documents that contain
                                        'Test' in the document description. This field is case
                                        sensitive. Select the <emphasis role="bold"
                                            >Exclude?</emphasis> check box to exclude documents with
                                        the specified title from the list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Document
                                    Route Status</entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Select the route status you want. The
                                        choices are 'All,' 'Approved,' 'Disapproved,' 'Enroute,'
                                        'Exception,' 'Processed and Saved'. Select the <emphasis
                                            role="bold">Exclude?</emphasis> check box to exclude
                                        documents with the selected status from the list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Action Requested</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Select an action from the list. The
                                        choices are 'Acknowledge,' 'Approve,' 'Complete,' and 'FYI'.
                                        Select the <emphasis role="bold">Exclude?</emphasis> check
                                        box to exclude documents with the selected action from the
                                        list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Action Requested Group</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Select the name of the group that is
                                        requested to take an action. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Document Type</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Select a document type from the lookup <mediaobject>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata fileref="../images/Lookup.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </mediaobject> . Select the <emphasis role="bold"
                                            >Exclude?</emphasis> check box to exclude documents with
                                        the selected type from the list. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Date Created</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Enter a date range or select dates
                                        from the calendar <mediaobject>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/basic-miniCalendar.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </mediaobject> to limit the documents based on the date they
                                        were created. Select the <emphasis role="bold"
                                            >Exclude?</emphasis> check box to exclude documents that
                                        were created during this given time range. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells">Date Last Assigned</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">
                                    <para role="Table Cells"> Enter a date range or select dates
                                        from the calendar <inlinemediaobject>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/basic-miniCalendar.png"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </inlinemediaobject> to limit the documents based on the
                                        date that this action item was generated for you. Select the
                                            <emphasis role="bold">Exclude?</emphasis> check box to
                                        exclude documents that entered your action list during this
                                        given time range. The acceptable format is mm/dd/yyyy.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable>
                <section>
                    <title>Clearing the Action List Filter</title>
                    <note>
                        <para> The <emphasis role="bold">Clear Filter</emphasis> button is visible
                            only when you have previously created the filter. </para>
                    </note>
                    <para> To remove the filter and view the entire list, click the <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Clear Filter</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-98.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject> button. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Action List Clear Filter Button: Available on the top right of
                                    the screen</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-99.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title><anchor xml:id="_advancedDocumentSearches"/>Advanced Document
                    Searches</title>
                <para> In <link linkend="_usingDocSearch">Using Doc Search to Find a
                    Document</link>, we introduced the basic search capabilities within the KEW. The
                    system also provides more advanced and sophisticated search capabilities. </para>
                <section>
                    <title>Detailed Verses Basic Search</title>
                    <para> When you click the <emphasis role="bold">doc search</emphasis> button,
                        the system displays a search screen that initially defaults to a basic
                        search. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Doc Search Screen</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-100.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> To switch between the basic search and detailed search, click the
                            <emphasis role="bold">detailed search</emphasis> or <emphasis
                            role="bold">basic search</emphasis> button near the top of the screen.
                        The detailed search screen gives you more options for specifying search
                        criteria. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Doc Search Detailed Search</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-101.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Superuser Verses Non-Superuser Searches</title>
                    <para> The search screen initially defaults to a non-superuser search mode. If
                        you are a member of a role (e.g., the OLE-SYS Workflow Administrator role)
                        that has the administer routing for document permission, you may switch
                        between non-superuser search and superuser search mode by clicking the
                            <emphasis role="bold">Superuser Search</emphasis> or <emphasis
                            role="bold">Non-Superuser Search</emphasis> link. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Doc Search Superuser Search</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-102.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para> The search screen initially defaults to a non-superuser search mode. If
                        you are a member of a role (e.g., the OLE-SYS Workflow Administrator role)
                        that has the administer routing for document permission, you may switch
                        between non-superuser search and superuser search mode by clicking the
                            <emphasis role="bold">Superuser Search</emphasis> or <emphasis
                            role="bold">Non-Superuser Search</emphasis> link. </para>
                    <note>
                        <para> Anyone can search for documents using superuser search, but only
                            users with an appropriate role can actually take special actions on the
                            documents retrieved by the superuser search function. </para>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Document Specific Searches</title>
                    <para> Document-specific searches allow you to specify additional criteria when
                        you search specific document types or groups of documents such as financial
                        transactions or purchasing/accounts payable documents. In addition to the
                        standard search criteria available in the basic and advanced searches,
                        document-specific searches allow you to specify fields such as dollar
                        amounts, status, and document-specific reference numbers. </para>
                    <note>
                        <para> For more information about document-specific search, see the help
                            documentation section on the applicable document type in the appropriate
                            guide listed in the <link xlink:href="../../../html/Index.html">OLE
                                Documentation Portal</link>. </para>
                    </note>
                    <para> You may also access these search options after you click the doc search
                        button. To access document-specific search at this point, either enter the
                        document type name and tab out of the field or use the <emphasis role="bold"
                            >Document Type</emphasis> lookup <inlinemediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/Lookup.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject> . The system displays the appropriate additional search
                        fields. </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Named Searches</title>
                    <para> When you name a set of search criteria, the system saves your search as a
                        named search. When you later click <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis>,
                        the system displays a list of all named searches you have created in the
                        Searches list. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Doc Search Named Searches Appear in the Searches Drop
                                    Down</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-103.png" width="100%"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Clear Saved Searches</title>
                    <para> To clear all of your named searches, click <emphasis role="bold">clear
                            saved searches</emphasis>. OLE clears the Searches list. </para>
                    <para/>
                    <para>
                        <screenshot>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <alt>Doc Search Searches Drop Down that has been cleared</alt>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-104.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </screenshot>
                    </para>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Clear Searches</title>
                    <para> To clear your previous search criteria, click <inlinemediaobject>
                            <alt>Clear</alt>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/basic-105.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>.</para>
                </section>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
