<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<chapter xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    version="5.0" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title><anchor xml:id="_Introduction"/>Introduction </title>
    <para role="Normal (Web)">This guide provides information about using Deliver Functions. The
        Deliver Module covers the interactions between the library and its patrons. </para>
    <note>
        <para>To learn more about the Deliver Module, see the <emphasis>Deliver Overview</emphasis>
            in the wiki’s<link xlink:href="../html/Index.html">OLE Documentation Portal</link>.
        </para>
    </note>
    <para role="Body Text">This guide is organized as follows.</para>
    <itemizedlist mark="disc" spacing="normal">
        <listitem>
            <para role="C1H Bullet">The first section provides an explanation of Deliver Batch
                Processes </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="C1H Bullet">The next section provides an explanation of circulation and
                billing processes. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para role="C1H Bullet">The next section presents information related to patrons. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The final sections describe the associated maintenance documents (Maintenance
                documents control database tables) for circulation, then for patrons.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para role="C1H Bullet">These sections are divided into subsections covering individual
        functions. For each function, the applicable subsection presents a breadcrumb trail showing
        how to access the function and information on the layout and fields on the related
        screen(s). As appropriate, some subsections include business rules and routing information
        for e-docs and/or special instructions for performing activities. </para>
    <note>
        <para>In order to work efficiently in the system’s Deliver screens, you need to understand
            the basics of the user interface. For information and instructions on logging on and
            off, navigating, understanding the components of screens, and performing basic
            operations in the screens, see <link xlink:href="../../../webhelp/BASICS/index.html">OLE Basic
                Functionality and Key Concepts.</link>
        </para>
        <para> This guide as well as guides to other OLE modules are available from the <link
                xlink:href="../html/Index.html">OLE Documentation Portal</link>.</para>
    </note>
</chapter>
